Ames
Oklahoma, U.S.A.
N 36° 15'
W 98° 12'
16
470 ± 30
N
Y
M
-
Ahern, J. L., Gravity and magnetic investigation of the Ames structure, North-central Oklahoma. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 330-333. 1997.
Ahern, J. L., Impact structure or volcanic structure: The results of gravity and magnetic modelling of the Ames structure (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 25. 1995.
Ambers, C. P., Brändlein, P. and Gilbert,M.C., Petrology of enigmatic rocks from 2.75 km depth in the Ames structural anomaly, Major County, Oklahoma, and their relationship to suevite from the Ries crater, Nördlingen, Bavaria. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 302-309. 1997.
Ambers, C. P., Gilbert, M. and Brändlein,P., Petrology of enigmatic rocks from 2.75 km depth in the Ames structural anomaly, Major County, Oklahoma, and their relationship to suevite from the Ries crater, Nördlingen, Bavaria (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 26. 1995.
Attrep, Jr,M., Quintana, L.R. and Cisneros,M.R., Iridium concentrations in samples from four wells in the Ames structure (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 27. 1995.
Banks, R., Kuykendall, M. D., Arcuate faults help to "relax" and explain the Ames structure. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 339-356. 1997.
Banks, R., Kuykendall, M., Arcuate faults help to "relax" and explain the Ames structure (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 28. 1995.
Bridges, L. W. D., Ames depression, Oklahoma: Domal collapse and later subsurface solution. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 153-168. 1997.
Bridges, L. W. D., Ames depression, Oklahoma: Domal collapse and later subsurface solution (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 10. 1995.
Buthman, D. B., Global hydrocarbon potential of impact structures. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 83-99. 1997.
Carpenter B.N., Carlson, R., The Ames meteorite-impact crater. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 104-119. 1997.
Carpenter, B. N., The Ames astrobleme (astract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 1. 1995.
Carpenter, B. N., Carlson, R., The Ames impact crater. Oklahoma Geological Survey, v. 52, pp. 208-223. 1992.
Castaño, J. R., Clement, J.H., Kuykendall, M.D. and Sharpton,V.L., Source-rock potential of impact craters. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 100-103. 1997.
Coughlon, J. P., Denney, P. P., The Ames structure and other North American cryptoexplosion features: Evidence for endogenic emplacement. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 133-152. 1997.
Coughlon, J. P., Denney, P., The Ames structural depression: An endogenic cryptoexplosion feature along a transverse shear. Shale Shaker, pp. 44-58. 1993.
Curtiss, D. K., Wavrek, D. A., The Oil Creek-Arbuckle (!) petroleum system, Major County, Oklahoma. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 240-258. 1997.
Denison, R. E., Stern, R.J. and Sun,C.-H., Basement rocks in the Ames area. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 334-338. 1997.
Denison, R. E., Basement rocks in the Ames area (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 30. 1995.
Denney, P., Coughlon, J. P., The Ames structural depression: One of 15 endogenic cryptoexplosion features located along a zone of transcontinental transverse shear (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 9. 1995.
Donofrio, R. R., Survey of hydrocarbon-producing impact structures in North America: Exploration results to date and potential for discovery in Precambrian basement rock. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 17-29. 1997.
Evans, J., Historical development and production of the Arbuckle and exotic lithologies in the Ames structure, Oklahoma. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 207-213. 1997.
Fischer, J. F., The Nicor No. 18-4 Chestnut core, Ames structure, Oklahoma: Description and petrography. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 223-239. 1997.
Haines, R. A., Comparison of Sylvan structure residual maps of the Ames feature, using control as of December 1990 and December 1994. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, p. 374. 1997.
Haines, R. A., Comparison of Sylvan structure residual maps of the Ames hole using control as of December 1990 and December 1994 (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 32. 1995.
Hamm, H., Olsen, R. E., Oklahoma Arbuckle lime exploration centered on buried astrobleme structure. Oil & Gas, v. 90, pp. 113-116. 1992.
Hannibal J.T., Feldmann, R. M., Phyllocarid crustaceans from a Middle Ordovician black shale within the Ames structure, Northwest Oklahoma. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 370-373. 1997.
Hannibal, J. T., Feldmann, R. M., Phyllocarid crustaceans from the ?oil creek shale (Ordovician), within the Ames structure, northwest Oklahoma (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 33. 1995.
Heyer, J. F., Trapping mechanisms in Arbuckle strata, Major County, Oklahoma. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 214-222. 1997.
Huffman, A. R., Shock-induced microstructures and experimental constraints on the formation of the Ames impact structure. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 310-325. 1997.
Huffman, A. R., Experimental constraints on shock-induced microstructures in the impact deposits of the Ames crater (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 34. 1995.
Johnson K.S., Smith, D., Ames structure of northwestern Oklahoma is reflected in overlying Permian strata. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 357-362. 1997.
Johnson, K. S., Smith, D., Ames structure reflected in overlying Permian strata (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 36. 1995.
Koeberl, C., Milkereit, B., Continental Drilling and the Study of Impact Craters and Processes - an ICDP Perspective, In: Continental Scientific Drilling (eds. Harms, U., Koeberl, C., and Zoback, M.D.), Springer, Heidelberg, p. 95-161. 2007.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W. U., Kelley., Petrography, geochemistry, and argon -40/argon -39 ages of impact-melt rocks and breccias from the Ames impact structure, Oklahoma: The Nicor Chestnut 18-4 drill core. Meteoritics & Planetary Science v. 36(2001)(is. 5), pp. 651-669. 2001.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W. U., Kelley., Petrography, geochemistry, and 40Ar-39Ar ages of impact melt rocks and breccias from the Ames Impact Structure, Oklahoma: The Nicor Chestnut 18-4 drill core, Meteoritics & Planetary Science Vol. 36, No. 5., pp. 651-671. 2001.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W.U., Brandt, D., Dallmeyer, R.D. and Powell,R.A., Target rocks and breccias from the Ames impact structure, Oklahoma: Petrology, mineralogy, geochemistry, and age. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 169-198. 1997.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W. U., Petrological and geochemical studies of samples from the Nicor Chestnut 18-4 drill core, Ames impact structure, Oklahoma (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science, v. XXVII, pp. 679-680. 1996.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W.U., Dallmeyer, R.D. and Powell,R.A., Petrology, mineralogy, geochemistry, and age of impact melt rocks from the Ames structure, Oklahoma (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVI, pp. 775-776. 1995.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W.U. and Powell,R.A., Petrology, mineralogy, geochemistry, and age of the Ames structure (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 20. 1995.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W.U. and Powell,R.A., Shocked quartz and impact melt rock at the Ames structure, Oklahoma (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 29, pp. 483. 1994.
Koger, D. G., Wiley, M. A., Correlation of Landsat MSS (Multi-Spectral Scanner) and TM (Thematic Mapper) images with subsurface structure, Ames, Oklahoma. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 260-264. 1997.
Koger, D. G., Wiley, M. A., Satellilte data use and season/sensor/image comparisons; Ames Hole, Oklahoma (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 18. 1995.
Kuykendall, M. D., Johnson, C.L. and Carlson,R.A., Reservoir characterization of a complex impact structure: Ames impact structure, northern shelf, Anadarko Basin. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 199-206. 1997.
Kuykendall, M. D., Johnson, C.L. and Carlson,R.A., Reservoir characterization of a complex impact crater: "Ames Crater", Northern Shelf, Anadarko Basin (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 21. 1995.
Kuykendall, M. D., Johnson, C.L. and Carlson,R.A., Reservoir characterization of a complex impact crater: "Ames Crater, " northern shelf, Anadarko Basin (abstract). AAPG Annual Meeting, Denver, Colorado. 1994.
Mescher, P., Schultz, D. J., Gamma ray marker in Arbuckle dolomite, Wilburton Field, Oklahoma -- A widespread event associated with the Ames Hole impact crater (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 35. 1995.
Nick, K. E., Lithologic and stratigraphic evidence for the impact origin of a buried Ordovician age crater and reservoir near Ames, Major County, Oklahoma (abstract). AAPG Annual Meeting, Denver, Colorado. 1994.
Northcutt R.A., Brown, D. P., Drilling and oil and gas production history at the Ames feature, Major County, Oklahoma. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 297-301. 1997.
Northcutt, R. A., Brown, D. P., The drilling and oil and gas production history at the "Ames Hole", Major County, Oklahoma (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 38. 1995.
Ormo, J., Lindstrom, M., When a cosmic impact strikes the sea bed, Geol. Mag. V.137(1), p.67-80. 2000.
Philp, R. P., Allen, J. and Weber,J.L., Organic geochemical characteristics of oils and possible source rocks from the Ames impact structure. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, p. 259. 1997.
Philp, R. P., Allen, J. and Weber,J., Organic geochemical characteristics of oils and possible source rocks from the Ames impact crater (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 23. 1995.
Read, D. L., Richmond, G. L., Geology and reservoir characteristics of the Arbuckle Brown zone in the Cottonwood Creek field, Carter County, Oklahoma. Petroleum-reservoir geology in the southern Midcontinent, 1991 symposium: Oklahoma Geological Survey Circular 95, (K.S. Johnson and J.E. Campbell, eds.), pp. 113-125. 1993.
Repetski, J. E., Conodont age constraints on the Middle Ordovician black shale within the Ames structure, Major County, Oklahoma. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 363-369. 1997.
Repetski, J. E., Conodonts from the Middle Oodovician black shale within the Ames Structure, Major County, Oklahoma (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 39. 1995.
Roberts, C., Sandridge, B., The Ames hole. Shale Shaker, pp. 118-121. 1992.
Roemer, C. D., Roemer, C. and Williams,K., Gravity, magnetics point to volcanic origin for Oklahoma's Ames anomaly. Oil & Gas Journal, v. 90, pp. 75-80. 1992.
Sandridge, R., Ainsworth, K., The Ames structure reservoirs and three-dimensional seismic development. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 120-132. 1997.
Sandridge, R., Ainsworth, K., The Ames crater reservoirs and 3-D seismic development (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 42. 1995.
Sandridge, R., Ainsworth, K., The Ames crater reservoirs and 3-D seismic development (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 8. 1995.
Shirley, K., Overlooked 'Hole' found. AAPG Explorer, pp. 1, 11-13. 1992.
Tiedemann, H. A., The Wells Creek structure, Tennessee - From Heaven or Hell?. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 265-271. 1997.
Tucker, J. D., Hitzman, D.C. and Rountree,B.A., Production and structural features identified by surface geochemical techniques, Ames impact structure, Oklahoma. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 326-329. 1997.
Tucker, J. D., Hitzman, D.C. and Rountree,B.A., Ames hole production and structural features identified by surface geochemical techniques (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop, pp. 44. 1995.
Westbroek, H., Stewart, R., The formation, morphology, and economic potential of meteorite impact craters, CREWES Research Report v. 8, p. 1-26. 1996.
Williams, P., Oklahoma's Ames hole. Oil and Gas Investor, v. 13, pp. 30-38. 1993.
