Avak
Alaska, U.S.A.
N 71° 15'
W 156° 38'
12
3-95
N
Y
S
-
Cockell, C. S., Lee, P., The Biology of Impact Craters - a review. Biol. Rev., 77, P. 279 - 310. 2002.
Collins, F. R., Robinson, F. M., Exploration of Naval Petroleum Reserve No. 4 and adjacent areas, northern Alaska, 1944-53 - Part 5, Subsurface geology and engineering data. U.S. Geological Survey Open File Report, Geological Survey Professional Paper 305-K, pp. 140-145. 1967.
Collins, F. R., Core tests and test wells - Barrow area, Alaska. U.S. Department of the Interior, Geological Survey Professional Paper 305-K, pp. 629-641. 1961.
Donofrio, R. R., Survey of hydrocarbon-producing impact structures in North America: Exploration results to date and potential for discovery in Precambrian basement rock. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 17-29. 1997.
Grieve, R. A. F., Masaitis, V. L., The economic potential of terrestrial impact craters. International Geology Review, v. 36, pp. 105-151. 1994.
Kirschner, C. E., Grantz, A. and Mullen,M.W., Impact origin of the Avak Structure, Arctic Alaska, and genesis of the Barrow gas fields. The American Association of Petroleum Geologists Bulletin, v. 76, pp. 651-679. 1992.
Lantz, R., Barrow gas fields- N. Slope, Alaska. Oil and Gas Journal, v. 79, pp. 197-207. 1981.
Therriault, A. M., Grantz, A., Planar deformation features in quartz grains from mixed breccia of the Avak structure, Alaska (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVI, pp. 1403-1404. 1995.
Westbroek, H., Stewart, R., The formation, morphology, and economic potential of meteorite impact craters, CREWES Research Report v. 8, p. 1-26. 1996.