Calvin
Michigan, U.S.A.
N 41° 50'
W 85° 57'
8.5
450 ± 10
N
Y
S
-
Buthman, D. B., Global hydrocarbon potential of impact structures. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 83-99. 1997.
Donofrio, R. R., Survey of hydrocarbon-producing impact structures in North America: Exploration results to date and potential for discovery in Precambrian basement rock. Ames Structure in Northwest Oklahoma and Similar Features: Origin and Petroleum Production (1995 Symposium), K. S. Johnson and J. A. Campbell, Oklahoma Geological Survey, Norman, Oklahoma, v. Circular 100, pp. 17-29. 1997.
Milstein, R. L., The Calvin impact crater, Cass County, Michigan: Identification and analysis of a subsurface Ordovician astrobleme (abstract). Ames Structure and Similar Features - A Workshop -, p. 37. 1995.
Milstein, R. L., The Calvin impact crater, Cass County, Michagan: Identification and anlaysis of a subsurface Ordovician astrobleme. Ph. D. Ph.D. Thesis, Oregon State University, 86. 1994.
Milstein, R. L., Impact origin of the Calvin 28 cryptoexplosive distrunbance, Cass County, Michigan. Michigan Department of Natural Resources, Geological Survey Division, v. Report of Investigation 28, pp. 1-33. 1988.
Milstein, R. L., The Calvin 28 structure: Evidence for impact origin. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 25, pp. 1524-1530. 1988.
Milstein, R. L., The Calvin 28 cryptoexplosive distrubance, Cass County, Michigan. Geological Society of America Centennial Field Guide - North-Central Section, pp. 315-320. 1987.
Naeye, R., The hole in Nebraska. Discover, p. s. 1993.
Westbroek, H., Stewart, R., The formation, morphology, and economic potential of meteorite impact craters, CREWES Research Report v. 8, p. 1-26. 1996.