Charlevoix
Quebec, Canada
N 47° 32'
W 70° 18'
54
342 ± 15*
Y
Y
M
-
Anglin, F., Buchbinder, G., Microseismicity in the mid-St. Lawrence valley Charlevoix zone, Quebec. Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America, v. 71, pp. 1553-1560. 1981.
Bradley, D. C., Tectonics of the Acadian orogeny in New England and adjacent Canada. Journal of Geology, v. 91, pp. 381-400. 1983.
Buchbinder, G. G. R., Keith, C. M., Stability of P travel times in the region of La Malbaie, Quebec. Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America, v. 69, pp. 463-481. 1979.
Chagnon, J. Y., Study of erosion phenomena and unconsolidated deposits in Baie-Saint-Paul - Saint-Urbain area, Charlevoix county. Quebec Department of Natural Resources, Special Paper 3, 28 p. 1969.
Clark, J. F., Magnetic survey data at meteoritic impact sites in North America. Geomagnetic Service of Canada, Earth Physics Branch Open File # 83-5, 30 p. 1983.
Cooper, R. V., Lamontagne, M. and Halpenny,J., St. Lawrence River gravity survey aids Charlevoix study (abstract). GSC Forum '95. 1995.
Frost, N. H., Lilly, J. E., Crustal movements in the Lake St. John area, Quebec. Canadian Surveyor, v. XX, pp. 292-299. 1966.
Goltrant, O., Cordier, P and Doukhan,J - C., Planar deformation features in shocked quartz; a transmission electron microscopy investigation. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 106, pp. 103-115. 1991.
Gurov, E. P., Gorova, E.P. and Rakitskaya,R.B., On the orientation of planar feature sets in quartz from rocks of explosion meteorite craters (in Russian). Zapiski Vsesoyuznogo mineralogicheskogo obshchestva, v. 108, pp. 578-584. 1979.
Hansen, S. P., A crater formed by gas erosion of a nuclear explosion vent. Meteoritics, v. 4, pp. 61-142. 1968.
Hargraves, R. B., Roy, D. W., Paleomagnetism of anorthosite in and around the Charlevoix crytoexplosion structure, Quebec. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 11, pp. 854-859. 1974.
Hearty, D. J., Mereu, R.F. and Wright,C., Lateral variations in upper crustal structure below the La Malbaie area from slowness, azimuth, and traveltime measurements of telleseisms. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 14, pp. 2284-2293. 1977.
Hurley, P. M., Rb-Sr isotopic investigation of crater rocks of possible impact origin. U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, Seventeenth Annual Progress Report, pp. 27-29. 1969.
Lambert, P., Pagel, M., The planar elements of quartz from the structures of Carswell and Charlevoix (Canada) and Rochechouart (France) (in French). Comptes Rendus, v. 284, pp. 1623-1626. 1977.
Lamontagne, M., Ranalli, G., Faults and spatial clustering of earthquakes near La Malbaie, Charlevoix seismic zone, Canada. Seismological Research Letters, v. 68, pp. 337-352. 1997.
LaSalle, P., Rondot, J., New C14 dates from the St. Jean area, Quebec. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 3, pp. 568-561. 1967.
Lavigne, J., Un cratere "lunaire" en plein Quebec (in French). Quebec Science, v. 12, pp. 17-19. 1974.
Leblanc, D., Le météorite de Charlevoix. Geographica, v 2, n 3, p 4-11. 1998.
Leblanc, G., Stevens, A.E. and Wetmiller,R.J., A microearthquake survey of the St. Lawrence valley near La Malbaie, Quebec. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 10, pp. 42-53. 1973.
Lemieux, Y., Tremblay, A. , Lavoie, D., Structural analysis of supracrustal faults in the Charlevoix area, Quebec: relation to impact cratering and the St-Laurent fault system. Canadian Journal of Earth Science, Vol. 40, P. 221 - 235. 2003.
Lyons, J. A., Forsyth, D.A. and Mair,J.A., Crustal studies in the La Malbaie region, Quebec. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 17, pp. 478-490. 1980.
Mareschal, M., Chouteau, M., A magnetotelluric investigation of the structural geology beneath Charlevoix Crater, Quebec. Physics of the Earth and Planetary Interiors, v. 60, pp. 120-131. 1990.
Masaitis, V. L., Danilin, A.N., Maschak, M.S., Raykhlin, A.I., Selivanovskaya, T.V. and Shadenkov,Ye.M., The Geology of Astroblemes (in Russian). Leningrad, Nedra, 231 p. 1980.
McDougall, D. J., Natural thermoluminescence of calcareous rocks from the Charlevoix (Malbaie) structure. Meteoritics, v. 5, pp. 75-83. 1970.
Ogilvie, B. Y., Robertson, B. and Grieve,R.A.F., Meteorite impact features in Canada: An inventory and an evaluation. Unpublished Report, 180 p. 1984.
Pagel, M., Poty, B., Fluid inclusion studies in rocks of the Charlevoix structure (Quebec, Canada). Fortshritte der Mineralogie, v. 52, pp. 479-489. 1975.
Reimold, W. U., Dressler, B. O., The economic significance of impact processes (abstract). Abstracts for the International Workshop on Meteorite Impact on the Early Earth, Perth, Australia, pp. 36-37. 1990.
Robertson, P. B., Roy, J. L., Shock-diminished paleomagnetic remanence at the Charlevoix impact structure, Quebec. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 16, pp. 1842-1856. 1979.
Robertson, P. B., Grieve, R. A. F., Shock attenuation at terrestrial impact structures. Roddy, D.J., Pepin, R.O. and Merrill, R.B., eds., Impact and Explosion Cratering, Pergamon Press, New York, pp. 687-702. 1977.
Robertson, P. B., Grieve, R. A. F., Charlevoix, Quebec (abstract). Journal of the Royal Astronomical Society of Canada, v. 69, p. 11. 1975.
Robertson, P. B., Zones of shock metamorphism at the Charlevoix impact structure, Quebec. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 86, pp. 1630-1638. 1975.
Robertson, P. B., Zones of shock metamorphism at the Charlevoix crater, Quebec (abstract). EOS, v. 55, p. 336. 1974.
Robertson, P. B., La Malbaie structure, Quebec-A Palaeozoic meteorite impact site. Meteoritics, v. 4, pp. 89-112. 1968.
Rondot, J., Modeles d'astroblemes d'apres le deplacement des masses rocheuses : Charlevoix et le Ries, Canadian Journal of Earth Science, Vol 44, P. 607 - 617. 2007.
Rondot, J., Charlevoix and Sudbury as gravity-readjusted impact structures, Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 35, pp. 707-713. 2000.
Rondot, J., Charlevoix and Sudbury as simple readjusted craters (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Rondot, J., Charlevoix and Sudbury as simple readjusted craters (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Rondot, J., How deep are ancient astroblemes eroded? (abstract). Abstracts for the International Workshop on Meteorite Impact on the Early Earth, Perth, Australia, pp. 40-41. 1990.
Rondot, J., Géologié de Charlevoix (in French). Publication Gèoscientifiques de le DGEGM, MB89-21, 606 p. 1989.
Rondot, J., Comparison of the astroblemes of Siljan, Sweden, and Charlevoix, Quebec (in French). Bulletin of the Geological Institute of the University of Uppsala, v. 6, pp. 85-92. 1975.
Rondot, J., The Charlevoix astrobleme (in French). Geoscience, Spring, pp. 18-20. 1975.
Rondot, J., Geology of the Charlevoix structure (in French). International Geological Congress, 24th, Montreal, Canada, pp. 140-147. 1972.
Rondot, J., Geology of the Gouffre River area, Charlevoix county. Gouvernement du Quebec, Ministere des Richesses Naturelles, Preliminary Report 605, 26 p. 1972.
Rondot, J., La transgression Ordovicienne dans le comte de Charlevoix, Quebec (in French). Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 9, pp. 1187-1203. 1972.
Rondot, J., Impactite of the Charlevoix structure, Quebec, Canada. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 76, pp. 5414-5423. 1971.
Rondot, J., Les brèches d'impact de Charlevoix (abstract) (in French). Meteoritics, v. 6, pp. 307-308. 1971.
Rondot, J., The impact breccias of Charlevoix (in French). Meteoritics, v. 6, pp. 307-308. 1971.
Rondot, J., The Charlevoix compared with other meteor impacts. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 7, pp. 1194-1202. 1970.
Rondot, J., Preliminary report on the Malbaie River region (in French). Ministere des Richesses Naturelles, Quebec, Preliminary Report no. 576, 35 p. 1969.
Rondot, J., Significance of the breccia dikes of the Charlevoix structure (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 4, pp. 291-292. 1969.
Rondot, J., A new fossil meteor impact? The Charlevoix semi-circular structure (in French). Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 5, pp. 1305-1317. 1968.
Rondot, J., Geological field trip to the Charlevoix structure. Contribution au Congres de "the Meteoritical Society", Ministere des Richesses Naturelles du Québec, 23 p. 1968.
Rondot, J., Geology of L'Anse Saint-Jean area, Chicoutimi and Charlevoix counties. Department of Natural Resources, Quebec, Preliminary Report, 556, 13 p. 1967.
Rondot, J., Geology of La Malbaie area, Charlevoix county. Department of Natural Resources, Quebec, Preliminary Report 544, 18 p. 1966.
Roy, D. W., Tectonic rotations and isostatic recovery exhibited by the Charlevoix and the Manicouagan astroblemes, Quebec (abstract). Geological Association of Canada-Mineral Association of Canada Joint Annual Meeting, v. 7, p. 77. 1982.
Roy, D. W., Origin and evolution of the Charlevoix cryptoexplosion structure. Unpublished Ph.D. thesis, Princeton University, 190 p. 1978.
Roy, D. W., Origin and evolution of the Charlevoix cryptoexplosion structure (CCS), Quebec, Canada (abstract). EOS, v. 55, p. 336. 1974.
Roy, D. W., Rondot, J. and Dymek,R.F., A crypto-explosion structure at Charlevoix and the St. Urbain anorthosite. International Geological Congress, 24th, Montreal, 26 p. 1972.
Roy, D. W., Rondot, J., Shatter cones of Charlevoix (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 5, pp. 219-220. 1970.
Trepmann, C. A., Spray, J. G., Post-Shock Crystal-Plastic processes in quartz from crystalline target rocks of the Charlevoix Impact Structure, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXV. 2004.
Walawender, M. J., Shock-produced mosaicism in plagioclase, Charlevoix structure, Quebec. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 14, pp. 74-81. 1977.
Walawender, M. J., X-ray (oscillation) studies of naturally shocked plagioclase from the Charlevoix structure, Quebec, Canada (abstract). Geological Society of America, v. 5, pp. 118-119. 1973.