Gweni-Fada
Chad
N 17° 25'
E 21° 45'
14
< 345
Y
N
S
-
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W. U. , Cooper, G. , Cowan, D. and Vincent, P. M., Aorounga and Gweni Fada impact structures, Chad: Remote sensing, petrography, and geochemistry of target rocks, Meteoritics & Planetary Science, 40, No 9/10 P. 1455 - 1471. 2005.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W.U., Vincent, P. M., Brandt,D., Aorounga and Gweni Fada Impact Structures, Chad, Central Afr.: Petrology and Geochemistry of Target Rocks, LPSC XXIX, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston, TX, (CD-ROM). 1998.
Vincent P.M., Beauvilain, A., Découverte d'un nouveau cratère d'impact météoritique en Afrique: l'astroblème de Gweni-Fada (Ennedi, Sahara du Tchad) (in French). Comptes Rendus de l'Académie des Sciences, v. 323, pp. 987-997. 1996.
Vincent P.M., Beauvilain, A., The circular structure of Gweni-Fada, Ennedi: A second meteorite impact crater in Northern Chad? (abstract). 4th International Workshop of the ESF Scientific Network on "Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth". The Role of Impacts on the Evolution of the Atmosphere and Biosphere with Regard to Short- and Long-Term Changes, pp. 156-157. 1995.
Vincent, P. M., The circular structure of Gweni-Fada, Ennedi: A second meteorite impact crater in Northern Chad? (abstract). 4th International Workshop of the ESF Scientific Network on "Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth". The Role of Impacts on the Evolution of the Atmosphere and Biosphere with regard to Short- and Long-Term Changes, p. 156-157. 1995.