Lawn Hill
Queensland
S 18° 40'
E 138° 39'
18
> 515
Y
N
M
-
Darlington, V. J., Blenkinsop, T. G., Shock microstructures of the Lawn Hill impact structure. Contributions of the Economic Geology Research Unit, vol. 68. 2013. 
Dietz, R. S., McHone, J. F., Astroblemes recently confirmed with shatter cones (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 26, p. 332. 1991.
Haines, P. W., Impact Cratering and Distal Ejecta: The Australian Record. Australian Journal of Earth Sciences 52, P. 481 - 507. 2005.
Roddy, D. J., Shoemaker, E.M., Shoemaker, C.S. and Roddy,J.K., Aerial photography and geologic studies of impact structures in Australia (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XIX, pp. 990-991. 1988.
Shoemaker, E. M., Shoemaker, C. S., The Proterozoic impact record of Australia. AGSO Journal of Australian Geology & Geophysics, v. 16, pp. 379-398. 1996.
Shoemaker, E. M., Shoemaker, C. S., Proterozoic impact record of Australia (abstract). Abstracts of the International Workshop on Meteorite Impact on the Early Earth, Perth, Australia, pp. 47-48. 1990.
Shoemaker, E. M., Shoemaker, C. S., Impact structures of Australia (1987) (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XIX, pp. 1079-1080. 1988.
Stewart, A., Mitchell, K., Shatter cones at the Lawn Hill circular structure, northwestern Queensland: Presumed astrobleme. Australian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 34, pp. 477-485. 1987.
Yang, J., Radulescu, M., Paleo-fluid flow and heat transport at 1575 Ma over an E-W- section in the Northern Lawn HIll Platform, Australia: Theoretical results from finite element modeling, Journal of Geochemical Exploration, 89, P. 445 - 449. 2006.