Lockne
Sweden
N 63° 0'
E 14° 49'
7.5
~ 458
Y
Y
M
-
Agarwal, A., Reznik, B., Kontny, A., Heissler, S., Schilling, F., Lingunite-a high-pressure plagioclase polymorph at mineral interfaces om dp;eritic rock of the Lockne impact structure (Sweden). Scientific Reports, 6:25991. 2016.
Alwmark, C., Alwmark-Holm, S., Ormo, J., and Sturkell, E. Shocked quartz grains from the Malingen Structure, Sweden; evidence for a twin crater of the Lockne impact structure. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, vol.49, pp.1076. 2014.
Alwmark, C., Schmitz, B., Extraterrestrial chromite in the resurge deposits of the early Late Ordovician Lockne crater, central Sweden. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, 253, P. 291 - 303. 2007.
Dalwigk, I.,von., Ormo, J., Formation of resurge gullies at impacts at sea: The Lockne Crater, Sweden, Meteoritics & Planetary Science 36, abs. 3. 2001.
Ekelund, A., Sturkell, E. F. F., Shattercones from the Lockne impact-structure in central Sweden (abstract). Second International Conference. Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth. The Identification and Characterization of Impacts. 1994.
Forsberg, P., Sturkell, E.F.F., Broman, C. and Torssander,P., Stable isotopes and fluid inclusions in cavity grown minerals from the Lockne impact breccia, Jämtland, Sweden (abstract). GFF, v. 118, pp. A98-A99. 1996.
Grahn, Y., Chitinozoan Biostratigraphy of the Early Caradocian Lockne Impact Structure, Jamtland, Sweden, Meteoritics; vol. 32, p. 745-51. 1997.
Grahn, Y., Nolvak, J and Paris,F., Precise chitinozoan dating of Ordovician impact events in Baltoscandia, Journal of Micropalaeontology, v.15, p.21-35. 1996.
Grahn, Y., Nolvak, J., Chitinozoan dating of Ordovician impact events in Sweden and Estonia. A preliminary note. Geologiska Föreningens I Stockholm Förhandlingar, v. 115, pp. 263-264. 1993.
Henkel, H., Pesonen, L. J., Impact craters and craterform structures in Fennoscandia. Tectonophysics, v. 216, pp. 31-40. 1992.
Kenkmann, T., Kiebach, F., Rosenau, M., Raschke, U., Pigowske, A., Mittelhaus, K., Eue, D., Coupled effects of impact and orogeny: is the marine Lockne crater, Sweden, pristine? Meteoritics and Planetary Science 42, 1995-2012.
Lindström, M., Ekvall, J, Hagenfeldt, S E., Sawe, B and Sturkell,E F.F., A well-preserved Cambrian impact exposed in Central Sweden. Geolgische Rundschau, v. 80/1, pp. 201-204. 1991.
Lindström, M., Ormö, J., Sturkell, E.F.F. and Törnberg,R., Geological information from Ordovician marine impact craters (abstract). GFF, v. 118, pp. A99-A100. 1996.
Lindström, M., Presentation of Lockne, our host impact structure (abstract). Second International Conference. Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth. The Identification and Characterization of Impacts. 1994.
Lindstrom, M., Shuvalov, V. , Ivanov, B., Lockne crater as a result of marine-target oblique impact. Planetary and Space Science, Vol. 53, P. 803 - 815. 2005.
Lindström, M., Simon, S, Paul, B and Kessler,K., The Ordovician and its mass movements in the Lockne Area near the Caledonian margin, central Sweden. Geologica et Palaeontologica, v. 17, pp. 17-27. 1983.
Lindström, M., Sturkell, E.F.F., Ormö, J. and Törnberg,R., The Lockne marine impact in the Ordovician of central Sweden (abstract). Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, pp. A80-A81. 1996.
Lindström, M., Sturkell, E.F.F., Törnberg, R. and Ormö,J., The marine impact crater at Lockne, central Sweden. GFF, v. 118, pp. 193-206. 1996.
Ormo, J., Lindstrom, M., Sturkell, E. and Tornberg,R., The Middle Ordovician Lockne crater as a small-scale model for impacts at sea (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Ormo, J., Lindstrom, M., Sturkell, E.F.F., Tornberg, R., von Dalwigk,I., Lockne. A well-displayed marine-target in the heart of Scandinavia, Bolide Impacts on Wet Targets, Geological Society of America Field Forum Abstracts. 2001.
Ormo, J., Lindstrom, M., The Influence of Deep Shelf Sea on the Excavation and Modification of the Marine-Target Crater, the Lockne Crater, Central Sweden, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXV. 2004.
Ormo, J., Lindstrom, M., When a cosmic impact strikes the sea bed, Geol. Mag. V.137(1), p.67-80. 2000.
Ormo, J., Miyamoto, H., Computer modelling of the water resurge at a marine impact: the Lockne crater, Sweden, Deep Sea Research II, v.49, p.983-994. 2002.
Ormo, J., Next step in marine impact studies: combining geological data with numerical simulations for applications in planetary research, Workshop on Impact Cratering. 2003.
Ormo, J., Shuvalov, V. V., Lindstrom,M., Numerical modeling for target water depth estimation of marine-target impact craters, Journal of Geophysical Research, v.107, No.E12. 2002.
Ormö, J., Sturkell, E.F.F. and Törnberg,R., Magnetic model of the Lockne impact crater, central Sweden (abstract). GFF, v. 118, pp. A100-A102. 1996.
Ormoe, J., Sturkell, E., Nolvak, J., Melero-Asensio, I., Frisk, A., and Wikstrom, T. The geology of the Malingen Structure; a probable doublet to the Lockne marine-target impact crater, central Sweden. Meteoritics & planetary Science , vol.49, pp.313. 2014.
Strurkell, E., Ormo, J., Nolvak, J., Wallin,A., Distant ejecta from the Lockne marine-target impact crater, Sweden, Meteorit. Planet. Sci. 35 (2000) 929-936. 2000.
Sturkell, E. F. F., Impact-related Ir anomaly in the Middle Ordovician Lockne impact structure, Jamtland, Sweden, GFF, v 120, p 333-336. 1998.
Sturkell, E. F. F., Lindström, M., Interrelation between the Lockne impact structure and regional left-lateral strike-slips (abstract). Second International Conference. Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth. The Identification and Characterization of Impacts. 1994.
Sturkell, E. F. F., Lindström, M., Mass balance of the Lockne impact structure, central Sweden (abstract). GFF, v. 118, pp. A102-A103. 1996.
Sturkell, E. F. F., Ormö, J., Magnetometry of the marine, Ordovician Lockne impact structure, Jämtland, Sweden. Journal of Applied Geophysics, v. 38, pp. 195-207. 1998.
Sturkell, E. F. F., Resurge morphology of the marine Lockne impact crater, Jämtland, central Sweden. Geol. Mag., v. 135, pp. 121-127. 1998.
Sturkell, E. F. F., The origin of the marine Lockne impact structure, Jämtland. Ph.D. thesis Ph.D. Thesis, Stockholm University, Stockholm,. 1998.
Sturkell, E. F. F., Tremadocian Ceratopyge limestone identified by means of conodonts, in Jämtland, Sweden. Geologiska Föreningens i Stockholm Förhandlingar (GFF), v. 113, pp. 185-188. 1991.
Sturkell, E. R. R., Ormö, J., Impact-related clastic injections in the marine Ordovician Lockne impact structure, Central Sweden. Sedimentology, v. 44, pp. 793-804. 1997.
Sturkell, E., Ormo, J., and Lepinette, A. Early modification stage (preresurge) sediment mobilization in the Lockne concentric, marine-target crater, Sweden. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, vol.48, pp.321. 2013.
Sturkell, E., Ormo, J., Nolvak, J., Wallin,A., Distant ejecta from the Lockne marine-target impact crater, Sweden. Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v.35, No.5, p.929-936. 2000.
Sturkell, F. F., Ormo, J., Impact-Related Clastic Injections in the Marine Ordovician Lockne Impact Structure, Central Sweden, Sedimentology; vol. 44, no. 5, p. 793-804. 1997.
Sundblad, K., Lead isotopic composition of galena associated with the Early Palaeozoic meteorite impact structures at Lockne (Sweden) and Kardla (Estonia) (abstract). European Science Foundation, Second International Conference. Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth. The Identification and Characterization of Impacts.,. 1994.
Therriault, A. M., Lindström, M., Planar deformation features in quartz grains from resurge deposit of the Lockne structure, Sweden (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 1385-1386. 1994.
Therriault, A. M., Lindström, M., Planar deformation features in quartz grains from the resurge deposit of the Lockne structure, Sweden. Meteoritics, v. 30, pp. 700-703. 1995.
Törnberg, R., Impact-related resurge sedimentology as exemplified by the Lockne, Tvären and Kärdla structures (abstract). GFF, v. 118, p. A102. 1996.
von Dalwigk, I., Ormo, J., Formation of resurge gullies at impacts at sea: the Lockne crater, Sweden, abstract, ESF IMPACT Workshop on Oceanic Impacts, Alfred Wegener Institute Bremerhaven, pp. 23-26. 1999.
von Dalwigk, I., Ormo, J., Formation of resurge gullies at impacts at sea: The Lockne crater, Sweden, Meteoritics & Planetary Science, March 2001, v.36 (is. 3), pp. 359-369. 2001.
von Dalwigk, I., Ormo, J., The formation of resurge gullies during impacts at sea: the Lockne crater, Sweden, Bolide Impacts on Wet Targets, Geological Society of America Field Forum Abstracts. 2001.
Wickman, F. E., Possible impact structures in Sweden. A. Boden and K.G. Eriksson, eds., in Deep Drilling in Crystalline Bedrock, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, p. 298-327. 1988.