Luizi
Democratic Republic of Congo
S 10° 10'
E 28° 00'
17
< 573
Y
N
S
-
Ferrière, L., Lubala, F. R. T., Osinski, G. R. and Kaseti, P. K. 2011. The newly-confirmed Luizi impact structure, Democratic Republic of Congo – Insights into central uplift formation and post-impact erosion. Geology, 39(9), pp. 851-854.
Ferrière, L., Lubala, F. R. T., Osinski, G. R. and Kaseti, P. K. 2011. The Luizi structure (Democratic Republic of Congo) – First confirmed meteorite impact crater in Central Africa, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXXII, (abstract #1637).
Ferrière, L., Osinski, G. R. 2011. The new Luizi impact structure (Democratic Republic of Congo) and implications for central peak and peak ring formation, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXVIII, (abstract #1642).