Manson
Iowa, U.S.A.
N 42° 35'
W 94° 33'
35
73.8 ± 0.3
N
Y
M
Chondrite
Abramov, O., Kring, D. A., Finite-difference modeling of impact-induced hydrothermal systems, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXIV. 2003.
Anderson, R. R., Alexander, E. C., Schilling, K. E., Peate, D. W., & Dorale, J., The geology and geochemistry of ancient groundwater in the central peak aquifer of the manson impact structure, iowa. Paper presented at the , 43(5) 29-29. 2011.
Anderson, R. R., Hartung, J. B., The Manson impact structure; its contribution to impact materials observed at the Cretaceous/Tertiary boundary. Proceedings Lunar and Planetary Science Conference 22nd, pp. 101-110. 1992.
Anderson, R. R., Hartung, J. B., The structural configuration of the Manson impact structure, Iowa, as interpreted from seismic data and confirmed by drill samples (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXII, pp. 25-26. 1991.
Anderson, R. R., Hartung, J.B., Reagan, M.K., Bell, M.S. and Plocher,O., First results from the Manson impact structure core-drilling project: Preliminary observations and interpretations from the M-1 core (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIII, pp. 31-32. 1992.
Anderson, R. R., Hartung, J.B., Roddy, D.J. and Shoemaker,E.M., Research core drilling in the Manson impact structure, Iowa (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 2-3. 1992.
Anderson, R. R., Hartung, J.B., Witzke, B.J., Shoemaker, E.M. and Roddy,D.J., Preliminary results of the U.S.Geological Survey - Iowa Department of Natural Resources Geological Survey Bureau Manson Core Drilling Project. Geological Society of America Special Paper 293, pp. 237-247. 1994.
Anderson, R. R., Witzke, B. J., Bunte breccia-like deposits within the Manson impact structure (Iowa); evidence for impact into a shallow marine environment? (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 31-32. 1994.
Anderson, R. R., Witzke, B.J. and Hartung,J.B., Preliminary descriptions of impact rocks recovered by recent core drilling in the Manson impact structure (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 28, p. 317. 1993.
Anderson, R. R., Witzke, B.J. and Roddy,D.J., The drilling of the 1991-1992 Geological Survey Bureau and U.S. Geological Survey Manson impact structure research cores. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 45-88. 1996.
Anderson, R. R., Witzke, B.J., Hartung, J.B., Shoemaker, E.M. and Roddy,D.J., Descriptions and preliminary interpretations of cores recovered from the Manson impact structure (Iowa) (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 35-36. 1993.
Anderson, R. R., Witzuke, B.J., Hammond, R.H. and Watkins,D.K., Preliminary investigation of shocked grains (Manson ejecta?), paleontology, & depositional features in the Crow Creek member, Pierre shale (Upper Cretaceous) of SE South Dakota and NE Nebraska, & its effect on U. Cretaceous biota(abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVI, pp. 43-44. 1995.
Anderson, R.R., Witzke, B.J., The terminal Cretaceous Manson impact structure in north-central Iowa: a window into the late Cretaceous history of the eastern margin of the Western Cretaceous Seaway, Perspectives on the eastern margin of the Cretaceous Western Interior Basin, pp. 197-210, 1994
Arthur, M.A., When worlds collide: the end-Cretaceous global crisis, Earth & Mineral Sciences, v. 62, pp. 3-12, 1993
Bell, M. S., Reagan, M.K. anderson, R.R. and Foster Jr.,C.T., Petrography of the crystalline breccias from the Manson M-1 core: Implications for impact breccia emplacement (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 28, pp. 321-322. 1993.
Bell, M. S., Reagan, M.K. anderson, R.R. and Foster, C.T.,Jr., Petrography of crystalline clast breccias from the Manson M-1 core. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 221-233. 1996.
Bell, M. S., Reagan, M.K. anderson, R.R. and Foster, Jr.,C.T., Petrography and preliminary interpretations of the crystalline breccias from the Manson M-1 core (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 87-88. 1993.
Blum, J. D., Chamberlain, C.P., Higston, M.P. and Koeberl,C., Neodymium, strontium and oxygen isotope investigation of the target stratigraphy and impact melt rock from the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 317-324. 1996.
Blum, J. D., Chamberlain, C.P., Higston, M.P., Koeberl, C., Marin, L.E., Schuraytz, C. and Sharpton,V.L., Isotopic comparison of K/T boundary imapct glass with melt rock from the Chicxulub and Manson impact structures, Nature, v. 364, pp. 325-327. 1993.
Blum, J. D., Chamberlain, C.P., Hingston, M.P. and Koeberl,C., Strontium & oxygen isotope study of M-1, M-3 & M-4 drill core samples from the Manson impact structure, Iowa: Comparison with Haitian K-T impact glasses (abs.), Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 135-136. 1993.
Boer, R. H., Reimold, W.U., Koeberl, C. and Kesler,S.E., Fluid inclusion studies on drill core samples from the Manson impact crater: Evidence for post-impact hydrothermal activity. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 377-382. 1996.
Boer, R. H., Reimold, W.U., Koeberl, C., Kesler,S.E., Fluid Inclusion Studies on Drill Core Samples from the Manson Impact Crater: Evidence for Post-Impact Hydrothermal Activity (abstract), GSA Special Paper 302 p. 377. 1996.
Bostock, H. H., The Clearwater complex, New Quebec. Geological Survey of Canada Bulletin, v. 178, 63 p. 1969.
Boynton, W. V., Baedecker, P.A., Chou, C.-L., Robinson, K.L. and Wasson,J.T., Mixing and transport of lunar surface materials: Evidence obtained by the determination of lithophile, sideropohile, and volatile elements. Proceedings Lunar and Planetary Science Conference 6th, pp. 2241-2259. 1975.
Buchanan, P. C., Koeberl, C., Planar deformation features in quartz grains from the Manson impact structure, Iowa, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v 33, n 4, p A24-A25. 1998.
Cisowski, S. M., Paleomagnetism of Manson structure cores inconsistent with a K/T link (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XIX, pp. 188-189. 1988.
Cockell, C. S., Lee, P., The Biology of Impact Craters - a review. Biol. Rev., 77, P. 279 - 310. 2002.
Crossey, L. J., Kudo, A. M., McCarville., Post-impact hydrothermal systems: Manson impact structure, Manson, Iowa (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 299-300. 1994.
Crossey, L. J., McCarville, P. M., Post-impact hydrothermal systems: Manson impact structure. Proceedings of the VIIth International Symposium on the Observation of the Continental Crust Through Drilling, Sante Fe, New Mexico, pp. 211-214. 1994.
Crossey, L. J., McCarville, P., Post-impact alteration of the Manson impact structure (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 351-352. 1993.
Crossey, L. J., McCarville, P., Post-impact hydrothermal systems: Manson impact structure (abstract). Proceedings of the VII th International Symposium on the Observation of the Continental Crust Through Drilling, pp. 211-214. 1993.
French, B. M., Impact event at the Cretaceous-Tertiary boundary: A possible site. Science, v. 226, pp. 353. 1984.
Grieve, R. A. F., Cintala, M. J., An analysis of differential impact melt-crater scaling and implications for the terrestrial impact record. Meteoritics, v. 27, pp. 526-538. 1992.
Grieve, R. A. F., Dence, M.R. and Robertson,P.B., Cratering processes: As interpreted from the occurrence of impact melts. In: Impact and Explosion Cratering (D.J. Roddy, R.O. Pepin and R.B. Merrill, eds.), pp. 791-814, Pergamon Press, New York. 1977.
Grieve, R. A. F., Floran, R. J., Manicouagan impact melt, Quebec, 2. Chemical interactions with basement and formational processes. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 83, pp. 2761-2771. 1978.
Grieve, R. A. F., Manson structure implicated. Nature, v. 340, pp. 428-429. 1989.
Grieve, R. A. F., Terrestrial impact: The record in the rocks. Meteoritics, v. 26, pp. 175-194. 1991.
Grieve, R. A. F., The record of impact on Earth: Implications for a major Cretaceous/Tertiary impact event. Geological Society of America, Special Paper 190, pp. 25-37. 1982.
Gurov, E. P., Gurova, E. P., Impact structures on the Earth's surface (in Russian). Geologicheskii Zhurnal, v. 47, pp. 117-124. 1987.
Hartung J.B., Anderson, R. R., A brief history on investigations of the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 31-43. 1996.
Hartung, J. B., Anderson, R. R., A Brief History on Investigations of the Manson Impact Structure (Abstract), GSA Special Paper 302 p. 31. 1996.
Hartung, J. B., Anderson, R. R., A compilation of information and data on the Manson impact structure. Lunar and Planetary Institute Technical Report 88-08, 32 p. 1988.
Hartung, J. B., Anderson, R. R., A summary of data on the Manson impact structure (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XIX, pp. 455-456. 1988.
Hartung, J. B., Anderson, R. R., Manson impact structure rocks: Evidence for impact melting (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXI, pp. 465-466. 1990.
Hartung, J. B., Izett, G.A., Naeser, C.W., Kunk, M.J. and Sutter,J.F., The Manson, Iowa, impact structure and the Cretaceous-Tertiary boundary event (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XVII, pp. 313-314. 1986.
Hartung, J. B., Kunk, M.J. and Anderson,R.R., Geology, geophysics, and geochronology of the Manson impact structure. Global Catastrophes in Earth History, Geological Society of America, Special Paper 247, pp. 207-221. 1990.
Hartung, J., Kracher, A. anderson, R. and Plocher,O., Manson impact structure rocks: Evidence for an exotic component (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIII, pp. 497-498. 1992.
Hartung, J., Manson structure team will help guide research. EOS, v. 68, pp. 1641. 1987.
Holtzman, A. F., Gravity study of the Manson "Disturbed Area", Calhoun, Pocahontas, Humboldt, and Webster Counties, Iowa (thesis). Master's Thesis, University of Iowa, 48 p. 1970.
Hoppin, R. A., Dryden, J. E., An unusual occurrence of pre-Cambrian crystalline rocks beneath glacial drift near Manson, Iowa. Journal of Geology, v. 66, pp. 694-699. 1958.
Hörz, F., Ostertag, R. and Rainey,D.A., Bunte Breccia of the Ries: Continuous deposits of large impact craters. Reviews of Geophysics and Space Physics, v. 21, pp. 1667-1725. 1983.
Izett, G. A., Cobban, W. A., Size and distribution of shocked mineral grains in the Pierre shale (Late Cretaceous) of South Dakota related to the Manson, Iowa, impact event (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 607-608. 1994.
Izett, G. A., Cobban, W.A., Dalrymple, G.B. and Obradovich,J.D., 40Ar/39Ar age of the Manson impact structure, Iowa, and correlative impact ejecta in the Crow Creek Member of the Pierre Shale (Upper Cretaceous), South Dakota and Nebraska. GSA Bulletin, v. 110, pp. 361-376. 1998.
Izett, G. A., Cobban, W.A., Obradovich, J.D. and Kunk,M.J., The Manson impact structure: 40Ar/39Ar age and its distal impact ejecta in the Pierre shale in southeastern South Dakota. Science, v. 262, pp. 729-732. 1993.
Izett, G. A., Reynolds, R.L., Rosenbaum, J.G. and Nishi,J.M., A discontinuous melt sheet in the Manson impact structure (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, p. 705-706. 1993.
Jolliff, B. L., Korotev, R.L., Rockow, K.M. and Haskin,L.A., Manson impact structure: The impact-melt component (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVI, pp. 693-694. 1995.
Jolliff, B. L., Rockow, K.M., Korotev, R.L., Haskin, L.A., Crossey, L.J. and Mc Carville,P.M., Geochemical study of cores from the Manson impact structure. In: Proceedings of the VIIth International Symposium on the Observation of the Continental Crust Through Drilling, Santa Fe, New Mexico, pp. 215-218. 1994.
Jolliff, B. L., Rockow, K.M., Korotev, R.L., Haskin, L.A., McCarville, P.M. and Crossey,L.J., Geochemical study of cores from the Manson Impact Structure, Proceedings of the VIIth International Symposium on the Observation of the Continental Crust Through Drilling, pp. 215-218. 1994.
Jones, M. C., McCormick, G.R. and Anderson,R.R., Preliminary clay-mineral investigation of some impactites recovered by core drilling in the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 341-346. 1996.
Katongo, C., et al., Geochemistry and shock petrography of the Crow Creek Member, South Dakota, USA: Ejecta from the 74-Ma Manson impact structure, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v. 39, pp. 31-51, 2004
Keiswetter, D., Black, R. and Steeples,D., Seismic reflection analysis of the Manson Impact Structure, Iowa. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 101, pp. 5823-5834. 1996.
Keiswetter, D., Black, R. and Steeples,D., Structure of the terrace terrane, Manson Impact Structure, Iowa, interpreted from high-resolution, seismic reflection data. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 105-113. 1996.
Keiswetter, D., Black, R., Steeples, D.W. and Anderson,R.R., High-resolution seismic reflection survey at the Manson crater, Iowa (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 781-782. 1993.
Koeberl, C., Anderson, R. R., Manson and company: Impact structures in the United States. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 1-29. 1996.
Koeberl, C., Anderson, R.R., Boer, R.H., Blum, J.D., Chamberlain, C.P., Kracher, A.,Reimold,., Mineralogical, petrological, and geochemical studies of drill cores from the Manson impact structure (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 719-720. 1994.
Koeberl, C., Anderson, R.R., Hartung, J.B. and Reimold,W.U., Manson impact structure, Iowa: First geochemical results for drill core M-1 (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 811-812. 1993.
Koeberl, C., Hartung, J. B., Geochemistry of Manson impact structure rocks: Target rocks, impact glasses, and microbreccias. Proceedings Lunar and Planetary Science Conference 22nd, pp. 111-126. 1992.
Koeberl, C., Martinez-Ruiz, F., The Stratigraphic Record of Impact Events: A Short Overview, Impact Markers in the Stratigraphic Record p. 1 - 40. 2003.
Koeberl, C., Milkereit, B., Continental Drilling and the Study of Impact Craters and Processes - an ICDP Perspective, In: Continental Scientific Drilling (eds. Harms, U., Koeberl, C., and Zoback, M.D.), Springer, Heidelberg, p. 95-161. 2007.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W.U. anderson, R.R. and Kracher,A., Origin of impact melt breccias and suevites in drill cores from the Manson impact structure (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVI, pp. 771-772. 1995.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W.U., Kracher, A., Träxler, B., Vormaier, A. and Körner,W., Mineralogical, petrological, and geochemical studies of drill core samples from the Manson impact structure, Iowa. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 145-219. 1996.
Koeberl, C., Shirey, S. B., Re-Os isotope study of rocks from the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special paper 302, pp. 331-339. 1996.
Koeberl, C., Shirey, S.B., Re-Os isotope systematics as a diagnostic tool for the study of impact craters and distal ejecta, Palaeogeography, Palaeoclimatology, Palaeoecology, v. 132, pp. 25-46, 1997
Korotev, R. L., Compositional variations in Apolo 16 impact-melt breccias and inferences for the geology and bombardment history of the Moon. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, in press. 1994.
Korotev, R. L., Jolliff, B.L., Rockow, K.M., Haskin, L.A. and Crossey,L.J., A preliminary geochemical study of crystalline melt from the Manson impact structure (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 28, pp. 383-384. 1993.
Korotev, R. L., Rockow, K.M., Jolliff, B.L., Haskin, L.A. , McCarville, P. and Crossey,L.J., Geochemical comparison of four cores from the Manson impact structure (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 729-230. 1994.
Korotev, R. L., Rockow, K.M., Jolliff, B.L., Haskin, L.A., McCarville, P. and Crossey,L.J., Geochemical comparison of four cores from the Manson impact structure, Geological Society of America Special Paper on the Manson Impact Structure, in press. 1995.
Korotev, R. L., Rockow, K.M., Jolliff, B.L., Haskin, L.A., McCarville, P. and Crossey,L.J., Geochemical comparison of four cores from the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 275-315. 1996.
Korotev, R. L., Rockow, K.M., Jolliff, B.L., Haskin, L.A., McCarville, P., Crossey,L.J., Geochemical Comparaison of Four Cores from the Manson Impact Structure (Abstract), GSA Special Paper 302 p. 275. 1996.
Kracher, A., Anderson, R.R. and Koeberl,C., Compostion of breccia matrices from the Manson M-1 drill core (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 29, pp. 485. 1994.
Kunk, M. J., Izett, G.A. and Sutter,J.F., 40Ar/39Ar age spectra of shocked K-feldspar suggests K-T boundary age for Manson, Iowa, impact structure. EOS Trans., AGU, v. 68, p. 1514. 1987.
Kunk, M. J., Izett, G.A., Haugerud, R.A. and Sutter,J.F., 40Ar-39Ar dating of the Manson impact structure: A Cretaceous-Tertiary boundary crater candidate. Science, v. 244, pp. 1565-1568. 1989.
Kunk, M. J., Snee, L.W., French, B.M., Harlan, S.S. and McGee,J.J., Preliminary 40Ar/39Ar age spectrum and laser probe dating of the M1 core of the Manson impact structure, Iowa: A K-T boundary crater candidate (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 835-836. 1993.
Leroux, H., Doukhan, J. -C., A transmission electron microscope study of shocked quartz from the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 267-274. 1996.
Masaitis, V. L., Danilin, A.N., Maschak, M.S., Raykhlin, A.I., Selivanovskaya, T.V. and Shadenkov,Ye.M., The Geology of Astroblemes (in Russian). Leningrad, Nedra, 231 p. 1980.
McCarville, P., Crossey, L. J., Post-impact hydrothermal alteration of the Manson impact structure (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 861-862. 1994.
McCarville, P., Crossey, L. J., Postimpact hydrothermal alteration of the Manson impact structure (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 29, pp. 499-500. 1994.
McCarville, P., Crossey, L. J., Post-impact hydrothermal alteration of the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 347-376. 1996.
McCarville, P., Postimpact hydrothermal alteration of the Manson impact structure, Manson, Iowa. M.S. Thesis, The University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 186 p. 1994.
McHone J F., Dietz, R. S., Earth's multiple impact craters and astroblemes (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science, v. XXIII, pp. 887-888. 1992.
Naumov, M. V., Zonation of hydrothermal alteration in the central uplift of the Puchezh-Katunki astrobleme (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 28, pp. 408-409. 1993.
Newsom, H. E., Graup, G., Sewards, T. and Keil,K., Fluidization and hydrothermal alteration of the suevite deposit at the Ries crater, West Germany, and implications for Mars. Proceedings Lunar and Planetary Science Conference 17th, Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 91, E239-251. 1986.
Officer, C.B., Carter, N.L., A review of the structure, petrology, and dynamic deformation characteristics of some enigmatic terrestrial structures, Earth Science Reviews, v. 30, pp. 1-49, 1991
Ormo, J., Lindstrom, M., When a cosmic impact strikes the sea bed, Geol. Mag. V.137(1), p.67-80. 2000.
Pernicka, E., Kaether, D. and Koeberl,C., Siderophile element concentrations in drill core samples from the Manson crater. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 325-330. 1996.
Pisarik, R., Petershagen, J., Wilke, K. and Sendlein,L.V.A., Magnetic studies of the Manson disturbed area (abstract). Geological Society of America, v. 5, 642 p. 1977.
Plescia, J. B., Gravity investigation of the Manson impact structure, Iowa (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 1157-1158. 1993.
Plescia, J. B., Gravity investigation of the Manson impact structure, Iowa. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 89-104. 1996.
Premo, W. R., Nd-Sr isotopic signature of the Pierre shale: Target material at the Manson impact site and source of the Haitian tektites (K-T Boundary)? (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIII, pp. 1099-1100. 1992.
Reagan, M. K., C.T. Foster, Jr., Bell, M.S. and Anderson,R.R., Preferential feldspar comminution in impact melt breccias from the M-1 core of the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 235-243. 1996.
Reagan, M. K., Foster, J r. C. T. and Bell,M S., Origin of the upper crystalline-clast bearing suevite in the Manson M-1 core (abstract). 1993 Fall Meeting, AGU, v. Fall, p. 386. 1993.
Reimold, W. U., Reid, A.M. and Therriault,A.M., Observations on granitic clasts in granophyre from the Vredefort Dome (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXI, pp. 1009-1010. 1990.
Roddy, D. J., Shoemaker, E. M., Manson impact structure research program: Summary through January 1995 (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVI, pp. 1181-1182. 1995.
Roddy, D. J., Shoemaker, E.M. and Anderson,R.R., Manson impact structure research program: Summary through February 1994. In: Proceedings of the VIIth International Symposium on the Observation of the Continental Crust Through Drilling, Santa Fe, New Mexico, pp. 203-207. 1994.
Roddy, D. J., Shoemaket, E.M. and Anderson,R.R., The Manson impact crater: Estimation of the energy of formation, possible size of the impacting asteroid or comet, and ejecta volume and mass (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 1211-1212. 1993.
Schreyer, W., Medenbach, O., CO2-rich fluid inclusions along planar elements of quartz in basement rocks of the Vredefort dome, South Africa. Contributions of Mineralogy and Petrology, v. 77, pp. 93-100. 1981.
Schultz, P. H., Anderson, R. R., Asymmetry of the Manson impact structure: Evidence for impact angle and direction. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 397-417. 1996.
Shoemaker, E. M., Roddy, D.J. and Anderson,R.R., Research program on the Manson impact structure, Iowa (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 1301-1302. 1993.
Short, N. M., Gold, D. P., Petrographic analysis of selected core materials from the Manson (Iowa) impact structure (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 28, pp. 436-437. 1993.
Short, N. M., Gold, D. P., Petrography of shock features in the 1953 Manson 2-A drill core (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 1303-1304. 1993.
Short, N. M., Gold, D. P., Petrography of shocked rocks from the central peak at the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 245-265. 1996.
Smith, T. A., Sendlein, L. V. A., Geophysical study of the Manson impact crater (abstract). EOS, v. 52, pp. 264-265. 1971.
Steiner M B., Shoemaker, E. M., The late cretaceous Manson impact structure (abstract). 1993 Fall Meeting, AGU, v. Fall, p. 386. 1993.
Steiner M.B., Shoemaker, E. M., A hypothesized Manson impact tsunami: Paleomagnetic and stratigraphic evidence in the Crow Creek Member, Pierre Shale. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 419-432. 1996.
Steiner, M. B., Implications of magneto-mineralogic characteristics of the Manson and Chicxulub impact rocks. Geological Society of America Special Paper 307, pp. 89-104. 1996.
Steiner, M. B., Shoemaker, E. M., Two-polarity magnetization in the Manson impact breccia (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 1347-1348. 1993.
Steiner, M. B., Unusual magnetization characteristics of Manson and Chicxulub impact structures: Implications for post-impact time (abstract), Geological Society of America, 1995 Annual Meeting, pp. A-349. 1995.
Stöffler, D., Knöll, H.-D. and Maerz,U., Terrestrial and lunar impact breccias and the classification of lunar highland rocks. Proceedings Lunar and Planetary Science Conference 10th, pp. 639-675. 1979.
Stöffler, D., Shock metamorphism of quartz in nature and experiment: A review (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 28, pp. 445. 1993.
Sutherland, F. L., Meteoritic versus volcanic events at the Cretaceous/Tertiary boundary - An Australian perspective (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 25, pp. 412-413. 1990.
Therriault, A. M., Petrographic analysis of shocked quartz in the central uplift of the Manson structure, Iowa. B.Sc. (Honours) Thesis, University of Ottawa, unpublished. 1989.
Van Schmus, W. R., Bickford, M.E. anderson, R.R., Shearer, C.K., Papike, J.J. and Nelson,B.K., Quimby, Iowa, scientific drill hole: Definition of Precambrian crustal features in northwestern Iowa. Geology, v. 17, pp. 536-539. 1989.
Van Schmus, W.R., et al., New insights into the southern margin of the Archean-Proterozoic boundary in the north-central United States based on U-Pb, Sm-Nd, and Ar-Ar geochronology, Precambrian Research, v. 157, pp. 80-105, 2007
Varricchio, D.J., et al., Soot and palynologic analysis of Manson impact-related strata (Upper Cretaceous) of Iowa and South Dakota, USA, Cretaceous Research, v. 30, pp. 127-134, 2009
Varricchio, D.J., et al., Tracing the Manson impact event across the Western Interior Cretaceous Seaway, Special Paper of the Geological Society of America, Issue 465, pp. 269-299, 2010
Varricchio, D.J., Koeberl, C., Raven, R.F., Wolbach, W.S., Elsik, W.C., et al, Tracing the Manson impact event across the Western Interior Cretaceous Seaway. Special Paper- Geological Society of America, vol.465, pp.269-299. 2010.
Varricchio, D.J., Raven, R.F., Wolbach, W.S., Elsik, W.C., Witzke, B.J., Soot and palynologic analysis of Mason impact-related strata (Upper Cretaceous) of Iowa and South Dakota, USA. Cretaceous Research, vol.30, pp.127-134. 2009.
Weber, R.D., Watkins, D.K., Evidence from the Crow Creek Member (Pierre Shale) for an impact-induced resuspension event in the late Cretaceous Western Interior Seaway, Geology, v. 35, pp. 1119-1122, 2007
Westbroek, H., Stewart, R., The formation, morphology, and economic potential of meteorite impact craters, CREWES Research Report v. 8, p. 1-26. 1996.
Witzke B.J., Anderson, R. R., Sedimentary-clast breccias of the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 115-144. 1996.
Witzke, B. J., Anderson, R. R., Iowa's Manson crater; the largest impact site in the U.S. Iowa Geology, v. 13, pp. 4-7. 1988.
Witzke, B. J., General stratigraphy of the Phanerozoic and Keweenawan sequence, M.G. Eischeid #1 drillhole, Carroll Co., Iowa. In: The Amoco M.G. Eischeid #1 Deep Petroleum Test, Carroll County, Iowa, Special Report Series No. 2. Iowa Department of Natural Resources, pp. 39-57. 1990.
Witzke, B. J., Hammond, R.H. and Anderson,R.R., Deposition of the Crow Creek Member, Campanian, South Dakota and Nebraska. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 433-456. 1996.
Yurk, Yu Yu., Yeremenko, G.K. and Polkanov,Yu.A., The Boltysh depression: A fossil meteorite crater. International Geology Review, v. 18, pp. 196-202. 1975.
Zeitler, P. K., Kunk, M. J., Age and thermochronology of K-feldspars from the Manson impact structure (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 1567-1568. 1993.
Zeitler, P., 40Ar/39Ar thermochronology of shocked feldspars from the Manson impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 302, pp. 383-396. 1996.