Mjølnir
Norway
N 73° 48'
E 29° 40'
40
142.0 ± 2.6
N
Y
S
-
Dypvik, H., Attrep Jr, M., Geochemical signals of the late Jurassic, marine Mjølnir impact, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v 34, p 393-406. 1999.
Dypvik, H., Attrep, Jr,M., The Mjølnir Impact- Environmental Consequences, LPSC XXIX, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston, TX, (CD-ROM). 1998.
Dypvik, H., et al., Early post-impact sedimentation around the central high of the Mjølnir impact crater (Barents Sea, Late Jurassic), Sedimentary Geology, v. 168, pp. 227-247, 2004
Dypvik, H., et al., Marine impacts and environmental consequences - Drilling of the Mjølnir structure, the Barents Sea, Scientific Drilling, Issue 6, pp. 55-57, 2008
Dypvik, H., Ferrell Jr., R.E., Sandbakken, P.T., The clay mineralogy of sediments related to the marine Mjølnir impact crater, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v.38, pp. 1437-1450, 2003
Dypvik, H., Ferrell, R. E.,Jr., Clay mineral alteration associated with a meteorite impact in the marine environment (Barents Sea). Clay Minerals, v. 33, pp. 51-64. 1998.
Dypvik, H., Gudlaugsson, S.T., Tsikalas, F., Attrep, M. Jr., Ferrell, R.E. Jr., Krinsley, D.H., Mork, A., Faleide, J.I. and Nagy,J., Mjølnir structure: An impact crater in the Barents sea. Geology, v. 24, pp. 779-782. 1996.
Dypvik, H., Jansa, L. F., Sedimentary signatures and processes during marine bolide impacts: a review, Sedimentary Geology v. 161, p. 309-337. 2003.
Dypvik, H., Kalleson, E., Mechanisms of late synimpact to early postimpact crater sedimentation in marine-target impact structures, Special Paper of the Geological Society of America, Issue 465, pp. 301-318, 2010
Dypvik, H., Smelror, M. , Sandbakken, P. T. , Salvigsen, O. and Kalleson, E., Traces of the marine Mjolnir impact event, Palaeogeography, Palaeoclimatology, Palaeoecology, 241, P. 621 - 636. 2006.
Dypvik, H., The Mjolnir Impact - a Late Jurassic / Early Cretaceous impact in the Paleo-Barents Sea, Bolide Impacts on Wet Targets, Geological Society of America Field Forum Abstracts. 2001.
Glimsdal, S., Tsunami generation and propagation from the Mjølnir asteroid impact, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v. 42, pp. 1473-1493, 2007
Grieve, R. A. F., When will enough be enough? Nature, v. 363, pp. 670-671. 1993.
Group, Mjolnir Research., Mjølnir - A probable impact structure in the Barents Sea. Department of Geology, University of Oslo in association with IKU Petroleum Research, Trodheim, p. 67. 1995.
Gudlaugsson, S. T., Large impact crater in the Barents Sea, Geology, v. 21, pp. 291-294. 1993.
Gudlaugsson, S. T., Tsikalas, F., Eldholm, O. and Faleide,J.I., Geophysical modeling of the Mjølnir impact structure, Barents Sea (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Gudlaugsson, S. T., Tsikalas, F., Faleide, J.I. and Dypvik,H., Impact origin of the Mjølnir structure, Barents Sea (abstract), European Science Foundation, Second International Conference. Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth. The Identification and Characterization of Impacts,. 1994.
Hammer, O., Hydrocarbon seeps from close to the Jurassic-Cretaceous boundary, Svalbard, Palaeogeography, Palaeoclimatology, Palaeoecology, v. 306, pp. 15-26, 2011
Koeberl, C., Milkereit, B., Continental Drilling and the Study of Impact Craters and Processes - an ICDP Perspective, In: Continental Scientific Drilling (eds. Harms, U., Koeberl, C., and Zoback, M.D.), Springer, Heidelberg, p. 95-161. 2007.
Langenhorst, F., Dypvik, H., Microstructural characteristics of shocked quartz from ejecta of the submarine Mjølnir impact structure, Barents Sea (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science, v. XXVII, pp. 727-728. 1996.
Ormo, J., Lindstrom, M., When a cosmic impact strikes the sea bed, Geol. Mag. V.137(1), p.67-80. 2000.
Ormo, J., Next step in marine impact studies: combining geological data with numerical simulations for applications in planetary research, Workshop on Impact Cratering. 2003.
Sandbakken, P.T., Langenhorst, F., Dypvik, H., Shock metamorphism of quartz at the submarine Mjølnir impact crater, Barents Sea, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v. 40, pp. 1363-1375, 2005
Shuvalov, V., Dypvik, H., Ejecta formation and crater development of the Mjølnir impact, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v. 39, pp. 467-479, 2004
Shuvalov, V.V., Trubestkaya, I.A., Numerical modeling of marine target impacts, Solar System Research, v. 36, pp. 417-430, 2002
Shuvalov., Dypvik, H. and Tsikalas,F., Numerical simulations of the Mjolnir marine impact crater. Journal of Geophysical Research, v.107, E7, p.?. 2002.
Smelror, M., Dypvik, H., Mork., Phytoplankton Blooms in the Jurassic-Cretaceous Boundary Beds of the Barents Sea Possibly Induced by Mjolnir Impact, Buffetaut, E. and Koeberl, C. (eds.). Geological and biological effects of impact events. Berlin ; New York : Springer., p.69-82. 2002.
Smelror, M., R.A. Kelly, H.Dypvik. A. Mørk,J.Nagy and F.Tsikalas., Mjølnir (Barents Sea) meteorite impact ejecta offers a Volgian – Ryazanian boundary marker. Newsl. Stratigr., v.38, p.129 - 140. 2001.
Tsikalas, F. and Faleide, J.I., Reconstruction of the original impact-crater relief for Mjolnir, Chicxulub and Bosumtwi impact craters reveals surprisingly shallow structures: Did we miss something?, Lunar and Planetary Science Conference XXXVIII, abstract #1014. 2007.
Tsikalas, F., A geophysical study of Mjølnir: a proposed impact structure in the Barents Sea. Ph.D Ph.D. Thesis, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway, 97. 1997.
Tsikalas, F., Dypvik, H., Faleide, J.I., Smelror,M., Towards a better understanding of marine impact processes: What a potential drilling of the Mjolnir Crater (Barents Sea) has to offer, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXV. 2004.
Tsikalas, F., Faleide, J. I., Eldholm, O., Dypvik,H., Seismic correlation of the Mjolnir marine impact crater to shallow boreholes, In: Impact Studied (Impacts in Precambrian Shields) eds. Plado, J., Pesonsen, L. J. Springer-Verlag, Berlin, Heidelberg, p. 307-321. 2002.
Tsikalas, F., Faleide, J. I., Near-field erosional features at the Mjolnir impact crater: the role of marine sedimentary target, In: Impact Studied (Cratering in Marine Environments and on Ice) eds. Dypvik, H., Burchell, M., Claeys, P. Springer-Verlag, Berlin, Heidelberg, p. 39-55. 2003.
Tsikalas, F., Faleide, J. I., Reconstruction of the Original Impact-Crater Relief for Mjolnir, Chicxulub and Bosumtwi Impact Craters Reveals Suprisingly Shallow Structures: Did We Miss Something? Lunar and Planetary Science XXXVIII (1014.pdf). 2007.
Tsikalas, F., Faleide, J.I., Gudlaugsson, S.T. and Solberg,C.E., Geophysical signature of the proposed Mjølnir impact structure, Barents Sea (abstract), European Science Foundation, Second International Conference. Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth. The Identification and Characterization of Impacts, pp. 1385-1386. 1994.
Tsikalas, F., Faleide, J.I., Post-impact structural crater modification due to sediment loading: An overlooked process, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v. 42, pp. 2013-2029, 2007
Tsikalas, F., Gudlaugsson, S. T. and J. I. Faleide., The anatomy of a buried complex impact structure: the Mjølnir structure, Barents Sea, Journal of Geophysical Research, v 103, B12, p 30469-30483. 1998.
Tsikalas, F., Gudlaugsson, S. T., Faleide, J. I., Eldholm,O., The Mjolnir marine impact crater porosity anomaly, Deep-Sea Research II v.49, p. 1103-1120. 2002.
Tsikalas, F., Gudlaugsson, S.T., Eldholm, O., Faleide,J.I., Integrated Geophysical Analysis Supporting the Impact Origin of the Mjølnir Structure, Barents Sea, Tectonophysics v. 289, pp. 257-280. 1998.
Tsikalas, F., Gudlaugsson, S.T., Faleide, J.I. and Eldholm,O., Mjølnir structure, Barents Sea: a marine impact crater laboratory. Geol.Soc.Amer. Spec.Paper, v.339, p.193-204. 1999.
Tsikalas, F., Gundlaugsson, S.T. and Faleide,J.I., Collapse, infilling, and postimpact deformation at the Mjølnir impact structure, Barents Sea. GSA Bulletin, v. 110, pp. 537-552. 1998.
Tsikalas, F., Gundlaugsson, S.T. and Faleide,J.I., Seismic analysis of the Mjølnir impact structure, Barents Sea (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Tsikalas, F., Mjolnir Crater as a Result of Oblique Impact: Asymmetry Evidence Constrains Impact Direction and Angle. Impact Studies (Impact Tectonism).
Tsikalas, F., Post-Impact modification correction factor: a necessity to better constrain cratering scaling law estimates and impact-related consequences at all buried impact craters, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXIX, abstract #1009. 2008.
Werner, S.C., Torsvik, T.H., Downsizing the Mjølnir impact structure, Barents Sea, Norway, Tectonophysics, v. 483, pp. 191-202, 2010
Westbroek, H., Stewart, R., The formation, morphology, and economic potential of meteorite impact craters, CREWES Research Report v. 8, p. 1-26. 1996.