Montagnais
Nova Scotia, Canada
N 42° 53'
W 64° 13'
45
50.5 ± 0.76
N
Y
S
-
Aubry, M-P., Gradstein, F.M. and Jansa,L.F., The late early Eocene Montagnais bolide: No impact on biotic diversity. Micropaleontology, v. 36, pp. 164-172. 1990.
Bottomley, R. J., York, D., Age measurement of the submarine Montagnais impact crater. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 15, pp. 1409-1412. 1988.
Clark, J. F., Magnetic survey data at meteoritic impact sites in North America. Geomagnetic Service of Canada, Earth Physics Branch Open File # 83-5, 30 p. 1983.
Cockell, C. S., Lee, P., The Biology of Impact Craters - a review. Biol. Rev., 77, P. 279 - 310. 2002.
Croft, S. K., A first-order estimate of shock heating and vaporization in oceanic impacts. Geological Society of America, Special Paper 190, pp. 143-152. 1982.
Deptuck, M.A. and Campbell, D.C. Widespread erosion and mass failure from the ~51 Ma Montagnais marine bolide impact off southwestern Nova Scotia, Canada. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences 49, 1576-1594. 2012.
Deptuck, M.E., Campbell, D.C., Ryan, B., Kosters, E., Widespread collapse of the southwestern Scotian margin triggered by the approximately 51 Ma Montagnais marine bolide impact, offshore Nova Scotia. Atlantic Geology, 49:26. 2013.
Dypvik, H., Jansa, L. F., Sedimentary signatures and processes during marine bolide impacts: a review, Sedimentary Geology v. 161, p. 309-337. 2003.
Edwards, A., Geophysical investigation of a potential meteorite impact site, offshore Nova Scotia, Canada (abstract). Society of Exploration Geophysists Fifty-ninth Annual International Meeting & Exposition, Dallas, Texas, p. 535-537. 1989.
Fel'dman, V. I., Rare-Earth elements in astrobleme impactites. Geochemistry International, v. 32, pp. 24-48. 1995.
Given, M. M., Mesozoic and early Cenozoic geology of offshore Nova Scotia. Canadian Petroleum Geology Bulletin, v. 25, pp. 63-91. 1977.
Grieve, R.A.F., Robertson, P.B., Life obliterated., Geos, v. 16, pp. 15-17, 1987
Gurov, E. P., Gurova, E. P., Impact structures on the Earth's surface (in Russian). Geologicheskii Zhurnal, v. 47, pp. 117-124. 1987.
Jansa, L. F., Pe-Piper, G., Identification of an underwater extraterrestrial impact crater. Nature, v. 327, pp. 612-614. 1987.
Jansa, L. F., Pe-Piper, G., Robertson, P.B. and Freidenreich,O., Montagnais: A submarine impact structure on the Scotian shelf, eastern Canada. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 101, pp. 450-463. 1989.
Jansa, L. F., Pe-Piper, G., Robertson, P.B. and Friedenreich,O., Meteorite impact crater on the North Atlantic shelf (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XIX, pp. 549-550. 1988.
Jansa, L. F., Wade, J. A., Geology of the continental margin off Nova Scotia and Newfoundland. Geological Survey of Canada Paper 74-30, v. 2, pp. 51-105. 1975.
Jansa, L.F., Cometary impacts into ocean: their recognition and the threshold constraint for biological extinctions, Palaeogeography, Palaeoclimatology, Palaeoecology, v.104, pp. 271-286, 1993
Koeberl, C., New estimates of area and mass for the North American tektite strewn field. Proceedings Lunar and Planetary Science Conference 19th, pp. 745-751. 1989.
McKinnon, W. B., Impact into the Earth's ocean floor: Preliminary experiments, a planetary model, and possibilities for detection. Geological Society of America, Special Paper 190, pp. 129-142. 1982.
Melosh, H. J., The mechanics of large meteoroid impacts in the Earth's oceans. Geological Society of America, Special Paper 190, pp. 121-127. 1982.
Monahan, D., Three dimensional representation of submarine relief: Continental margin of eastern North America. Marine Sciences Branch, Department of the Environment, Ottawa, Marine Science Paper 9, 10 p. 1971.
Monastersky, R., Big splash from an ancient fall. Science News, v. 131, pp. 404. 1987.
Ormo, J., Lindstrom, M., When a cosmic impact strikes the sea bed, Geol. Mag. V.137(1), p.67-80. 2000.
Pilkington, M., Jansa, L.F. and Grieve,R.A.F., Geophysical studies of the Montagnais impact crater (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 1085-1086. 1994.
Pilkington, M., Jansa, L.F. and Grieve,R.A.F., Geophysical studies of the Montagnais impact crater, Canada. Meteoritics, v. 30, pp. 446-450. 1995.
Poag, C.W., Plescia, J.B., Molzer, P.C., Ancient impact structures on modern continental shelves: The Chesapeake Bay, Montagnais, and Toms Canyon craters, Atlantic margin of North America, Deep-Sea Research Part II: Topical Studies in Oceanography, v. 49, pp. 1081-1102, 2002
Stecher, O., Ngo, H.H., Papanastassiou, D.A., Wasserburg, G.J. and Jansa,L.F., Rb-Sr and Sm-Nd signatures from the Montagnais and Popigai impact craters (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XX, pp. 1048-1049. 1989.
Tsikalas, F., Faleide, J.I., Post-impact structural crater modification due to sediment loading: An overlooked process, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v. 42, pp. 2013-2029, 2007
Tsikalas, F., Post-Impact modification correction factor: a necessity to better constrain cratering scaling law estimates and impact-related consequences at all buried impact craters, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXIX, abstract #1009. 2008.
Westbroek, H., Stewart, R., The formation, morphology, and economic potential of meteorite impact craters, CREWES Research Report v. 8, p. 1-26. 1996.