Neugrund
Estonia
N 59° 20'
E 23° 40'
8
~ 535
N
-
S
-
Suuroja, K., Saadre, T., Gneiss breccia erratic boulders from northwestern Estonia as withnesses of an unknown impact structure (in Estonian). Bulletin of the Geological Survey of Estonia, v. 5/1, pp. 26-28. 1995.
Suuroja, K., Suuroja, S., Neugrund Structure - the Newly Discovered Submarine Early Cambrian Impact Crater. (Gilmour I. and Koeberl C. eds) Impacts and the early Earth, Lecture notes in Earth Sciences, 91, pp. 389-416. 2000.
Suuroja, S., Surroja, K., and Floden, T. Features of the dislocation zone of complex impact structures; marine impact structures Neugrund and Kardla (Baltic Sea, Estonia). Opas - Geologian Tutkimuskeskus, vol.57, pp.82. 2012.
Suuroja, S., Suuroja, K., and Flodén, T. A comparative analysis of two Early Palaeozoic marine impact structures in Estonia, Baltic Sea: Neugrund and Kärdla. Bulletin of the Geological Society of Finland, 85, 83–101. 2013.