Rock Elm
Wisconsin, U.S.A.
N 44° 43'
W 92° 14'
6
< 505
-
-
S
-
Arana, A., and Cavosie, A. J. 2014. A study of shocked quartz in breccia from the Rock Elm impact structure. 45th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, abstract #2185.
Cavosie, A. J., Erickson, T. M., and Timms, N. E. (2015) Nanoscale records of ancient shock deformation: Reidite (ZrSiO4) in Sandstone at the Ordovician Rock Elm impact crater. Geology, v. 43, no. 4, p. 315-318.
Cavosie, A. J., Erickson, T. M., and Timms, N. E. 2014. Reidite and shock-twinned zircon in polymict breccia from the Ordovician Rock Elm impact structure, USA. Geological Society of America Abstracts with Programs, 46(6).
Cavosie, A. J., Roig, C. I., McDougal, D. J., Ushikubo, T., Spicuzza, M. J., Fournelle, J., … Mattson, C. 2013. The Sedimentary Record of a Small, Deeply Eroded Impact Structure: A Search for Detrital Shocked Minerals and Extraterrestrial Chromites in Sediments Eroded from the Ordovician Rock Elm Impact Structure (USA). 44th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, abstract #2028.
Cordua, W. S. 1985. The Rock Elm Structure, Pierce County, Wisconsin, a possible cryptoexplosion structure. Geology, 13, 372–374.
Cordua, W. S. 1987. The Rock Elm Disturbance, Pierce County, Wisconsin. Minnesota Geological Survey Guidebook Series #15, 123–152.
French, B. M., and Cordua, W. S. 1999. Intense fracturing of quartz at the Rock Elm (Wisconsin) “cryptoexplosion” structure: evidence for meteorite impact. 30th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, abstract #1123.
French, B.M., Cordua, W.S., Plescia, J.B., The Rock Elm meteorite impact structure, Wisconsin; geology and shock-metamorphic effects in quartz. Geological Society of America Bulletin, 116, pp.200-218. 2004.
Roig, C. I., Cavosie, A. J., McDougal, D., Cordua, W. S., and Mattson, C. 2013. Detrital shocked quartz in modern sediments eroded from the Rock Elm impact structure, Wisconsin, USA. 44th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, abstract #2685.