Sudbury
Ontario, Canada
N 46° 36'
W 81° 11'
130
1850 ± 3
Y
Y
C
-
Abramov, O., Kring, D. A., Finite-difference modeling of impact-induced hydrothermal systems, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXIV. 2003.
Abramov, O., Kring, D. A., Impact-Induced Hydrothermal system at the Sudbury Crater: Duration Temperatures, Mechanics and Biological Implcations, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXV. 2004.
Addison, W. D., Brumpton, G.R., Vallini, D.A., McNaughton, N.J., Davis, D.W., Kissin, S.A., Fralick, P.W., Hammond,A.L., Discovery of distal ejecta from the 1850 Ma Sudbury impact event, Geology, v. 33 , n. 3 , p. 193-196. 2005.
Ames, D. E., Gibson, H. L., Controls on and geological setting of regional hydrothermal alteration within the Onaping Formation, footwall to the Errington and Vermilion base metal deposits, Sudbury Structure, Ontario, Current Research 1995-E; Geological Survey of Canada, pp. 161-173. 1995.
Ames, D. E., Gibson, H.L. and Jonasson,I.R., Impact-induced hydrothermal base metla mineralization, Whitewater Group, Sudbury structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Ames, D. E., Gibson, H.L., Watkinson, D.H. and Jonasson,I.R., Large semi-conformable alteration zones within the Onaping Formation (abstract). GCS Forum '95,. 1995.
Ames, D. E., Watkinson, D.H. and Parrish,R.R., Dating of a regional hydrothermal system induced by the 1850 Ma Sudbury impact event. Geology, v. 26, pp. 447-450. 1998.
Ames, D.E., Hanley, J.T., Tuba, G., Jackson, S., High-grade sperrylite zone reveals primitive source in the Sudbury imact structure. Mineralogic Magazine, vol. 77, pp.587. 2013.
Ariskin, A. A., Deutsch, A. Ostermann,M., Sudbury Igneous Complex: simulating phase equilibria and in situ differentiation for two proposed parental magmas, in Large meteorite impacts and planetary evolution II ed B.O. Dressler & V.L. Sharpton. Geological Society of America Special Paper 339 p 373-397. 1999.
Ariskin, A. A., Simulating phase equilibria and in situ differentiations for the proposed parental Sudbury magmas (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Avermann, M. E., Brockmeyer, P., The Onaping formation of the Sudbury structure (Canada): An example for allochthonous impact breccias (abstract). Pesonen, L.J. and Niemisara, H., eds., Symposium Fennoscandian Impact Structures, p. 42. 1990.
Avermann, M. E., Brockmeyer, P., The Onaping formation of the Sudbury structure (Canada): an example of allochthonous impact breccias (extended abstract). Tectonophysics, v. 216, pp. 227-234. 1992.
Avermann, M. E., Investigations on the Green Member of the Onaping Formation, Sudbury structure, Ontario, Canada (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Avermann, M. E., Origin of the polymict, allochthonous breccias of the Onaping Formation, Sudbury, Ontario, Canada. Geological Society of America Special Paper (in press). 1994.
Avermann, M. E., Origin of the polymict, allochthonous breccias of the Onaping Formation,Sudbury Structure, Ontario, Canada. Geological Society of America Special Paper 293, pp. 265-274. 1994.
Avermann, M. E., Sudbury project (University fo Munster-Ontario Geological Survey): (6) Origin of the polymict, allochthonous breccias of the Onaping formation (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 4-5. 1992.
Avermann, M. E., Sudbury project (University of Munster-Ontario Geological Survey): (1) Summary of results - an updated impact model (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetray Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 5-6. 1992.
Avermann, M. E., The Green Member of the Onaping Formation, the collapsed fireball layer of the Sudbury impact structure, Ontario Canada, in Large meteorite impacts and planetary evolution II ed B.O. Dressler & V.L. Sharpton. Geological Society of America Special Paper 339 p 323-330. 1999.
Ballhaus, C., Tredoux, M. and A. Spath., Phase relations in the Fe-Ni-Cu-PGE-S system at magmatic temperature and application to massive sulphide ores of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Journal of Petrology, v 42, n 10, p 1911-1926. 2001.
Basu, A. R., Impact-triggered mafic magmatism in Earth history (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 21. 1988.
Beales, F. W., Lozej, G. P., Additional note on the origin of the Sudbury structure. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 13, pp. 179-181. 1976.
Beales, F. W., Lozej, G. P., Sudbury basin sediments and the meteoritic impact theory of origin for the Sudbury structure. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 12, pp. 629-635. 1975.
Becker, L., Bada, J. L., Fullerenes in the K/T boundary: Are they a result of global wildfires (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVI, pp. 85-86. 1995.
Becker, L., Bada, J.L. and Poreda,R.J., Extraterrestrial He trapped in fullerenes in the Sudbury impact structure (abstract). Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, pp. A12-A13. 1996.
Becker, L., Bada, J.L., Poreda, R.J. and Bunch,T.E., Extraterrestrial helium (He@C60) trapped in fullerenes in the Sudbury impact structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Becker, L., Bada, J.L., Winans, R.E., Hunt, J.E., Bunch, T.E. and French,B.M., Fullerenes in the 1.85 billion-year-old Sudbury impact structure (abstract). Sudbury Geology Workshop and Fieldtrip,. 1994.
Becker, L., Bada, J.L., Winans, R.E., Hunt, J.E., Bunch, T.E. and French,B.M., Fullerenes in the 1.85-billion-year-old Sudbury impact structue. Science, v. 265, pp. 642-645. 1994.
Becker, L., Poreda, R. J., Bunch., Fullerenes, Helium and Impact Events on the Earth Throughout Geologic Time: Implications for Changes in the Biostratigraphic Record, GSA Annual Meeting 1999, Abstr. 51972. 1999.
Becker, L., Poreda, R.J. and Bada,J.L., Extraterrestrial helium trapped in fullerenes in the Sudbury impact structure. Science, v. 72, pp. 249-252. 1996.
Beswich, A. E., Compositional discontinuities within the main mass of the North Range of the Sudbury Igneous Complex (abstract). Sudbury Geology Workshop and Fieldtrip,. 1994.
Bethune, K. M., The Sudbury dyke swarm and its bearing on the tectonic development of the Grenville Front, Ontario, Canada. Precambrian Research, v. 85, pp. 117-146. 1997.
Binney, W. P., Foy, R.A., Halladay, S.H., Poulin, R.Y. and Sweeny,J.M., The Lindsley Ni-Cu-PGE deposit and its geological setting (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v.30, p. 485-486. 1992.
Bird, R. T., Roest, W.R., Ernst, R.E. and Buchan,K., Restoring continental deformation with gridded geophysical data: Preliminary reconstruction of the Matachewan dyke swarm and Kapuskasing Structural Zone (abstract). Canadian Geophysical Union, Banff, AB, 50. 1995.
Bischoff, L., Dressler, B O., Avermann, M E., Brockmeyer, P, Lakomy, R and Müller-Mohr,V., Sudbury project (University of Munster-Ontario Geological Survey): (2) Field studies 1984-1989 - summary of results (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, p. 7. 1992.
Blais, E., Livelybrooks, D. and Mareschal,M., Analysis and 3D modelling of magnetotelluric data over a deep massive sulphide deposit, Sudbury Structure, Ontario (abstract). GCU, Program with Abstracts, Banff, AB. 1994.
Boast, M. and Spray, J.G. 2006. Superimposition of a thrust-transfer fault system on a large impact structure: implications for Ni-Cu-PGE exploration at Sudbury. Economic Geology, v.101 1583-1594.
Boast, M., Holmes, T., Spray., Geology of the footwall rocks on the North Range of the Sudbury Impact Crater, and investigations into the nature of the metamorphic aureole, Canadian Tectonics Group Annual Meeting, Sudbury 2001, Abstracts. 2001.
Boast, M., Holmes, T., Spray., The Metamorphic Aureole of the Sudbury Structure, Summit 2000, GSA Annual Meeting Program with Abstracts. 2000.
Boast, M., Spray, J. G., A comparison of four transects through the North Range metamorphic aureole of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Sudbury, Ontario, 1st Joint Meeting, Northeastern Section, GSA and Atlantic Geoscience Society, Abstracts. 2003.
Boast, M., Spray, J. G., Hidden ore: using thermal metamorphism to determine shortening on thrust faults cutting the sudbury igneous complex, GSA Abstracts with Programs, v.34, n.06, September 2002. 2002.
Boerner, D. E., Kellett, R. and Mareschal,M., Inductive source EM sounding of the Sudbury Structure. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 943-946. 1994.
Boerner, D. E., Kellett, R. and Mareschal,M., Lithoprobe EM studies of the Sudbury structure (abstract). Canadian Geophysical Union, Banff, Alberta. 1993.
Boerner, D. E., Milkereit, B. and A. Davidson., Geoscience impact: a synthesis of studies of the Sudbury Structure. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, V. 37, p. 477-501. 2000.
Boerner, D. E., Milkereit, B. and Naldrett,A.J., Introduction to the Special Section on the Lithoprobe Sudbury Project. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 919-922. 1994.
Boerner, D. E., Milkereit, B., Structural evolution of the Sudbury impact structure in the light of seismic reflection data, Geological Society of America, Special Paper 339, p 419-429. 1999.
Boerner, D. E., Milkereit, B., Wu,J.and M.Salisbury., Seismic images and three-dimensional architecture of a Proterozoic shear zone in the Sudbury Structure (Superior Province, Canada). Tectonics, v. 19, n. 2, p. 397-405. 2000.
Bohor, B. F., Betterton, W. J., Shocked zircons in the Onaping formation: Further proof of impact origin (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 9-10. 1992.
Brockmeyer, P., Deutsch, A. and Buhl,D., Sudbury impact structure (Ontario, Canada): Isotope systematics (abstract). Pesonen, L.J. and Niemisara, H., eds., Symposium Fennoscandian Impact Structures, p. 43. 1990.
Brockmeyer, P., Deutsch, A., The origin of the breccias in the lower Onaping formation, Sudbury structure (Canada): Evidence from petrographic observations & Sr-Nd isotope data (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XX, pp. 113-114. 1989.
Brocoum, S. J., Dalziel, I. W. D., The Sudbury Basin, the Southern Province, the Grenville Front, and the Penokean Orogeny. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 85, pp. 1571-1580. 1974.
Brocoum, S. J., Dalziel, I. W. D., The Sudbury Basin, the Southern Province, the Grenville Front, and the Penokean Orogeny: discussion. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 87, pp. 958. 1976.
Brooks, E. R., The Sudbury Basin, the Southern Province, the Grenville Front, and the Penokean Orogeny: Discussion and reply. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 87, pp. 954-958. 1976.
Buhl, D., Deutsch, A. and Ostermann,M., Isotope systematics support: The impact origin of the Sudbury Structure (Canada) (abstract). Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth, First International Workshop, Nordlingen, Germany. 1993.
Buhl, D., Deutsch, A., Lakomy,R., Brockmeyer, P. and Dressler,B., Sudbury project (University of Munster-Ontario Geological Survey): (7) Sr-Nd in heterolithic breccias and gabbroic dikes (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 11-12. 1992.
Bunch, T. E., Becker, L., Schultz, P.H. and Wolbach,W.S., New potential sources for Black Onaping carbon (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Butler, H. R., Lineament analysis of the Sudbury multiring impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 293, pp. 319-329. 1994.
Butler, H. R., Sudbury as a multi-ringed impact structure (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 14. 1988.
Card, K. D., Gupta, V.K., McGrath, P.H. and Grant,F.S., The Sudbury structure: Its regional geological and geophysical setting. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Ministry of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 25-43. 1984.
Card, K. D., Hutchinson, R. W., The Sudbury structure: Its regional geological setting. Geological Association of Canada, Special Paper no. 10, pp. 67-78. 1972.
Card, K. D., Metamorphism in the Agnew Lake area, Sudbury district, Ontario, Canada. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 75, pp. 1011-1030. 1964.
Card, K. D., Robertson, J. A., General geology of the Sudbury-Elliot Lake region. International Geological Congress, 24th, Montreal, Canada, part C-38, 56 p. 1972.
Chai, G., Eckstrand, O. R., A new intrepretation of the Sudbury Igneous Complex: A two magma model. Summary Report1993-1994, Canada, Ontario, Northern Ontario Development Agreement, Minerals, edited by: N. Wood, R. Shannon, L. Owsiacki, M. Walters, design: J. King. 1994.
Chai, G., Eckstrand, O. R., A new intrepretation of the Sudbury Igneous Complex: A two magna model. Summary Report 1993-1994, Natural Resources Canada, Ministry of Northern Development and Mines, Ontario, N. Wood, R. Shannon, L. Owsiacki and M. Walters, p. 83-89. 1994.
Chai, G., Eckstrand, O. R., Origin of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Ontario - differentiate of two separate magmas. In Current Reserach, Part E; Geological Survey of Canada, Paper 93-1E, pp. 219-230. 1993.
Chai, G., Eckstrand, O.R. and Gregoire,D.C., Low level PGE analysis on the Sudbury Igneous Complex and its country rocks, GSC Forum, Program with Abstracts, p. 21. 1993.
Chai, G., Eckstrand, R. and Grégoire,C., Platinum group element concentractions in the Sudbury rocks, Ontario - an indicator of petrogenesis. In Current Research, Part C; Geological Survey of Canada, Paper 93-1C, pp. 287-293. 1993.
Chai, G., Eckstrand, R., Rare-earth element characteristics and origin of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Ontario, Canada. Chemical Geology, v. 113, pp. 221-244. 1994.
Clark, J. F., Magnetic survey data at meteoritic impact sites in North America. Geomagnetic Service of Canada, Earth Physics Branch Open File # 83-5, 30 p. 1983.
Coats, C. J. A., Snadjr, P., Ore deposits of the north range, Onaping-Levack area, Sudbury. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 327-346. 1984.
Cochrane, L. B., Ore deposits of the Copper Cliff offset. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 347-359. 1984.
Cockell, C. S., Lee, P., The Biology of Impact Craters - a review. Biol. Rev., 77, P. 279 - 310. 2002.
Cohen, A. S., Burnham, O.M., Hawkesworth, C.J., Lightfoot,P.C., Pre-emplacement Re-Os ages from ultramafic inclusions in the sublayer of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Ontario, Chemical Geology, v. 165, p.37-46. 2000.
Collins, W. H., Life history of the Sudbury Nickel Irruptive. Part I. Petrogenesis. Transactions of the Royal Society of Canada, v. 28, pp. 123-177. 1934.
Collins, W. H., Life history of the Sudbury Nickel Irruptive. Part II. Intrusion and defromation. Transactions of the Royal Society of Canada, v. 29, pp. 191. 1935.
Collins, W. H., Life history of the Sudbury Nickel Irruptive. Part III. Environment. Transactions of the Royal Society of Canada, v. 30, p. 29-53. 1936.
Collins, W. H., Life history of the Sudbury Nickel Irruptive. Part IV. Mineralization. Transactions of the Royal Society of Canada, v. 31, pp. 15-43. 1937.
Collins, W. H., Sudbury series. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 47, pp. 1675-1690. 1936.
Corfu, F., Lightfoot, P. C., U-Pb geochronology of the sublayer environment, Sudbury Igneous Complex, Ontario. Economic Geology, v. 91, pp. 1263-1269. 1996.
Coulter, A.B., Osinski, G.R. The nature and origin of the Garson Member of the Onaping Formation, Sudbury impact structure, Canada. Special Paper - Geological Society of America, vol.518, pp.165-176. 2015.
Cowan, E. J., Schwerdtner, W. M., Fold origin of the Sudbury Basin. Ontario Geological Survey Special Paper , vol.5, Canada. 1994.
Cowan, E. J., Schwerdtner, W. M., Funnel-shaped emplacement geometry of the Sudbury Igneous Complex: A structural perspective (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Cowan, E. J., Schwerdtner, W. M., Intrusive origin of the Sudbury igneous complex: Structural and sedimentological evidence (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 17-18. 1992.
Cowan, E. J., Shanks, W.S. and Schwerdtner,W.M., Geometrical significance of the geological map pattern of the Sudbury structure (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Meteoritical Association of Canada, v. 30, p. 486-487. 1992.
Cowen, E. J., Riller, U., Schwerdtner., Emplacement Geometry of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, in Large meteorite impacts and planetary evolution II ed B.O. Dressler & V.L. Sharpton. Geological Society of America Special Paper 339 p 399-418. 1999.
Craig, J. R., Solberg, T. N., Compositional zoning in ore minerals at the Craig mine, Sudbury, Ontario, Canada. Canadian Mineralogist, v. 37, p. 1163-1176. 1999.
Crocket, J. H., Dickin, A P., McNutt, R H., Richardson, J M., Benetau, S B. and Frape,S.K., Isotopic studies at Sudbury (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Stucture, p. 22. 1988.
Dabizha, A. I., Krass, M. S., The evolution of explosive meteorite craters on Earth (in Russian). "Zemlya i Vselennaya", v. 5, pp. 80-88. 1975.
Darling, J.R., Storey, C.D., Hawkesworth, C.J., Lighfoot, P.C., In situ Pb isotope analysis of Fe-Ni-Cu sulphides by laset ablation multi-colletor ICPMS; new insights into ore formatio nin the Sudbury impact melt sheet. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, vol. 99, pp. 1-17. 2012.
Davies, J. F., Leroux, M.V. and Whitehead,R.E., Oxygen-isotope composition and temperature of fluids involved in deposition of Proterozoic sedex deposits, Sudbury Basin, Ontario. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 27, pp. 1299-1303. 1990.
Davis, G. C., Little Stobie mine: A south range contact deposit. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 361-369. 1984.
Dence, M. R., Boudette, E.L. and Lucchitta,I., Guide to the geology of Sudbury basin, Ontario, Canada. United States Department of the Interior, Geological Survey for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Interagency Report: 43, 41 p. 1972.
Dence, M. R., Guy-Bray, J. V., Some astroblemes, craters and cryptovolcanic structures in Ontario and Quebec. International Geological Congress, 24th, Montreal, Quebec, Excursion A-65, 61 p. 1972.
Dence, M. R., Meteorite impact craters and the structure of the Sudbury Basin. Geological Association of Canada, Special Paper No. 10, pp. 7-18. 1972.
Dence, M. R., The nature and significance of terrestrial impact structures. International Geological Congress, 24th, Montreal, Canada, pp. 77-89. 1972.
Deutsch, A., Brockmeyer, P. and Buhl,D., Sudbury again: New and old isotope data (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXI, pp. 282-283. 1990.
Deutsch, A., Buhl, D., Brockmeyer, P., Lakomy, R. and Flucks,M., Sudbury project (University of Munster-Ontario Geological Survey): (4) Isotope systematics support the impact origin (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 21-22. 1992.
Deutsch, A., Grieve, R. A. R., The Sudbury Structure: Constraints on its genesis from Lithoprobe results. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 963-966. 1994.
Deutsch, A., Grieve, R.A.F., Avermann, M., Bischoff, L., Brockmeyer, P., Buhl, D., Lakomy, R., Müller-Mohr, V., Ostermann, M. and Stöffler,D., The Sudbury Structure (Ontario, Canada): a tectonically deformed multi-ring basin. Geologische Rundschau, v. 84, pp. 697-709. 1995.
Deutsch, A., Isotope systematics support the impact origin of the Sudbury Structure (Ontario, Canada). Geological Society of America Special Paper 293, pp. 289-302. 1994.
Deutsch, A., Isotope systematics support the impact origin of the Sudbury structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper (in press). 1994.
Deutsch, A., Lakomy, R. and Buhl,D., Strontium- and neodymium-isotopic characteristics of a heterolithic breccia in the basement of the Sudbury impact structure, Canada. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 93, pp. 359-370. 1989.
Deutsch, A., Ostermann, M., Schärer, U. and Agrinier,P., On the formation of impact melt rocks: A geochemical case study at Foy offset dike, Sudbury impact structure (Canada) (abstract). IV International Conference on Advanced Material, Symposium 19, Cancún, Mexico. 1995.
Deutsch, A., Ostermann, M., Schärer, U. and Agrinier,P., On the formation of impact melt rocks: A geochemical case study at Foy offset dike, Sudbury impact structure (Canada) (abstract). IV International Conference on Advanced Material, Symposium 19,. 1995.
Dickin, A. P., Artan, M.A. and Crocket,J.H., Isotopic evidence for distinct crustal sources of North and South Range ores, Sudbury Igneous Complex. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, v. 60, pp. 1605-1613. 1996.
Dickin, A. P., Crocket, J. H., Sudbury: Geochemical evidence for a single-impact melting event (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Dickin, A. P., Nguyen, T., Crocket., Isotopic evidence for a single impact melting origin of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, in Large meteorite impacts and planetary evolution II ed B.O. Dressler & V.L. Sharpton. Geological Society of America Special Paper 339 p 361-371. 1999.
Dickin, A. P., Richardson, J.M., Crocket, J.H., McNutt, R.H. and Peredery,W.V., Osmium isotope evidence for a crustal origin of platinum group elements in the Sudbury nickel ore, Ontario, Canada. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, v. 56, p. 3531-3537. 1992.
Dickin, A. P., The role of the crust as a source of PGE in the Sudbury nickel deposit: Re/Os isotope evidence. Geoscience Research Grant Program, Summary of Research 1990-1991, Ontario Geological Survey, Miscellaneous Paper 156, Grant 382, pp. 99-104. 1991.
Dietz, R. S., Butler, L. W., Shatter-cone orientation at Sudbury, Canada. Nature, v. 204, pp. 280-281. 1964.
Dietz, R. S., Sudbury astrobleme, splash emplaced sub-layer and possible cosmogenic ores. Geological Association of Canada, Special Paper no. 10, pp. 29-40. 1972.
Dietz, R. S., Sudbury astrobleme: A review (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 6, pp. 259-260. 1971.
Dietz, R. S., Sudbury structure as an astrobleme. Journal of Geology, v. 72, pp. 412-434. 1964.
Dietz, R. S., Sudbury structure as an astrobleme: Updated (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 13. 1988.
Ding, T. P., Schwarcz, H. P., Oxygen isotopic and chemical compositions of rocks of the Sudbury Basin, Ontario. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 21, pp. 305-318. 1984.
Dressler, B. O., Breccias in the footwall of the Sudbury impact structure-terrestrial equivalents of lunar breccias? (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XIV, pp. 167-168. 1983.
Dressler, B. O., Geology of the Wanapitei Lake area, District of Sudbury. Ontario Geological Survey Report, v. 213, 131 p. 1982.
Dressler, B. O., Gupta, V. K. and T. L. Muir., The Sudbury Structure. in Geology of Ontario, OGS Special Volume 4, p593-625. 1991.
Dressler, B. O., Morrison, G.G., Peredery, W.V. and Rao,B.V., The Sudbury structure, Ontario, Canada - A review. Pohl, J., ed., Research in Terrestrial Impact Structures, Friedr.Vieweg and Sohn, Braunschweig/Weisbaden, pp. 39-68. 1987.
Dressler, B. O., Peredery, W.V. and Muir,T.L., Geology and Mineral Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Ontario Geological Survey Guidebook 8, Ministry of Northern Development and Mines, Ontario, Toronto, 30. 1992.
Dressler, B. O., Sharpton, V. L., Comment on "Isotopic evidence for distinct crustal sources of North and South Range ores, Sudbury Igneous Complex" by A.P. Dickin, M.A. Arten, and J.H. Crocket. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, v. 62, pp. 315-317. 1998.
Dressler, B. O., Sharpton, V. L., The Sudbury structure, Ontario, Canada: A persistent enigma (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Dressler, B. O., The effects of the Sudbury event and the intrusion of the Sudbury igneous complex on the footwall rocks of the Sudbury structure. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 97-136. 1984.
Dressler, B. O., The Sudbury structure - a review (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 8. 1988.
Dressler, B. O., Weiser, T. and Brockmeyer,P., Recrystallized glasses and other melts of the Onaping formation and the origin of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Ontario, Canada (abstract). Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, p. A40. 1996.
Dressler, B. O., Weiser, T. and Brockmeyer,P., Recrystallized impact glasses of the Onaping Formation and the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Sudbury Structure, Ontario, Canada. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, v. 60, pp. 2019-2036. 1996.
Dutch, I., The Sudbury meteor impact structure: Resolution of a problem in deformational chronology (abstract). EOS, v. 57, p. 275. 1976.
Faggart, B. E.,Jr., Basu, A.R. and Tatsumoto,M., Origin of the Sudbury complex by meteoritic impact: Neodymium isotopic evidence. Science, v. 230, pp. 436-439. 1985.
Fairbairn, H. W., Faure, G., Pinson, W.H., Jr. and Hurley,P.M., Rb-Sr whole-rock age of the Sudbury lopolith and basin sediments. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 5, pp. 707-714. 1968.
Fairbairn, H. W., Hurley, P.M. and Pinson,W.H., Re-examination of Rb-Sr whole-rock ages at Sudbury, Ontario. Geological Association of Canada, v. 16, pp. 95-101. 1965.
Fairbanks, E. E., Sudbury Basin, a geological enigma. Earth Science, v. 33, p. 73. 1980.
Farrell, K. P. J., Lightfoot, P. C. and R. R. Keays., Mafic-ultramafic inclusions in the sublayer of the Sudbury igneous complex, Whistle Mine, Sudbury, Ontario. Ontario Geological Survey Miscellaneous Paper 164, pp. 126-128. 1995.
Farrow C.E.G., Watkinson, D. H., Diversity of precious-metal mineralization in footwall Cu-Ni-PGE deposits, Sudbury, Ontario: Implications for hydrothermal models of formation. The Canadian Mineralogist, v. 35, pp. 817-839. 1997.
Farrow, C., The role of fluids in footwall Cu-Ni-PGE mineralization, Sudbury structure (abstract). Sudbury Geology Workshop and Fieldtrip,. 1994.
Faure, G., Fairbairn, H.W., Hurley, P.M. and Pinson,W.H., Whole-rock Rb-Sr age of norite and micropegmatite at Sudbury, Ontario. Journal of Geology, v. 72, pp. 848-854. 1964.
Fedorowich, J. S., Detailed structural analysis of Sudbury breccia at Strathcona Mine, Sudbury, Canada (abstract). GAC/MAC, p. A28. 1996.
Fedorowich, J. S., Rousell, D.H. and Peredery,W.V., Classification and distribution of Sudbury breccia (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Fedorowich, J. S., Structural controls and tectonic setting for Cu-Ni-PGE mineralization at Strathcona Mine, Sudbury (abstract). GAC/MAC, p. A28. 1996.
Fedynsky, V. V., Khryanina, L. P., The probable number of meteorite craters in the USSR (in Russian). Astronomicheskii Vestnik, v. 10, pp. 81-87. 1976.
Finn, G. C., Grant 431 - Field, petrographic and geochemical study of the granophyre phase, Sudbury Igneous Complex, 17 p. Unpublished Report, Department of Earth Sciences, Brock University, 17 p. 0.
Fleet, M. E., Tectonic origin for Sudbury, Ontario, shatter cones. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 90, pp. 1177-1182. 1979.
Fleet, M. E., Tectonic origin for Sudbury, Ontario, shatter cones: reply. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 91, pp. 755-756. 1980.
Foster, J. G., Lambert, D.D., Frick, L.R. and Maas,R., Re-Os isotopic evidence for genesis of Archaean nickel ores from uncontaminated komatites. Nature, v. 382, pp. 703-706. 1996.
French, B. M., Possible relations between meteorite impact and igneous petrogenesis, as indicated by the Sudbury structure, Ontario, Canada. Bulletin Volcanologique, v. XXXIV-2, pp. 466-517. 1970.
French, B. M., Production of deep melting by large meteorite impacts: The Sudbury structure, Canada. International Geological Congress, 24th, Planetology, pp. 125-132. 1972.
French, B. M., Shock-metamorphic features at Sudbury, Ontario: Their use in a scientific deep-drilling project (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 10. 1988.
French, B. M., Shock-metamorphic features in the Sudbury structure, Ontario: A review. Geological Association of Canada, Special Paper no. 10, pp. 19-28. 1972.
French, B. M., Sudbury Structure, Ontario: Some petrographic evidence for an origin by meteorite impact. French, B.M. and Short, N.M., eds., Shock Metamorphism of Natural Materials, Mono Book Corp., Baltimore, MD, pp. 383-412. 1968.
Fueten F., Redmond, D. J., Documentation of a 1450 Ma contractional orogeny preserved between the 1850 Ma Sudbury impact structure and the 1 Ga Grenville orogenic front, Ontario. GSA Bulletin, v. 109, pp. 268-279. 1997.
Fullagar, P. D., Bottino, M.L. and French,B.M., Rb-Sr study of shock-metamorphosed inclusions from the Onaping formation, Sudbury, Ontario. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 8, pp. 435-443. 1971.
Geological Staff Members., Fourth International Platinum Symposium - Field guide for the Sudbury field trip August 5-7, 1985. Ontario Ministry of Natural Resources, Sudbury and Toronto, Inco Limited, and Falconbridge Limited, 64 p. 1985.
Gibbins, S. F. M., Gibson, H.L. and Jonasson,I.R., The Onaping Formation: A product of passive and explosive hydroclastic fragmentation of an impact melt? (abstract). GAC/MAC, p. A35. 1996.
Gibbins, S. F. M., Gibson, H.L., Ames, D.E. and Jonasson,I.R., The Onaping formation: Stratigraphy, fragmentation, and mechanisms of emplacement (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Gibbins, S. F. M., Gibson, H.L., Whitehead, R.E.S., Watkinson, D.H. and Jonasson,I.R., Geology, geochemistry, stratigraphy and mechanisms of themplacement of the Onaping Formation, Dowling area, Sudbury Structure, Ontario, Canada (abs.). GAC/MAC, Program with Abstracts, Annual Meeting, Waterloo, ON, v. 19, A41. 1994.
Gibbins, W. A., McNutt, R. H., Rubidium-strontium mineral ages and polymetamorphism at Sudbury, Ontario. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 12, pp. 1990-2003. 1975.
Gibbins, W. A., McNutt, R. H., The age of the Sudbury Nickel Irruptive and the Murray granite. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 12, pp. 1970-1989. 1975.
Giblin, P. E., Glossary, The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure. E.G. Pye, A. J. Naldrett and P.E. Giblin, eds., Ontario Geological Survey Special Report Volume 1, p. 571-574. 1984.
Giblin, P. E., History of exploration and development, of geological studies and development of geological concepts. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Ministry of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 3-23. 1984.
Gibson, H. L., Gibbins, S.F., Stoness, J.A., Gray, M.J., Paakki, J.J. Ames, D.E. and Jonasson,I.R., The origin of the Palaeoproterozoic Onaping Formation and Errington and Vermilion Zn-Cu-Pb massive sulphide deposits, Sudbury, Ontario (abstract), GSC Forum '95. 1995.
Gibson, H. L., Gibbins, S.F.M., Gray, M.J., Stoness, J.A. Rogers, D., Jonasson, I.R. and Ames,D., Origin of the Onaping Formation and Zn-Cu-Pb massive sulphide deposits of the Proterozoic Sudbury structure. Summary Report 1993-1994, northern Ontario Development Agreement, p. 90-94. 1994.
Gibson, H. L., Gibbins, S.F.M., Gray, M.J., Stoness, J.A., Rogers, D., Ames, D. and Jonasson,I.R., Origin of the Onaping Formation and Zn-Cu-Pb massive sulphide deposits of the Proterozoic Sudbury structure (abstract). Sudbury Geology Workshop and Fieldtrip,. 1994.
Gibson, H. -M., Shatter cone morphology and orientation: Implications for their formation at Sudbury and other impact structures (abstract). European Science Foundation, Third International Workshop. Shock Wave Behaviour of Solids in Nature and Experiments, Limoges, France. 1994.
Gibson, H. -M., Spray, J. G., Detailed morphology of striated, conical fracture surfaces (shatter cones) and their orientation with respect to the Sudbury Structure: A possible ground zero indicator for the Sudbury impact event? (abstract). GAC/MAC, Program with Abstracts, Annual Meeting, Waterloo, ON, v. 19, A41. 1994.
Gibson, H. -M., Spray, J. G., Orientation, morphology and classification of shatter cones from the Sudbury impact structure, Canada (abstract). AGU, p. 389. 1993.
Gibson, H. -M., Spray, J. G., Shock-induced melting and vaporization of shatter cone surfaces: Evidence from the Sudbury impact structure. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 33, pp. 329-336. 1998.
Glikson, A. Y., Mega-impacts and mantle-melting episodes: tests of possible correlations. AGSO Journal of Australian Geology & Geophysics, v. 16, pp. 587-607. 1996.
Golightly, J. P., Fitting a crater to the Sudbury structure (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v. 30, p. 484-485. 1992.
Golightly, J. P., The Sudbury structure as a meteorite crater: Where is its center and what should we expect there? (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 12. 1988.
Grant, R. W., Bite, A., Sudbury quartz diorite offset dikes. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 275-300. 1984.
Greenman, L., The petrology of the footwall breccias in the vicinity of the Strathcona mine, Levack, Ontario. Ph.D. Thesis, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, 153 p. 1970.
Grieve, R. A. F., An impact model for Sudbury (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v. 30, p. 496. 1992.
Grieve, R. A. F., An impact model of the Sudbury Structure, Ontario. Lightfoot, P.C. and Naldrett, A.J., eds., Proceedings of the Sudbury - Noril'sk Symposium, Ontario Geological Survey special volume, Toronto, Ministry of Northern Development and Mines, v. 5, p. 119-132. 1994.
Grieve, R. A. F., An impact model of the Sudbury Structure, Ontario. Ontario Geological Survey Special Paper (in press). 1994.
Grieve, R. A. F., Deutsch, A. and Stöffler,D., A self-consistent model of the origin and evolution of the Sudbury structure (abstract). IV International Conference on Advanced Material, Symposium 19, Cancún, Mexico. 1995.
Grieve, R. A. F., Deutsch, A., The Sudbury structure: Additional constraints on its origin and evolution (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 477-478. 1994.
Grieve, R. A. F., Deutsch, A., Therriault, A.M. and Ostermann,M., The Sudbury Igneous Complex: Basic arguments for an impact origin (abstract). Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, pp. A54-A55. 1996.
Grieve, R. A. F., Masaitis, V. L., The economic potential of terrestrial impact craters. International Geology Review, v. 36, pp. 105-151. 1994.
Grieve, R. A. F., Robertson, P. B., The Sudbury impact structure: A context for deep drilling (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 9. 1988.
Grieve, R. A. F., Shoemaker, E. M., The record of past impacts on Earth. T. Gehrels, ed., Hazards Due to Comets and Asteroids, Tuscon, Arizona, University of Arizona Press, (in press). 1994.
Grieve, R. A. F., Stoffler, D. and Deutsch,A., An impact model of the Sudbury Structure, Ontario (abstract). GSC Forum, Program with Abstracts, p. 23. 1993.
Grieve, R. A. F., Stoffler, D. and Deutsch,A., The Sudbury igneous complex: An impact melt sheet (abstract). Geological Association of Canada-Mineralogical Association of Canada, Program With Abstracts, Toronto, v. 16, pp. A48. 1991.
Grieve, R. A. F., Stoffler, D. and Deutsch,A., The Sudbury structure: An emerging perspective (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXII, pp. 495-496. 1991.
Grieve, R. A. F., Stoffler, D. and Deutsch,A., The Sudbury Structure: Controversial or Misunderstood? Journal of Geophysical Reserach, v. 96, pp. 22,753-22,764. 1991.
Grieve, R. A. F., The record of impact on Earth: Implications for a major Cretaceous/Tertiary impact event. Geological Society of America, Special Paper 190, pp. 25-37. 1982.
Grieve, R. A. F., Therriault, A., Vredefort, Sudbury, Chicxulub; three of a kind, Annual Review of Earth and Planetary Sciences, v.28, p.305-338. 2000.
Grieve, R., Therriault, A., Vredefort, Sudbury, Chicxulub: Three of a Kind? Ann. Rev. Earth Planet. Sci. 2000 vol. 28, pp. 305-38. 2000.
Gupta, V. K., Grant, F.S. and Card,K.D., Gravity and magnetic characteristics of the Sudbury structure. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 381-410. 1984.
Gurov, E. P., Gorova, E.P. and Rakitskaya,R.B., On the orientation of planar feature sets in quartz from rocks of explosion meteorite craters (in Russian). Zapiski Vsesoyuznogo mineralogicheskogo obshchestva, v. 108, pp. 578-584. 1979.
Gurov, E. P., Gurova, E. P., Impact structures on the Earth's surface (in Russian). Geologicheskii Zhurnal, v. 47, pp. 117-124. 1987.
Guy-Bray, J. V., and Geological Staff., Shatter cones at Sudbury. Journal of Geology, v. 74, pp. 243-245. 1966.
Guy-Bray, J. V., Introduction: New development in Sudbury geology. Geology Association of Canada, Special Paper Number 10, pp. 1-5. 1972.
Guy-Bray, J. V., New developments in Sudbury geology. Geological Association of Canada, Special Paper No. 10, 124 p. 1972.
Hanley, J. J., Mungall, J. E., Chlorine enrichment and hydrous alteration of the Sudbury breccia hosting footwall Cu-Ni-PGE mineralization at the Fraser Mine, Sudbury, Ontario, Canada. The Canadian Mineralogist, Vol. 41, P. 857 - 881. 2003.
Hanley, J. J., Mungall, J.E., Bray, C.J., Gorton,M.P., The origin of bulk and water-soluble Cl and Br enrichments in ore-hosting Sudbury Breccia in the Fraser Copper Zone, Strathcona Embayment, Sudbury, Ontario, Canada, Canadian Mineralogist, v. 42 , n. 6 , p. 1777-1798. 2004.
Hearst, R. B., Morris, W.A. and Thomas,M.D., Potential field interpretation and modelling along the Sudbury structure lithoprobe transect (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v. 30, p. 482-483. 1992.
Hearst, R., Morris, W. and Thomas,M., Magnetic interpretation along the Sudbury Structure Lithoprobe Transect. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 951-954. 1994.
Hemming, S. R., McDaniel, D.K., McLennan, S.M. and Hanson,G.N., Pb isotope constraints on the provenance and diagenesis of detrital feldspars from the Sudbury Basin, Canada. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 142, pp. 501-512. 1996.
Heymann, D., Buseck, P.R., Knell, J. and Dressler,B.O., The search for fullerenes in rocks from the Whitewater Group of the Sudbury structure, Ontario, Canada (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Heymann, D., Dressler, B. O., Origin of the carbonaceous matter in rocks from the Whitewater Group of the Sudbury structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Heymann, D., Dressler, B.O. and Thiemens,M.H., Origin of native sulfur in rocks from the Sudbury structure, Ontario, Canada (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Heymann, D., Dressler, B.O., Dunbar, R.B. and Mucciarone,D.A., Carbon isotopic composition of carbonaceous matter in rocks from the Whitewater Group of the Sudbury structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Hirt, A. M., Lowrie, W., Clendenen, W.S. and Kligfield,R., Correlation of strain and the anisotropy of magnetic susceptibility in the Onaping Formation: evidence for a near-circular origin of the Sudbury Basin. Tectonophysics, v. 225, pp. 231-254. 1993.
Huber, M.S., McDonald, I., Koelberl, C. Petrography and geochemistry of ejecta from the Sudbury impact event. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, vol. 49, pp. 1749-1768. 2014.
Innes, D. G., Colvine, A. C., The regional metallogenetic setting of Sudbury. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Ministry of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 45-56. 1984.
Ivanov, B. A., Deutsch, A., Ostermann, M. and Ariskin,A., Solidification of the Sudbury impact melt body and nature of the Offset dikes - thermal modeling (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVIII, pp. 633-634. 1997.
Ivanov, B. A., Deutsch, A., Sudbury impact event: Cratering mechanics and thermal history (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Ivanov, B. A., Deutsch, A., Sudbury impact event: cratering mechanics and thermal history. Geological Society of America Special Paper 339, p.389-397. 1999.
Ivanov, B. A., Large impact crater formation: thermal softeneing and acoustic fluidization, 61st Annual Meteoritical Society Meeting, Dublin, Ireland. 1998.
Ivanov, B. A., Large impact crater formation: thermal softening and acoustic fluidization. Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v 33, n 4, p A76. 1998.
James, R. S., Dressler, B. O., Nature and significance of the Levack gneiss complex - footwall rocks of the north and east ranges of the Sudbury Igneous Complex (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v. 30, p.487. 1992.
James, R. S., Peck, D.C., Keays, R.R. and Gibson,H.L., The Huronian-Nipissing magnatic belt: Product of a global, early proterozoic tectonic and metallogenic episode (abstract). GAC/MAC, Program with Abstracts, Annual Meeting, Waterloo, ON, v. 19, A53. 1994.
James, R. S., Peredery, W. and Sweeny,J.M., Thermobarometric studies on the Levack gneisses - footwall rocks to the Sudbury igneous complex (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 41. 1992.
James, R. S., Peredery, W.V. and Sweeney,J.M., Thermobarometric studies of the Levack gneisses-footwall rocks to the Sudbury Igneous Complex (abstract). GAC/MAC, Program with Abstracts, Annual Meeting, Waterloo, ON, v. 19, A54. 1994.
Jessop, A. M., Geothermal experiment in the Sudbury basin 1967-1969 (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 17. 1988.
Johns, G. W., Dressler, B. O., The Sudbury Igneous Complex - an impact melt sheet? (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVI, pp. 679-680. 1995.
Johnson, B.C. Formation of melt droplets, melt fragments, and accretionary impact lapilli during a hypervelocity impact. Icarus, vol.228, pp.347-363. 2014.
Joreau, P., French, B.M. and Doukhan,J.-C., A TEM investigation of shock metamorphism in quartz from the Sudbury impact structure (Canada). Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 138, pp. 137-143. 1996.
Katsube, T. J., Salisbury, M., Implications of laboratory electrical measurements on interpretation of EM-surveys and origin of the Sudbury Structure. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 947-950. 1994.
Kellett R.L., Rivard, B., Characterization of the Benny deformation zone, Sudbury, Ontario. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 33, pp. 1256-1267. 1997.
Khryanina, L. P., Ivanov, O. P., Structure of meteorite craters and astroblemes (in Russian). Doklady Akademii Nauk SSSR, v. 233, pp. 457-460. 1977.
Khryanina, L. P., The structure of meteorite craters and their central uplifts (in Russian). Doklady Akademii Nauk SSSR, v. 238, pp. 195-198. 1978.
Kieley, J., The use of magnetotelluric surveys in deep crustal soundings (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 20. 1988.
Kissin, S. A., Fluid inclusions in meteorite impact structures and their relevance to the Sudbury structure (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 18. 1988.
Krogh, T. E., Davis, D.W. and Corfu,F., Precise U-Pb Zircon and Baddeleyite ages for the Sudbury area. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 431-446. 1984.
Krogh, T. E., Kamo, S.L. and Bohor,B.F., Shock metamorphosed zircons with correlated U-Pb discordance and melt rocks with concordant protolith ages indicate an impact origin for the Sudbury structure. Special AGU Publication, v. Geophysical Monograph 95, pp. 343-353. 1996.
Krogh, T. E., Kamo, S.L. and Bohor,B.F., U-Pb isotopic results for single shocked & polycrystalline zircons record 550-65.5-Ma ages for a K-T target site & 2700-1850-Ma ages for Sudbury imp. event (ab), International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 44-45. 1992.
Krogh, T. W., McNutt, R.H. and Davis,G.L., Two high-precision U-Pb zircon ages for the Sudbury Nickel Irruptive. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 19, pp. 723-728. 1982.
Kuo, H. Y., Crockett, T. H., Rare earth elements in the Sudbury Nickel Irruptive: Comparison with layered gabbros and implications for nickel irruptive petrogenesis. Economic Geology, v. 74, pp. 590-605. 1979.
Lakomy, R., Distribution of impact induced phenomena in complex terrestrial impact structures: Implications for transient cavity dimensions. Lunar and Planetary Science XXI, p. 676-677. 1990.
Lakomy, R., Implications for cratering mechanics from breccias in the basement of the Sudbury impact crater, Canada (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXI, pp. 678-679. 1990.
Lakomy, R., Implications of cratering mechanics from a study of the footwall breccia of the Sudbury impact structure, Canada. Meteoritics, v. 25, pp. 195-207. 1990.
Lakomy, R., Sudbury (Canada): Implications for cratering mechanics from the footwall breccia (abstract). Pesonen, L.J. and Niemisara, H., eds., Symposium Fennoscandian Impact Structures, p. 60. 1990.
Langenhorst, F., Shafranovsky, G. and Masaitis,V.L., A comparative study of impact diamonds from the Popigai, Ries, Sudbury, and Lappajarvi craters. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, vol. 33, No. 4, pp. A90-A91, Supplement. 1998.
Langenhorst, F., Shafranovsky, G. and V. L. Masaitis., A comparative study of impact diamonds from the Poigai, Ries, Sudbury, and Lappajarvi craters. Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v 33, n 4, p A90 - 91. 1998.
Li, C., Barnes, S. J., Partitioning of platinum-group elements and Au in the Fe-Ni-Cu-S system: experiments on the fractional crystallization of sulfide melt - a discussion. Contributions to Mineralogy and Petrology, v. 123, p. 435-437. 1996.
Lightfoot, P. C., Farrell, K.P., Pekeski, D., Moore, M. and Keays,R.R., Geochemical relationships among the main mass, sublayer and offsets of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Ontario, Canada. Ontario Geological Survey Miscellaneous Paper 164, pp. 116-133. 1995.
Lightfoot, P. C., Keays, R.R. and Doherty,W., Can impact-generated melts have mantle contributions?: Geochemical evidence from the Sudbury Igneous Complex (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Lightfoot, P. C., Keays, R.R., Morrison, G.G. and Bite,A., Geological and geochemical relationships between the contact sublayer, offsets, and main mass of the Sudbury Igneous Complex (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Lightfoot, P. C., Keays, R.R., Morrison, G.G., Bite, A. and Farrell,K.P., Geological and geochemical relationships between the contact sublayer, inclusions, and main mass of the Sudbury Igneous Complex: A case study of the Whistle Mine embayment. Economic Geology and the Bulletin of the Society of Economic Geologists, v. 92, pp. 647-673. 1997.
Lightfoot, P. C., Keays, R.R., Morrison, G.G., Bite,A.and K.P.Farrell., Geochemical relations in the Sudbury Igneous Complex: origin of the main mass and offset dikes. Economic Geology, v. 92, p. 289-307. 1997.
Long, D. G. F., Does the sedimentology of the Chelmsford formation provide evidence for a meteorite impact origin of the Sudbury structure? (abstract), International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 48. 1992.
Long, D. G. F., The tectonostatigraphic evolution of the Huronian basement and the subsequent basin fill: geological constraints on impact models of the Sudbury event. Precambrian Research, Vol. 129, P. 203 - 223. 2004.
Lowman, Jr,P.D., Impact origin of the Sudbury structure: Evolution of a theory (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 48. 1992.
Lowman, Jr,P.D., Origin of the Sudbury breccia: Field evidence for igneous/cataclastic formation (abstract). GAC/MAC, p. 15. 1996.
Lowman, Jr,P.D., Original shape of the Sudbury Sturcture, Canada: A study with airborne imaging radar. Canadian Journal of Remote Sensing, v. 17, pp. 152-161. 1991.
Lowman, Jr,P.D., Original size and shape of the Sudbury structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Lowman, Jr,P.D., Radar geology of the Canadian Shield: A 10-year review. Canadian Journal of Remote Sensing, v. 20, pp. 198-209. 1994.
Lowman, Jr,P.D., Singhroy V.H. and Slaney,V.R., Imaging radar investigations of the Sudbury structure (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 49. 1992.
Lowman, Jr,P.D., The Sudbury structure as a terrestrial mare basin. Reviews of Geophysics, 30, pp. 227-243. 1992.
Lowman, Jr,P.D., The Sudbury structure: A planetary perspective (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 15. 1988.
Lozej, G. P., Dence, M.R. and Beales,F.W., Crateri meteoritici terrestri: revisione e discussione con esempi di crateri dello scudo Canadese. Geologia Tecnica, v. 5, pp. 157-181. 1971.
Maloney, S., Kaiser, P. K., Geomechanical aspects of deep well drilling (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 23. 1988.
Marshall, D., Watkinson, D., Farrow, C., Molnar,F.and A.-M.Fouillac., Multiple fluid generations in the Sudbury igneous complex: fluid inclusion, Ar, O, H, Rb and Sr evidence, Chemical Geology, v 154, p 1-19. 1999.
Masaitis, V. L., Danilin, A.N., Maschak, M.S., Raykhlin, A.I., Selivanovskaya, T.V. and Shadenkov,Ye.M., The Geology of Astroblemes (in Russian). Leningrad, Nedra, 231 p. 1980.
Masaitis, V. L., Diamantiferous impactites, their distribution and petrogenesis (in Russian). Regional Geology and Metallogeny, v. 1, pp. 121-134. 1993.
Masaitis, V. L., Origin of the Sudbury structure in the light of new petrographic, mineralogical and geochemical data (in Russian). Zapiski Vserossiiskogo Mineralogicheskogo Obshchestva, V. 122, pp. 1-17. 1993.
Masaitis, V. L., Shafranovsky, G.I., Grieve, R.A.F., Langenhorst, F., Peredery, W.V., Balmasov, E.L., Fedorova, I.G. and Therriault,A., Discovery of impact diamonds at the Sudbury structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Masaitis, V. L., The deep structure of impact craters (in Russian). Razvedka i okhrana nedr, v. 8, pp. 10-13. 1991.
Masuoka, P. M., Hoppin, A.D. and Lowman, Jr.,P.D., A study of the Sudbury Basin, Ontario, using radar combined with digital elevation data: Preliminary results. 1995 ASPRS Annual Convention Proceedings. 1995.
McCormick, K. A., James, R.S., Fedorowich, J.S., Rousell, D.H., McDonald, A.M. and Gibson,H.L., A study of mineral and rock fragments and shock features in the late granite breccia at the Fraser Mine, North Range, Sudbury structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
McCormick, K. A., McDonald, A. M., Chlorine-bearing amphiboles from the Fraser mine, Sudbury, Ontario, Canada: description and crystal chemistry. Canadian Mineralogist, v. 37, p. 1385-1403. 1999.
McDaniel, D. K., Hemming, S.R., McLennan, S.M. and Hanson,G.N., Resetting of neodymium isotopes and redistribution of REEs during sedimentary processes: The Early Proterozoic Chelmsford Formation, Sudbury Basin, Ontario, Canada. Geochemica et Cosmochimica Acta, v. 58, pp. 931-941. 1994.
McGrath, P. H., Broome, H. J., A gravity model for the Sudbury Structure along the Lithoprobe seismic line. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 955-958. 1993.
McGrath, P. H., Broome, H. J., A gravity model for the Sudbury Structure along the Lithoprobe seismic line. Geophysical Reserach Letters, v. 21, p. 955-958. 1994.
McGrath, P. H., Broome, H. J., Gravity modelling of the Sudbury structure (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v. 30, p.482. 1992.
McGuinty, W. J., Petrology, geochemistry and paleomagnetism of a section from the North Range of the Sudbury Irruptive near Lavack, Ontario. University of Ottawa, Ottawa, 60. 1981.
McGuinty, W. J., Petrology, geochemistry and paleomagnetism of a section from the North Range of the Sudbury Irruptive near Lavack, Ontario. University of Ottawa, Ottawa, 60. 1981.
McHone J F., Dietz, R. S., Earth's multiple impact craters and astroblemes (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science, v. XXIII, pp. 887-888. 1992.
McHone, J. F., Dietz, R.S. and Peredery,W.V., Sudbury breccia and suevite as glacial indicators transported 800 km to Kentland astrobleme, Indiana (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 51. 1992.
Meldrum, A., Abdel-Rahman, A.-F.M., Martin, R.F. and Wodicka,N., The nature, age and petrogenesis of the Cartier Batholith, northern flank of the Sudbury Structure, Ontario, Canada. Precambrian Research, v. 82, pp. 265-285. 1997.
Miao, X. G., Moon, W.M. and Milkereit,B., Seismic imaging of the crustal structure of the Levack Gneiss Complex, northwest of the Sudbury Structure (abstract). CGU, Program with Abstracts, Banff, AB. 1994.
Miao, X., Moon, W.M., Milkeriet, B. and Mwenifumbo,C.J., Three component vertical seismic profiling (VSP) experiment in the Sudbury Basin. Geophysical Reserach Letters, v. 21, p. 939-942. 1994.
Mildereit, B., Wu, J. and White,D., Lithoprobe seismic reflection survey across the Sudbury structure (abstract). Canadian Geophysical Union, Banff, Alberta. 1993.
Milkereit, B., Berrer, E.K., King, A.R., Watts, A.H., Roberts, B., Adam, E., Eaton, D.W., Wu,J.and M.H.Salisbury., Development of 3-D seismic exploration technology for deep nickel-copper deposits--A case history from the Sudbury basin, Canada, Geophysics, v 65, n 6, p 1890-1899. 2000.
Milkereit, B., Boerner, D. E., Integrated geophysical study of the Sudbury structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Milkereit, B., Green, A., Wu, J., White, D. and Adam,E., Integrated seismic and borehole geophysical study of the Sudbury Igneous Complex. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 931-934. 1994.
Milkereit, B., Green,A.and the Sudbury Working Group., Deep geometry of the Sudbury structure from seismic reflection profiling. Geology, v. 20, p. 807-811. 1992.
Milkereit, B., Third dimension of the Sudbury structure: Results from reflection seismic profiling (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v. 30, p. 481. 1992.
Milkereit, B., White, D.J. and Green,A.G., Towards an improved seismic imaging technique for crustal structures: The Lithoprobe Sudbury experiment. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 927-930. 1994.
Milkereit, B., Wu, J. and Boerner,D., Probing the three-dimensional nature of the Sudbury structure (abstract). Canadian Geophysical Union (CGU), 163. 1995.
Milkereit, B., Wu, J. and Cowan,J., Probing the three-dimensional nature of the Sudbury structure (abstract). GSC Forum '95. 1995.
Miller, A. H., Innes, M. J. S., Gravity in the Sudbury basin and vicinity. Ottawa Dominion Observatory Publications, v. 18, pp. 15-32. 1955.
Molnár, F., Watkinson, D. H. and J. O. Everest., Fluid-inclusion characteristics of hydrothermal Cu-Ni-PGE veins in granitic and metavolcanic rocks at the contact of the Little Stobie deposit, Sudbury, Canada. Chemical Geology, v. 154, p. 279-301. 1999.
Molnár, F., Watkinson, D.H., Jones, P.C. and Gatter,I., Fluid inclusion evidence for hydrothermal enrichment of magmatic ore at the contact zone of the Ni-Cu-platinum-group Element 4b deposit, Lindsley Mine, Sudbury, Canada. Economic Geology, v. 92, pp. 674-685. 1997.
Moon, W. M., L.X. Jiao., Sudbury impact structure modeling with high resolution seismic reflection survey results. Journal of the Royal Astronomical Society of Canada, v. 92, p.250-257. 1998.
Moon, W. M., Miao, X.G. and Milkereit,B., Crustal structure northwest of the Sudbury basin (LITHOPROBE Sudbury Reflection Line #42). Sudbury Geology Workshop and Fieldtrip,. 1994.
Moon, W. M., Sereu, M., Kublik, E.R. and Krause,B.R., High resolution seismic survey in the north range of Sudbury basin, Ontario (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 19. 1988.
Moore, C. M., Nikolic, S., The Craig nickel deposit, Sudbury, Ontario (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v. 30, p. 486. 1992.
Moore, M., Lightfoot, P. C. and R. R. Keays., Geology and geochemistry of North Range footwall ultramafic rocks, Sudbury igneous complex, Sudbury, Ontario. Ontario Geological Survey Miscellaneous Paper 164, pp. 122-123. 1995.
Morris, W. A., Intrusive and tectonic history of the Sudbury micropegmatite: The evidence from paleomagnetism. Economic Geology, v. 76, pp. 791-804. 1981.
Morris, W. A., Is the Sudbury Igneous Complex a single melt sheet produced by a meteorite impact? Paleomagnetic and geochemical evidence for genesis by multiple phases (abstract). GAC/MAC, Program with Abstracts, Annual Meeting, Waterloo, ON, v. 19, A79. 1994.
Morris, W. A., Paleomagnetic constraints on the magmatic, tectonic, and metamorphic history of the Sudbury basin region. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 411-427. 1984.
Morris, W. A., Pay, R., Genesis of the Foy(?) offset and its sulfide ores: The paleomagnetic evidence from a study in Hess Township, Sudbury, Ontario. Economic Geology, v. 76, pp. 1895-1905. 1981.
Morris, W. A., Tectonic and metamorphic history of the Sudbury norite: The evidence from paleomagnetism. Economic Geology, v. 75, pp. 260-277. 1980.
Morrison, G. G., Jago, B.C. and Little,T.L., Sudbury footwall mineralization, with particular reference to the McCreedy East and Victor deposits (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v. 30, p. 483-484. 1992.
Morrison, G. G., Morphological features of the Sudbury structure in relation to an impact origin. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 513-520. 1984.
Morrison, G. G., The Sudbury basin at depth (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 11. 1988.
Muir, T. L., Geology of Morgan Lake-Nelson Lake Area, District of Sudbury. Ontario Geology Survey, Open File Report 5426, 203 p. 1983.
Muir, T. L., Peredery, W. V., The Onaping formation. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 139-210. 1984.
Muir, T. L., The Sudbury structure; considerations and models of an endogenic origin. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 449-490. 1984.
Müller-Mohr, V., Breccias in the basement of a deeply eroded impact structure, Sudbury, Canada (extended abstract). Tectonophysics, v. 216, pp. 219-226. 1992.
Müller-Mohr, V., Sudbury project (University of Munster-Ontario Geological Survey): (5) New investigations on Sudbury breccia (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 53. 1992.
Müller-Mohr, V., The Sudbury structure (Canada): Breccias in the basement of a deeply eroded impact structure (abstract). Pesonen, L.J. and Niemisara, H., eds., Symposium Fennoscandian Impact Structures, p. 49. 1990.
Mungall, J. E., Hanley, J. J., Origins of Outliers of the Huronian Supergroup within the Sudbury Structure. The Journal of Geology, Vol. 112, P. 59 - 70. 2004.
Naldrett, A. J., Asif, M., Schandl,E.and T.Searcy., Platinum-group elements in the Sudbiry ores: significance with respect to the origin of different ore zones and to the exploration for footwall orebodies. Economic Geology, v. 94, p. 185-210. 1999.
Naldrett, A. J., Bray, J.G., Gasparrini, E. L., Podolsky, T. and Rucklidge,J.C., Cryptic variation and the petrology of the Sudbury nickel irruptive. Economic Geology, v. 65, pp. 122-155. 1970.
Naldrett, A. J., Hewins, R. H., The main mass of the Sudbury igneous complex. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 235-251. 1984.
Naldrett, A. J., Hewins, R.H., Dressler, B.O. and Rao,B.V., The contact sublayer of the Sudbury igneous complex. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 253-274. 1984.
Naldrett, A. J., Innes, D.G., Sowa, J. and Gorton,M., Compositional variation within and between five Sudbury ore deposits. Economic Geology, v. 77, p. 1519-1534. 1982.
Naldrett, A. J., Kullerud, G., A study of the Strathcona mine and its bearing on the origin of the nickel-copper ores of the Sudbury district, Ontario. Journal of Petrology, v. 8, pp. 453-531. 1967.
Naldrett, A. J., Mineralogy and composition of the Sudbury ores. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 309-325. 1984.
Naldrett, A. J., Nickel sulphide deposits - their classification and genesis, with special emphasis on deposits of volcanic association. 1973 Transactions, The Canadian Institute of Mining and Metallurgy and The Mining Society of Nova Scotia, v. LXXVI, p. 183-201. 1973.
Naldrett, A. J., Pessaren, A. and Chusi Li., Variation in the Ni, Cu and PGE content of ore on the North Range at Sudbury, between the Hardy and Longvack mines (abstract). The Canadian Mineralogist, Journal of the Mineralogical Association of Canada, v. 30, p. 495-496. 1992.
Naldrett, A. J., Rao, B.V. and Evensen,N.M., Contamination at Sudbury and its role in ore formation. The Institute of Mining and Metallurgy, pp. 75-91. 1986.
Naldrett, A. J., Summary, discussion, and synthesis. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 533-569. 1984.
Norman, M. D., Sudbury Igneous Complex: Impact melt or endogenous magma? Implications for lunar crustal evolution. Geological Society of America Special Paper 293, pp. 331-341. 1994.
Norman, M. D., Sudbury igneous complex: Impact melt or igneous rock? Implications for lunar magmatism (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 54-55. 1992.
O'Connor, J. P., Spray, J. G., Geological setting of the Manchester Offset Dike within the South Range of the Sudbury impact structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Ogilvie, B. Y., Robertson, B. and Grieve,R.A.F., Meteorite impact features in Canada: An inventory and an evaluation. Unpublished Report, 180 p. 1984.
Olaniyan, O., Smith, R.S., Lafrance, B. A contrained potential field data interpretation of the deeop geomtry of the Sudbury Structure. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, vol.51, pp.715-729. 2014.
Ontario Geological Survey special volume, Proceedings of the Sudbury - Noril'sk Symposium. Lightfoot, P.C., and Naldrett, A.J., eds., Ministry of Northern Development and Mines, Toronto, v. 5, 423 p. 1994.
Orlov, L. N., The association between meteoritic impact and induced volcanism (in Russian). AN SSSR Izvestiya, seriya geologicheskaya, v. 9, pp. 154-157. 1976.
Ostermann, M., Deutsch, A. and Agrinier,P., Geochemical variations (REE, delta180) in the Dioritic Foy offset dike, Sudbury structure(Canada) (abstract). 4th International Workshop of the ESF Scientific Network on "Impact Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth". The Role of Impacts on the Evolution of the Atmosphere and Biosphere with Regard to Short- and Long-Term Changes, p. 131-132. 1995.
Ostermann, M., Deutsch, A., Buhl, D. and Schärer,U., Geochemical characteristics of the Foy Offset Dike, Sudbury Impact Structure (Canada) (abstract). European Science Foundation, Third International Workshop. Shock Wave Behaviour of Solids in Nature and Experiments, Limoges, France. 1994.
Ostermann, M., Deutsch, A., Geochemistry of the Sudbury Igneous Complex (SIC), Ontario, Canada (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVIII, pp. 1049-1050. 1997.
Ostermann, M., Deutsch, A., The Sudbury Igneous Complex (SIC) as impact melt layer: Geochemical evidence for in situ differentiation (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Ostermann, M., Deutsch, A., Therriault, A.M. and Grieve,R.A.F., The Sudbury impact structure: Geochemistry of the drill cores 70011 and 52848 ("Igneous" Complex) (abstract). Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, p. A102. 1996.
Ostermann, M., Schärer, U. and Deutsch,A., First U-Pb data for zircons from the Foy Offset Dike (Sudbury impact structure; Canada) (abstract). Second International Conference. Imapct Cratering and Evolution of Planet Earth. The Identification and Characterization of Impacts. 1994.
Ostermann, M., Schärer, U. and Deutsch,A., Impact melt dikes in the Sudbury multi-ring basin (Canada): Implications from uranium-lead geochronology on the Foy Offset Dike. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, pp. 494-501. 1996.
Owen, D. L., Coats, C. J. A., Falconbridge and East mines. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 371-378. 1984.
Pattison, E. F., Tectonic origin for Sudbury, Ontario, shatter cones: discussion. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 91, pp. 754-756. 1980.
Pattison, E. F., The Sudbury sublayer. Canadian Mineralogist, v. 17, pp. 257-274. 1979.
Pekeski, D., Lightfoot, P. C. and R. R. Keays., Geology and geochemistry of the Totten Mine section of the Worthington Offset, Sudbury igneous complex, Ontario. Ontario Geological Survey Miscellaneous Paper 164, pp. 124-125. 1995.
Pentek, A., Molnar, F., Tuba, G., Watkinson, D.H., Jones, P.S. The significance of partial melting precesses in hydrothermal low sulphide Cu-Ni-PGE mineralization within the footwall of the Sudbury igneous complex, Ontario, Canada. Economic Geology and the Bulletin of the Society of Economic Geologists, vol. 108, pp.59-78. 2013.
Peredery, W. V., Chemistry of fluidal glasses and melt bodies in the Onaping formation. Geological Association of Canada, Special Paper 10, pp. 49-59. 1972.
Peredery, W. V., Morrison, G. G., Discussion of the origin of the Sudbury structure. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Ministry of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 491-5. 1984.
Peredery, W. V., Naldrett, A. J., Petrology of the Upper Irruptive Rocks, Sudbury, Ontario. Economic Geology, vol. 70, pp. 164-175. 1975.
Peredery, W. V., Volcanic rocks, chilled micropegmatite, or impact breccias and melt rocks in the Onaping formation? (abstract). Geological Association of Canada-Mineralogical Association of Canada, Abstracts of Papers, Sudbury, p. 55. 1971.
Petrus, J.A., Ames, D.E., Kambler, B.S. On the track of the elusive Sudbury impact; geochemical evidence for a chondrite or comet bolide. Terra Nova, vol.27, pp.9-20. 2015.
Petrus, J.A., Kenny, G.G., Ayer, J.A., Lightfoot, P.C., Kamber, B.S. Uranium-lead zircon systematics in the Sudbury impact crater-fill; implications for target lithologies and crater evolution. Journal of the Geological Society of London, vol.173, pp.59-75. 2016.
Popelar, J., Gravity interpretation of the Sudbury area. Geological Association of Canada, Special Paper No. 10, pp. 103-111. 1972.
Popelar, J., Gravity measurements in the Sudbury area with map No. 138 - Sudbury. Department of Energy, Mines and Resources, Ottawa, Canada, 8 p. 1971.
Prevec, S. A., Baadsgaard, H., Petrogenesis and enigmatic geochronology from early Proterozoic gabbros in Drury and Falconbridge Townships; shock resetting: (abstract). GAC/MAC, Program with Abstracts, Annual Meeting, Waterloo, ON, v. 19, A90. 1994.
Prevec, S. A., Corfu, F., Moore, M.L., Lightfoot, P.C. and Keays,R.R., Postmagmatic zircon growth or exotic early magmatic phases associated with the emplacement of the Sudbury Igneous Complex: Samarium-neodymium isotopic, geochemical, and petrographic evidence (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Prevec, S. A., Cowan, D. R., Cooper., Geophysical evidence for a pre-impact Sudbury dome, southern Superior Province, Canada, Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 42 , n. 1 , p. 1-11. 2005.
Prevec, S. A., Keays, R.R., Lightfoot, P.C. and Xie,Q., Origin or the sublayer of the Sudbury Igneous Complex: Samarium-neodymium isotopic, geochemical, and petrographic evidence for incomplete crustal homogenization (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Prevec, S. A., Xie, Q., Keays, R.R. and Lightfoot,P.C., Geochemical and samarium-neodymium isotopic evidence regarding the origin of offset dikes of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Ontario (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Prevec, S. A., Zhou, M-F., Lightfoot,P.C.and R.R.Keays., Discrimination of Barren and mineralized sublayer environments of the Sudbury igneous complex. Ontario Geological Survey Miscellaneous Paper 164, pp. 129. 1995.
Pye, E. G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin,P.E.(eds.)., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure. Ministry of Natural Resources, Toronto, 604. 1984.
Rao, B. V., Naldrett, A.J. and Evensen,N.M., Grant 146 crustal contamination in the sublayer, Sudbury igneous complex: A combined trace element and strontium isotope study. Pye, E.G., ed., Ontario Geological Survey, Geoscience Research Grant Program, Summary of Research, Miscellaneous Paper 113, pp. 128-145. 1984.
Reimold, W. U., Dressler, B. O., The economic significance of impact processes (abstract). Abstracts for the International Workshop on Meteorite Impact on the Early Earth, Perth, Australia, pp. 36-37. 1990.
Riller, U. P., A.R., Cruden and Schwerdtner,W.M., Magnetic fabric and microstructural evidence for a tectono-thermal overprint of the early Proterozoic Murray pluton, Central Ontario, Canada. Journal of Structural Geology, v. 18, pp. 1005-1016. 1996.
Riller, U. P., Doman, D. , Grieve, R. A. F., The Sudbuy Igneous Complex; Canada: Evidence for large-meteorite impact during paleoproterozoic orogenic activity, First International Conference on Impact Cratering in the Solar System. 2006.
Riller, U. P., Schwerdtner, W. M., Mid-crustal deformation at the southern flank of the Sudbury Basin, central Ontario, Canada. GSA Bulletin, v. 109, pp. 841-854. 1997.
Riller, U. P., Schwerdtner, W. M., Structural significance of deformation patterns in Huronian footwall rocks of the Sudbury basin (abstract). Sudbury Geology Workshop and Fieldtrip,. 1994.
Riller, U. P., Tectonometamorphic episodes affecting the Southern Footwall of the Sudbury Basin and their significance for the origin of the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Central Ontario, Canada. Ph.D. Thesis, University of Toronto, p. 135. 1996.
Riller, U., Dressler, B. O., Structural Characteristics of the Sudbury Impact Structure, Canada, Point to a Protracted Tectonomagmatic Evolution of the Sudbury Igneous Complex. Large Meteorite Impacts. 2003.
Robertson, P. B., Grieve, R. A. F., Impact structures in Canada: Their recognition and characteristics. Journal of the Royal Astronomical Society of Canada, v. 69, pp. 1-21. 1975.
Roest, W. R., Pilkington, M., Restoring post-impact deformation at Sudbury: A circular argument. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 959-962. 1994.
Rondot, J., Charlevoix and Sudbury as gravity-readjusted impact structures, Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 35, pp. 707-713. 2000.
Rondot, J., Charlevoix and Sudbury as simple readjusted craters (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Rousell, D. H., Gibson, H. L., Did the Sudbury meteorite strike a hot spot? (abstract). GAC/MAC,. 1996.
Rousell, D. H., Gibson, H.L. and Jonasson,I.R., The tectonic, magmatic and mineralization history of the Sudbury structure. Explor. Mining Geol., v. 6, pp. 1-22. 1997.
Rousell, D. H., Long, D. G. F., Are outliers of the Huronian Supergroup preserved in structures associated with the collapse of the Sudbury Impact Structure, Journal of Geology, v.106, p.407-419. 1998.
Rousell, D. H., Long, D. G. F., Do outliers of the Huronian Supergroup mark the downfaulted rim of the Sudbury crater? (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Rousell, D. H., Mechanics of formation of Sudbury breccia (abstract). Sudbury Geology Workshop and Fieldtrip,. 1994.
Rousell, D. H., Mineralization in the Whitewater group. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Sturcture, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 219-232. 1984.
Rousell, D. H., Onwatin and Chelmsford formations. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 211-218. 1984.
Rousell, D. H., Peredery, W. V., Nature and origin of Sudbury breccia (abstract). GAC/MAC,. 1996.
Rousell, D. H., Structural geology of the Sudbury basin. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 83-95. 1984.
Rousell, D. H., Sudbury and the meteorite theory. Geoscience, v. 8, pp. 167-169. 1981.
Rousell, D. H., The origin of clastic Sudbury breccia (abstract). GAC/MAC, Program with Abstracts, Annual Meeting, Waterloo, ON, v. 19, A95. 1994.
Rousell, D. H., The origin of foliation and lineation in the Onaping formation and the deformation of the Sudbury basin. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 12, pp. 1379-1395. 1975.
Salisbury, M. H., Iuliucci, R. and Long,C., Velocity and reflection structure of the Sudbury Structure from laboratory measurements. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 923-926. 1994.
Schwarcz, H. P., Sulfur isotope analyses of some Sudbury, Ontario, ores. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 10, n. 9, p. 1444-1459. 1973.
Scott, R. G., Benn, K., Peak-ring rim collapse accomodated by impact melt-filled transfer faults, Sudbury impact structure, Canada, Geology, v 29, n 8, p 747-750. 2001.
Scott, R. G., Spray, J. G., Characteristics of the Frood-Stobie pseudotachylyte belt, Sudbury impact structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Scott, R. G., Spray, J. G., Magnetic fabric constraints on friction melt flow regimes and ore emplacement direction within the Southern Range Breccia Belt, Sudbury Impact Structure. Tectonophysics, v. 307, p. 163-189. 1999.
Scott, R. G., Spray, J. G., Magnetic Fabric Constraints on Friction Melt Flow Reimes and Ore Emplacement Direction Within the South Range Breccia Belt, Sudbury Impact Structure, Tectonophysics v. 307, pp. 163-189. 1999.
Scott, R. G., Spray, J. G., Structural origin and tectonic modification of the South Range Breccia Belt (SRBB), Sudbury Impact Structure, Ontario, 1998 GSA Annual Meeting, Toronto, Ontario. Abstract No. 51136. 1998.
Scott, R. G., Spray, J. G., The South Range Breccia Belt of the Sudbury Impact Structure: A possible terrace collapse feature, Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v.35, p.505-520. 2000.
Scribbins, B. T., Rae, D.R. and Naldrett,A.J., Mafic and ultramafic inclusions in the sublayer of the Sudbury igneous complex. Canadian Mineralogist, v. 22, pp. 67-75. 1984.
Shanks, W. S., Dressler, B.O. and Schwerdtner,W.M., New developments in Sudbury geology (abstract). Abstracts for the International Workshop on Meteorite Impact on the Early Earth, Perth, Australia, pp. 46. 1990.
Shanks, W. S., Schwerdtner, W. M., Crude quantitative estimates of the original northwest-southeast dimension of the Sudbury Structure, south-central Canadian Shield. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 28, pp. 1677-1686. 1991.
Shanks, W. S., Schwerdtner, W. M., Structural analysis of the central and southwestern Sudbury Structure, Southern Province, Canadian Shield. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 28, pp. 411-430. 1991.
Sharpton, V. L., Dressler, B.O. and Schuraytz,B.C., The Chicxulub and Sudbury multi-ring impact structures: A comparison (abstract). GAC/MAC, Program with Abstracts, Annual Meeting, Waterloo, ON, v. 19, A102. 1994.
Sims, P. K., Card, K.D., Morey, G.B. and Peterman,Z.E., The Great Lakes tectonic zone - A major crustal structure in central North America. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 91, pp. 690-698. 1980.
Singhroy, V., Mussakowski, R., Dressler, B.O., Trowell, N.F. and Grieve,R.A.F., SAR in support of geological investigations of the Sudbury structure (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 69. 1992.
Slaney, V. R., Misra, K., Radar studies of the Sudbury basin (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 16. 1988.
Sopher, S. R., Paleomagnetic study of the Sudbury irruptive. Geological Survey of Canada Bulletin, v. 90, 34 p. 1963.
Souch, B. E., Podolsky, T. and Geological Staff., The sulfide ores of Sudbury: Their particular relationship to a distinctive inclusion-bearing facies of the Nickel Irruptive. Economic Geology Monograph, v. 4, pp.252-261. 1969.
Speers, E. C., The age relation and origin of the common Sudbury breccia. Journal of Geology, v. 65, pp. 497-514. 1957.
Spray, J. G., Localized shock- and friction-induced melting in response to hypervelocity impact, in Meteorites: Flux with time and impact effects. ed M.M. Grady, R. Hutchinson, G.J.H. McCall & D.A. Rothery. London, England. Geological Society, Special Publication 140, p.195-204. 1998.
Spray, J. G., Murphy, A. j. , Shaw, C. S. J. and Tuchscherer, M. G., Chilling Evidence for the Bulk Composition of the Impact Melt Sheet at Sudbury: Evidence from Offsets Dykes.
Spray, J. G., Superfaults. Geology, v. 25, pp. 579-582. 1997.
Spray, J. G., Thompson, L. M., Friction melt distribution in multi-ring impact basins: Evidence from the Sudbury structure (abstract). AGU, p. 387. 1993.
Spray, J. G., Thompson, L. M., Friction melt distribution in terrestrial multi-ring impact basins. Nature, v. 373, pp. 130-132. 1994.
Stevenson, J. S., Recognition of the quartzite breccia in the Whitewater series, Sudbury basin, Ontario. Transactions of the Royal Society of Canada, v. LV, pp. 57-66. 1961.
Stevenson, J. S., Stevenson, L. S., Sudbury, Ontario, and the meteorite theory. Geoscience, v. 7, pp. 103-108. 1980.
Stevenson, J. S., Sudbury problems and suggestions for further research. Pye, E.G., Naldrett, A.J. and Giblin, P.E., eds., The Geology and Ore Deposits of the Sudbury Structure, Min. of Natural Resources, Toronto, v. 1, pp. 523-531. 1984.
Stevenson, J. S., The upper contact phase of the Sudbury micropegmatite. The Canadian Mineralogist, v. 7, pp. 413-419. 1963.
Stevenson, J. S., The volcanic origin of the Onaping formation Sudbury, Canada. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 249-257. 1990.
Stöffler, D., Avermann, M., Bischoff, L., Brockmeyer, P., Deutsch, A., Dressler, B.O.,Lakomy, R. and Müller-Mohr,V., Sudbury, Canada: Remnant of the only multi-ring (?) impact basin on Earth (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 24, p. 328. 1989.
Stöffler, D., Deutsch, A., Avermann, M., Bischoff, L., Brockmeyer, P., Buhl, D., Lakomy, R. and Müller-Mohr,B., The formation of the Sudbury Structure, Canada: Towards a unified impact model. Geological Society of America Special Paper 293, pp. 303-318. 1994.
Stöffler, D., Deutsch, A., Avermann, M., Brockmeyer, P., Lakomy, R. and Müller-Mohr,V., Sudbury project (University of Munster-Ontario Geological Survey): (3) Petrology, chemistry, and origin of breccia formations (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 71-72. 1992.
Swayne, R. E., Pascoli, L. S., Continuous wireline core drilling: An alternative method for oil and gas exploration (abstract). Canadian Continental Drilling Program Report 88-2, Scientific Drilling: The Sudbury Structure, p. 24. 1988.
Szabo, E., Halls, H. C., Deformation of the Sudbury Structure: Paleomagnetic evidence from the Sudbury Breccia, Precambrian Research, Vol. 150, P. 27 - 48. 2006.
Therriault, A. M., Fowler, A. D. and R. A. F. Grieve., The Sudbury igneous complex - unique but not so complex, GeoCanada2000: Millenium Geoscience Summit, May 29-June 2, Calgary Alberta, abstract 956. 2000.
Therriault, A. M., Grieve, R.A.F., Ostermann, M. and Deutsch,A., Sudbury Igneous Complex: How many melt systems? (abstract). Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, pp. A141-A142. 1996.
Therriault, A. M., Ostermann, M., Grieve, R.A.F. and Deutsch,A., Are Vredefort granophyre and Sudbury offsets birds of a feather? (abstract). Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, p. A142. 1996.
Thode, H. G., Dunford, H. B. and M. Shima., Sulfur isotope abundances in rocks of the Sudbury district and their geological significance. Economic Geology, v. 57, p. 565-578. 1962.
Thompson, L. M., A study of pseudotachylyte associated with the Sudbury Structure, Ontario, Canada. Unpublished Ph.D. thesis, University of New Brunswick, Canada, 202 p. 1996.
Thompson, L. M., Ring characteristics of the Sudbury multi-ring impact basin (abstract). European Science Foundation, Third International Workshop. Shock Wave Behaviour of Solids in Nature and Experiments, Limoges, France. 1994.
Thompson, L. M., Spray, J G. and Kelly,S P., Laser 40Ar-39Ar dating of pseudotachylytes from the Sudbury structure, Canada: Evidence for post-impact thermal overprinting in the north range (abstract). AGU, p. 389. 1993.
Thompson, L. M., Spray, J. G. and S. P. Kelley., Laser probe argon-40/argon-39 dating of pseudotachylyte from the Sudbury structure: evidence for post-impact thermal overprinting in the North Range. Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v. 33, p. 1259-1269. 1998.
Thompson, L. M., Spray, J. G., A comparison of the chemistry of pseudotachylyte breccias in the archean Levack gneisses of the Sudbury structure, Ontario (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 73-74. 1992.
Thompson, L. M., Spray, J. G., Pseudotachylyte petrogenesis: constraints from the Sudbury impact structure. Contributions to Mineralogy and Petrology, v. 125, pp. 359-374. 1996.
Thompson, L. M., Spray, J. G., Pseudotachylytic rock distribution and genesis within the Sudbury impact structure. Geological Society of America Special Paper 293, pp. 275-287. 1994.
Thompson, L. M., Spray, J.G. and Kelley,S.P., Dating of pseudotachylytic rocks from the Sudbury Impact Structure via the laser probe 40Ar-39Ar technique: Evidence for a 1.86 Ga formation event and post-impact thermal overprinting (abstract). GAC/MAC, Program with Abstracts, Annual Meeting, Waterloo, ON. 1994.
Thomson, O.A., Cavosie, A.J., Moser, D.E., Barker, I., Radovan, H.A. (2012) Detrital shocked zircons eroded from the 1.85 Ga Sudbury impact structure in modern fluvial and glacial sand deposits. GSA Abstracts with Program, v.44, no. 7, p.535.
Thomson, O.A., Cavosie, A.J., Moser, D.E., Barker, I., Radovan, H.A., and French, B.M. (2014) Preservation of detrital shocked minerals derived from the 1.85 Ga Sudbury impact structure in modern alluvium and Holocene glacial deposits. GSA Bulletin 126, 720-737.
Thomson, O.A., Cavosie, A.J., Radovan, H.A., Moser, D.E. (2011) First report of detrital shocked zircons from the Paleoproterozoic Sudbury impact structure, Ontario Canada. 42nd Annual Lunar and Planetary Science conference, abstr. 2217.
Thomson, O.A., Cavosie, A.J., Radovan, H.A., Moser, D.E. (2012) Origin of detrital shocked zircons from different sedimentary environments at the Sudbury impact structure, Ontario Canada. 43nd Annual Lunar and Planetary Science conference, abstr. 2129.
Vos, M. A., The petrology of some "quartz diorites" of the Sudbury basin, Ontario, Canada. Privately published paper, 70 p. 1966.
Vujovic, Z., Lightfoot, P. C. and C. J. Hawkesworth., Origin and geochemical evolution of mafic and ultramafic inclusions in the sublayer of the Sudbury igneous complex at Whistle Mine. Ontario Geological Survey Miscellaneous Paper 164, pp. 130-133. 1995.
Walker, R. J., Morgan, J.W., Naldrett, A.J., Li, C. and Fassett,J.D., Re-Os isotope systematics of Ni-Cu sulfide ores, Sudbury igneous Complex, Ontario: evidence for a major crustal component. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 105, pp. 416-429. 1991.
Warner, S., Martin, R.F., Abdel-Rahman,A-F.M.and R.Doig., Apatite as a monitor of fractionation, degassing, and metamorphism in the Sudbury igneous complex, Ontario. Canadian Mineralogist, v. 36, p. 981-999. 1998.
Warren, P. H., Claeys, P. and Cedillo-Pardo,E., Mega-impact melt petrology (Chicxulub, Sudbury, and the Moon): Effects of scale and other factors on potential for fractional crystallization and development of cumulates. Geological Society of America Special Paper 307, pp. 105-124. 1996.
Warren, P. H., Claeys, P. and Cedillo-Pardo,E., Where are the Chicxulub coarse-grained, igneously layered impact melt rocks analogous to those at Sudbury? Geological Society of America Special Paper (in press). 1994.
Watkinson D.H., Molnar, F., Remobilization of platinum-group elements by saline fluid: Evidence from fluid-inclusion studies at the Lindsley Mine, Sudbury, Ontario (abstract). GAC/MAC, p. A100. 1996.
Weiser, T., Dressler, B.O. and Brockmeyer,P., The Onaping Formation, Sudbury structure - A Proterozoic impact breccia (abstract). GAC/MAC, p. A101. 1996.
Westbroek, H., Stewart, R., The formation, morphology, and economic potential of meteorite impact craters, CREWES Research Report v. 8, p. 1-26. 1996.
White, D. J., Milkereit, B., Wu, J.J., Salisbury, M.H., Mwenifumbo, J., Berrer, E.K., Moon, W. and Lodha,G., Seismic reflectivity of the Sudbury Structure North Range from borehole logs. Geophysical Research Letters, v. 21, p. 935-938. 1994.
Wichman, R. W., Schultz, P. H., Floor-fractured crater models of the Sudbury structure, Canada (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 79-80. 1992.
Wichman, R. W., Schultz, P. H., Floor-fractured crater models of the Sudbury Structure, Canada: Implications for initial crater size and crater modifications. Meteoritics, v. 28, pp. 222-231. 1993.
Wichman, R. W., Schultz, P. H., Implications of early crater-centered volcanism and tectonism at the Sudbury structure (abstract). Abstracts for the International Workshop on Meteorite Impact on the Early Earth, Perth, Australia, pp. 36-37. 1990.
Wodicka N., Card, K. D., U-Pb zircon geochronology of the Levack gneiss complex, the northern footwall of the Sudbury structure (abstract). Sudbury Geology Workshop and Fieldtrip,. 1994.
Wood C.R., Spray, J. G., Origin and emplacement of Offset Dykes in the Sudbury impact structure: Constraints from Hess. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 33, pp. 337-347. 1998.
Wood, C. R., Spray, J.G. and Napoli,M., Emplacement of the Hess Offset in the North Range of the Sudbury impact structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Wu, J., Milkereit, B and Boerner,D., The enignatic Sudbury structure: What does seismic say? (abstract). AGU, p. 389. 1993.
Wu, J., Milkereit, B. and Boerner,D., Timing constraints on deformation history of the Sudbury impact structure. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 31, pp. 1654-1660. 1994.
Wu, J., Milkereit, B. and Boerner,D.E., Seismic imaging of the enigmatic Sudbury structure. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 100, pp. 4117-4130. 1995.
Xie, Q., Keays, R.R., Prevec, S.A. and Lightfoot,P.C., Origin of the Sudbury Igneous Complex and sulfide mineralization: Evidence from platinum group elements (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Zaychenko, V. Yu., Kuznetsov, O.L. and Popsuy Shapko,G.P., Nature of ring-shaped photo-anomalies identified by remote surveys (in Russian). Sovetskaya Geologiya, v. 1, pp. 98-106. 1981.
Zhou, M. -F., Lightfoot, P.C., Keays, R.R., Moore, M.L. and Morrison,G.G., Petrogenetic significance of chromian spinels from the Sudbury Igneous Complex, Ontario, Canada. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences, v. 34, pp. 1405-1419. 1997.
Zhou, M. -F., Sun, M. and J. Malpas., Origin of the Sudbury Igneous Complex (Northern Ontario, Canada): A new interpretation, Proceedings of the 30th International Geological Congress, v 9, p 429-440. 1997.
Zotkin, I. T., "Moon" craters on the Earth (in Russian). Priroda, v. 9, pp. 95-105. 1969.
Zotkin, I. T., Tsvetkov, V. I., Searches for meteorite craters on the Earth (in Russian). Astronomicheskii Vestnik, v. 4, pp. 55-56. 1970.