Tookoonooka
Queensland
S 27° 7'
E 142° 50'
55
128 ± 5
N
Y
M
-
Bron, K.A., Accretionary and melt impactoclasts from the Tookoonooka impact event, Australia, Special Paper of the Geological Society of America, Issue 465, pp. 219-244, 2010
Bron, K. A., Gostin, V., The Tookoonooka marine impact horizon, Australia: Sedimentary and petrologic evidence. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, 47: 296–318. 2012
Glikson, A., Uysal, I. T., Geophysical and structural criteria for the identification of buried impact structures, with reference to Australia. Earth-Science Reviews, vol. 125, pp. 114-122. 2005. 
Gorter, J. D., Gostin, V.A. and Plummer,P.S., The enigmatic sub-surface Tookoonooka Complex in south-west Queensland: its impact origin and implications for hydrocarbon accumulations. B.J. O'Neil, ed., in The Cooper and Eromanga Basins, Australia, Petroleum Exploration Society of Australia, Adelaide, p. 441-456. 1989.
Gostin, V. A., Therriault, A. M., Tookoonooka, a large buried early Cretaceous impact structure in the Eromanga Basin of southwestern Queensland, Australia. Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v. 32, pp. 593-599. 1997.
Grieve, R. A. F., Masaitis, V. L., The economic potential of terrestrial impact craters. International Geology Review, v. 36, pp. 105-151. 1994.
Haines, P. W., Impact Cratering and Distal Ejecta: The Australian Record. Australian Journal of Earth Sciences 52, P. 481 - 507. 2005.
Westbroek, H., Stewart, R., The formation, morphology, and economic potential of meteorite impact craters, CREWES Research Report v. 8, p. 1-26. 1996.
Young, I. F., Late Jurassic channels and associated fill, Eromanga Basin (ATP 259P), Queensland: A seismic stratigraphic study (abstract). Exploration Geophysics 5th Geophysical Conference and Exhibition, pp. 238-242. 1987.