Upheaval Dome
Utah, U.S.A.
N 38° 26'
W 109° 54'
10
< 170
Y
Y
S
-
Alvarez, W., Staley, E., O'Connor,D.and M.A.Chan., Synsedimentary deformation in the Jurassic of southeastern Utah - A case of impact shaking? Geology, v 26, n 7, p 579-582. 1998.
Boone, J. D., Albritton, C. C.,Jr., Established and supposed examples of meteoritic craters and structures. Field and Laboratory, v. 6, pp. 44-56. 1938.
Bridges, L. W. D., Alvarez, W., Staley, E., O'Conner, D., Chan,M.A., Synsedimentary Deformation in the Jurassic of Southeastern Utah- A Case of Impact Shaking?: Comment and Reply, Geology; July 1999, pp. 661-2. 1999.
Bucher, W. H., Cryptovolcanic structures in the United States. 16th International Geological Congress, Report, v. 2, pp. 1055-1084. 1936.
Buchner, E., Kenkmann, T., Upheaval Dome, Utah, USA: Impact Origin Confirmed. Geology, v 36, no 3, p 227-230. 2008
Grieve, R. A. F., The record of impact on Earth: Implications for a major Cretaceous/Tertiary impact event. Geological Society of America, Special Paper 190, pp. 25-37. 1982.
Gurov, E. P., Gurova, E. P., Impact structures on the Earth's surface (in Russian). Geologicheskii Zhurnal, v. 47, pp. 117-124. 1987.
Herkenhoff, K. E., Giegengack, R., Kriens, B.J., Louie, J.N., Omar, G.I., Plescia, J.B., Shoemaker,E.M., Geological and Geophysical Studies of the Upheaval Dome Impact Structure, Utah, LPSC XXX, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston, TX, Abstr. 1932 (CD-ROM). 1999.
Jackson, M. P. A., Shultz-Ela, D.D., Hudec, M.R., Watson, I.A. and Porter,M.L., Structure and evolution of Upheaval Dome: A pinched-off salt diapir, Geological Society of America Bulletin: vol. 110, No. 12, pp. 1547-1573. 1998.
Joesting, H. R., Plouff, D., Geophysical studies of the Upheaval Dome area, San Juan County, Utah. Intermountain Association of Petroleum Geologists, Guidebook, Ninth Annual Field Conference, pp. 86-92. 1958.
Kanbur, Z., Louie, J.N., Chavez-Perez, S., Plank,G.and D.Morey., Seismic reflection study of Upheaval Dome, Canyonlands National Park, Utah, Journal of Geophysical Research, v 105, E4, p 9489-9505. 2000.
Kenkmann, T., Jahn, A. Scherler, D. and Ivanov,B.A., Structure and formation of a central uplift: a case study at the Upheaval Dome impact crater, Utah. In Kenkmann, T., Hörz, F. and Deutsch, A. (eds.) Large Meteorite Impacts. Geological Society of America Special Paper 384 Chapter 6. 2005.
Kenkmann, T., Jahn, A. Scherler, D. and Ivanov,B.A., Anatomy of a central uplift of a complex impact crater: the Upheaval Dome structure, Utah. GSA Abstracts with Programs, 36 (5). 266. 2004.
Kenkmann, T., Ivanov, B. A., The Upheaval Dome impact crater, Utah: Combining structural and numerical data to constrain age, diameter, and amount of erosion. Lunar and Planetary Institute Third International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts, August 5-7th, 2003, Nordlingen, Germany. 2003.
Kenkmann, T., Dike formation, cataclastic flow, and rock fluidization during impact cratering: an example from the Upheaval Dome structure, Utah, Earth and Planetary Science Letters 214, p.43-58. 2003.
Kenkmann, T., Ivanov, B. A., The Upheaval Dome Impact crater, Utah: Combining Structural and Numerical data to constrain age, diameter, and amount of erosion. 3rd International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts, August 5-7, Nördlingen. 2003.
Kenkmann, T., Scherler, D., New structural constraints on the Upheaval Dome Impact Crater, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXIII. 2002.
Kenkmann, T., Scherler, D., New structural constraints on the Upheaval Dome impact crater. Lunar and Planetary Science Conference 33, Houston: CD-ROM 1037. 2002.
Key, W.R.O., Schultz, R.A. Fault formation formation in porous sedimentary rocks at high strain rates; first results from the Upheaval Dome impact structure in Uta, USA. Geological Society of America Bulletin, vol.123, pp.1161-1170. 2011.
Koeberl, C., Plescia, J.B., Hayward, C.L., Reimold,W.U., Impactites at the Upheaval Dome Structure, Utah? LPSC XXX, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston, TX, Abstr. 1094 (CD-ROM). 1999.
Koeberl, C., Plescia, J.B., Hayward, C.L., Reimold,W.U., A Petrographical and Geochemical Study of Quartzose Nodules, Country Rocks, and Dike Rocks form the Upheaval Dome Structure, Utah, Meteoritics; vol. 34, p. 861-8. 1999.
Kriens, B. J., Herkenhoff, K.E. and Shoemaker,E.M., Structure and kinematics of a complex crater: Upheaval Dome, southeast Utah (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Kriens, B. J., Herkenhoff, K. E., Shoemaker., Structure and Kinematics of a Complex Crater, Upheaval Dome, SE Utah, GSA Abstracts with Programs, 1996, Session 40. P. 108. 1996.
Louie, J. N., Chávez-Pérez, S. and Plank,G., Impact deformation at Upheaval Dome, Canyonlands National Park, Utah, revealed by seismic profiles (abstract), Fall AGU, p. F337. 1995.
McHone J F., Dietz, R. S., Earth's multiple impact craters and astroblemes (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science, v. XXIII, pp. 887-888. 1992.
McKnight, E. T., Geology of area between Green and Colorado rivers, Grand and San Juan counties, Utah. U.S. Geological Survey Bulletin 908, 147 p. 1940.
Okubo, C. H., Schultz, R. A., Compactional deformation bands in Wingate Sandstone; additional evience of an impact origin for Upheaval Dome, Utah. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, 256, P. 169 - 181. 2007.
Scherler, D., Kenkmann, T. , Jahn, A., Structural record of an oblique impact, Earth and Planetary Science Letters, 248, P. 43 - 53. 2006.
Scherler, D., Jahn, A. Kenkmann,T., Structural investigations in the central uplift of the Upheaval Dome impact crater, Utah, Lunar and Planetary Institute Third International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts, August 5-7th, 2003, Nordlingen, Germany. 2003.
Shoemaker, E. M., Herkenhoff, K. E., Upheaval Dome impact structure, Utah (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XV, pp. 778-779. 1984.
Shoemaker, E. M., Herkenhoff, K. E., Impact origin of Upheaval Dome, Utah (abstract). 36th Symposium on Southwestern Geology and Paleontology, Museum of Northern Arizona, Flagstaff, Arizona, p. 13. 1983.
Shoemaker, E. M., Structural features of southeastern Utah and adjacent parts of Colorado, New Mexico and Arizona. Stokes, W.L., ed., Guidebook to the Geology of Utah, no. 9, Uranium Deposits andGeneral Geology of Southeastern Utah, pp. 59-60. 1954.
Warme, J., Koeberl, C., Claeys,P.and W.Alvarez., Bolide impacts on wet targets, GSA Today, v 11, n 12, p 30-31. 2001.