Vredefort
South Africa
S 27° 0'
E 27° 30'
160
2023 ± 4
Y
Y
M
Chondrite
Albat, H. M., Mayer, J. J., Megascopic planar shock fractures in the Vredefort Structure: A potential time marker? Tectonophysics, v. 162, pp. 265-276. 1989.
Albat, H. M., Shatter cone/bedding interrelationship in the Vredefort structure: Evidence for meteorite impact? South African Journal of Geology, v. 91, pp. 106-113. 1988.
Allsopp, H. L., Fitch, F.J., Miller, J.A. and Reimold,U.W., 40Ar/39Ar stepheating age determinations relevant to formation of the Vredefort Dome, South Africa. South African Journal of Science, v. 87, pp. 431-442. 1991.
Antoine, L. A. G., Nicolaysen, L.O. and Niccol,S.L., Processed and enhanced gravity and magnetic images over the Vredefort structure and their interpretation. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 63-74. 1990.
Antoine, L. A. G., Reimold, W.U. and Colliston,W.P., A quasi-hertzian stress field from an internal source: A possible working model for the Vredefort structure (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 3-4. 1992.
Ashley, A. J., Gibson, R.L., Koeberl, C., Reimold, W.U., Greshake,A., A New Type of Melt Rock and First Evidence of Shock Deformation in Plagoclase from the Vredefort Impact Structure, South Africa, Meteoritics; vol. 34, A9-10. 1999.
Avdeev, V. L., Kats, Ya.G. and Fel'dman,V.I., Traces on meteorites on the surfaces of planets (in Russian). Priroda, v. 4, pp. 12-19. 1979.
Bayly, B., The Vredefort structure: estimates of energy for some internal sources and processes. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 153-167. 1990.
Bishopp, D. W., The geodynamics of the Vredefort dome. Geological Society of South Africa Transactions, v. 44, pp.1-18. 1941.
Bishopp, D. W., The Vredefort ring: A further consideration. The Journal of Geology, pp. 502-504. 1962.
Bisschoff, A. A., Mapping of the Vredefort Dome. 62nd Ann. Met. Soc., Johannesburg, Meteoritics Planet. Sci 34(suppl.), A11-A12. 2000.
Bisschoff, A. A., Note on the relative ages of the pseudotachylite and the basic granophyre in the Vredefort Dome. S. Afr. J. Geol., v. 99, pp. 89-92. 1996.
Bisschoff, A. A., The dioritic rocks of the Vredefort dome. Geological Society of South Africa Transactions, v. 75, pp. 31-45. 1972.
Bisschoff, A. A., The geology of the Vredefort Dome(Explanation of Geological Sheets 2627CA, CB, CC, CD, DA, DC, and 2727AA, AB, BA, 1:50000 scale). Council for Geoscience, Pretoria, 49pp. and map 1:50000 scale. 2000.
Bisschoff, A. A., The history and origin of the Vredefort Dome. South African Journal of Science, v. 84, pp. 413-417. 1988.
Bisschoff, A. A., The petrology of some mafic and peralkaline intrusions in the Vredefort Dome, South Africa. Geological Society of South Africa Transactions, v. 76, pp. 27-52. 1988.
Bisschoff, A. A., The petrology of some mafic and peralkaline intrusions in the Vredefort Dome, South Africa. Transactions and Proceedings of the Geological Society of South Africa, v. 76, pp. 27-52. 1973.
Bisschoff, A. A., The petrology of the igneous and metamorphic rocks in the Vredefort Dome and the adjoining parts of the Potchefstroom syncline. D.Sc., University of Potchefstroom, R.S.A. 1969.
Bisschoff, A. A., The pseudotachylite of the Vredefort Dome. Geological Society of South Africa Transactions, v. 65, pp. 207-226. 1962.
Bisschoff, A. A., Tholeiitic intrusion in the Vredefort Dome. Geological Society of South Africa Transactions, v. 75, pp. 23-30. 1972.
Boone, J. D., Albritton, C. C.,Jr., Meteorite scars in ancient rocks, Field and Laboratory, v. 5, pp. 53-64. 1937.
Bootsman, C. S., Reimold, W. U., Some Comparative Geomorphic Aspects of the Morokweng and Vredefort Impact Structures, South Africa, Meteoritics; vol. 34, No. 4, Supp. p. A15. 1999.
Borchers, R. B., Exploration of the Witwatersrand system and its extensions. Geological Society of South Africa Transactions, v. 64, pp. 67-98. 1961.
Brink, M. C., Waanders, F. B. and A. A. Bisschof., The Katdoornbosch-Witpoortjie Fault: a ring thrust of Vredefort Event age, South Africa Journal of Geology, v 103, n 1, p 15-31. 2000.
Brink, M. C., Waanders, F. B., Bisschoff., Evolution of the Ringed Basin Around Vredefort, South Africa, Meteoritics; vol. 34, No. 4, Supp. p. A19-20. 1999.
Brink, M. C., Waanders, F.B. and Bisschoff,A.A., The Foch Thrust-Potchefstroom Fault structural system, Vredefort, South Africa: a model for impact-related tectonic movement over a pre-existing barrier. J. Afr. Earth. Sci. 30, 99-117. 2000a.
Brink, M. C., Waanders, F.B. and Bisschoff,A.A., Vredefort: A model for the anatomy of an astrobleme. Tectonophysics, v. 270, pp. 83-114. 1997.
Brock, B. B., The Vredefort ring. Proceedures of the Geological Society of South Africa, v. 53, pp. 131-157. 1951.
Buchanan, P. C., Reimold, W. U., Impact-Related Features in Lithic Clasts form the Vrederfort Granophyre, South Africa, Meteoritics v. 36, No. 9, Supplement pg. 31. 2001.
Buchanan, P. C., Reimold, W. U., Planar deformation features and impact glass in inclusions from the Vredefort Granophyre, South Africa, Meteorics & Planetary Science, v.37, p.807-822. 2002.
Buchanan, P. C., Reimold, W. U., Planar Deformation Features and Impact Glass in Inclusions from the Vredefort Granophyre, South Africa, Meteoritics & Planetary Science 37 (July 2002 issue). 2002.
Buchanan, P. C., Reimold, W. U., Studies of the Rooiberg Group, Bushveld Complex, South Africa: No evidence for an impact origin. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 155, pp. 149-165. 1998.
Carlson, R. W., Boyd, F.R., Shirey, S.B., Janney, P.E.,et al., Continental Growth, Preservation, and Modification in Southern Africa, GSA Today, Vol. 10, No. 2. 2000.
Carporzen, L., Gilder, S. A. , Hart, R. J., Origin and implications of Verwey transitions in the basement rocks of the Vredefort meteorite crater, South Africa, Earth and Planetary Science Letters, 251, P. 305 - 317. 2006.
Carporzen, L., Gilder, S.A and Hart,R.J., Palaeomagnetism of the Vredefort meteorite crater and implications for craters on Mars, Nature, v. 435 , n. 7039 , p. 198. 2005.
Carter, N. L., Basal quartz deformation lamellae--a criterion for recognition of impactites. American Journal of Science, v. 263, pp. 786-806. 1965.
Cavosie, A.J., Quintero, R.R., Radovan, H.A. and Moser, D.E. A record of ancient cataclysm in modern sand: Shock microstructures in detrital minerals from the Vaal River, Vredefort Dome, South Africa. GSA Bulletin, v. 122, no. 11/12, pp. 1968-1980, doi: 10.1130/B30187.1. 2010.
Cavosie, AJ, Erickson, T.M., Timms, N.E., Reddy, S.M., Talavera, C., Montalvo, S.D., Pincus, M.R., Gibbon, R., and Moser, D (2015) A terrestrial perspective on using ex situ shocked zircons to date lunar impacts. Geology, v. 43 (11), p. 999-1002.
Cloete, M., Hart, R.J., Schmid, H.K., Drury, M., Demanet,C.M.and K.V.Sankar., Characterization of magnetite particles in shocked quartz by means of electron- and magnetic force microscopy: Vredefort, South Africa, Contribution to Mineralogy and Petrology, v 137, p 232-245. 1999.
Cockell, C. S., Lee, P., The Biology of Impact Craters - a review. Biol. Rev., 77, P. 279 - 310. 2002.
Coetzee, M. S., Beukes, G. J. , de Bruiun, H. and Bisschoff, A. A., Geochemistry and petrogenesis of theoleiitic intrusions of possible Bushveld-age in the Vredefort Dome, South Africa, Journal of African Earth Sciences, Vol. 43, P. 213 - 235. 2006.
Colliston, W. P., A model of compressional tectonics for the origin of the Vredefort structure. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 115-118. 1990.
Colliston, W. P., Praekelt, H.E., van der Merwe, R., Stevens,B., Recognition of Vredefort Related and Pre- Vredefort Deformation in the Vredefort Impact Structure, South Africa, Meteoritics; vol. 34, No. 4, Supp. p. A27. 1999.
Colliston, W. P., Reimold, W. U., Structural review of the Vredefort Dome (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 16-17. 1992.
Colliston, W. P., Reimold, W. U., Structural studies in the Vredefort Dome: Preliminary interpretations of results on the southern portion of the structure. Economic Geology Research Unit, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, Information Circular No.229, 31 p. 1990.
Corner, B., Durrheim, R.J. and Nicolaysen,L.O., Relationships between Vredefort structure and the Witwatersrand basin within tectonic framework of Kaapvaal craton as interpreted from regional gravity and aeromagnetic data. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 49-61. 1990.
Corner, B., Wilsher, W. A., 41. Structure of the Witwatersrand Basin derived from interpretation of aeromagnetic and gravity data. Proceedings of Exploration '87, Ontario Geological Survey, Special Volume 3, pp. 532-546. 1989.
Dabizha, A. I., A new interpretation of the structure of meteorite craters (in Russian). Astronomicheskii Vestnik, v. 11, pp. 73-77. 1977.
Daly, R. A., The Vredefort ring-structure of South Africa. Journal of Geology, v. 55, pp. 125-145. 1947.
Dietz, R. S., Astroblemes: Ancient meteorite-impact structures on the Earth. Middlehurst, B.M. and Kuiper, G.P., eds., The Moon, Meteorites and Comets, University of Chicago Press, Chicago, v. IV, pp. 285-300. 1963.
Dietz, R. S., The Vredefort ring structure: A reply. Journal of Geology, v. 70, pp. 502-504. 1962.
Dietz, R. S., Vredefort ring structure: Meteorite impact scar? Journal of Geology, v. 69, pp. 499-516. 1961.
Durrheim R.J., Reimold, W. U., Review of the geophysical signature of the Vredefort structure and its interpretations (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Durrheim, R. J., Nicolaysen, L.O. and Corner,B., A deep seismic reflection profile across the Archean-Proterozoic Witwatersrand Basin, South Africa. Continental Lithosphere: Deep Seismic Reflections, Geodynamics 22 (AGU), pp. 213-224. 1991.
Ellis, S., Reimold, W. U., Post- Transvaal Supergroup Age Thrusting Related to the Collapse Phase of the Vredefort Impact Event: Examples from the Western Ring Basin Area. Meteoritics; vol. 34, No. 4, Supp. p. A34. 1999.
Elston, W. E., Does the Bushveld-Vredefort system (South Africa) record the largest known terrestrial impact catastrophe? (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 23-24. 1992.
Erickson, T.M., Cavosie, A.J., Moser, D.E., Barker, I.R. and Radovan H.A. Correlating planar microstructures in shocked zircon from the Vredefort Dome at multiple scales: Crystallographic modeling, external and internal imaging, and EBSD structural analysis. American Mineralogist 98, 53-65. 2013.
Erickson, T.M., Cavosie, A.J., Moser, D.E., Barker, I.R., Radovan, H.A. and Wooden, J. Identification and provenance determination of distally transported, Vredefort-derived shocked minerals in the Vaal River, South Africa using SEM and SHRIMP-RG techniques. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, v. 107, pp. 170-188. 2013.
Fagereng, A., Harris, C. and La Grange, M., Stable isotope study of the Archaean rocks of the Vredefort impact structure, central Kaapvaal Craton, South Africa, Contributions to Mineral and Petrology, v. 155, pp. 63-78. 2008.
Fletcher, P., Reimold, W. U., Some notes and speculations on the pseudotachylites in the Witwatersrand Basin and Vredefort Dome, South Africa. South African Journal of Geology, v. 92, 223-234. 1989.
Foya, S. N., Gibson, R. L., Reimold., Impact-Related Hydrothermal Alteration of Witwatersrand Gold Reefs in the Vredefort Dome and Witwatersrand Goldfields, South Africa, Meteoritics; vol. 34, No. 4, Supp. p. A37. 1999.
French, B. M., Hargraves, R. B., Bushveld igneous complex, South Africa: Absence of shock-metamorphic effects in a preliminary search. Journal of Geology, v. 79, pp. 616-620. 1971.
French, B. M., Nielsen, R., Vredefort Bronzite Granophyre: Chemical evidence for origin as a meteorite impact melt. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 119-138. 1990.
French, B. M., Orth, C.J. and Quintana,L.R., Iridium in the Vredefort Bronzite Granophyre: Impact melting and limits on a possible extraterrestrial component. Proceedings Lunar and Planetary Science Conference 19th, pp. 733-744. 1989.
Fricke, A., Medenbach, O. and Schreyer,W., Fluid inclusions, planar elements and pseudotachylites in the basement rocks of the Vredefort structure, South Africa. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 169-183. 1990.
Frimmel, H. E., Le Roex, A.P., Knight, J. and Minter,W.E.L., A case study of the postdepositional alteration of the Witwatersrand basal reef gold placer. Economic Geology, v. 88, p. 249-265. 1993.
Frimmel, H. E., Witwatersrand iron-formations and their significance for gold genesis and the composition limits of orthoamphibole. Mineralogy and Petrology, v. 56, pp. 273-295. 1996.
Gersonde, R., Deutsch, A., Ivanov, B.A., Kyte,F.T., Oceanic impacts - a growing field of fundamental geoscience, Deep Sea Research Part II, v.49, p.951-957. 2002.
Gibson, R. L., Armstrong, R.A. and Reimold,W.U., PII S0016-7037 (97)00013-6. The age and thermal evolution of the Vredefort impact structure: A single-grain U-Pb zircon study. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, v. 61, pp. 1531-1540. 1997.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W. U., Magnetic anomaly near the center of the Vredefort structure: Implications for impact-related magnetic signatures: Comment and Reply. Geology, pp. 1149-1151. 1995.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W. U., Petrographic evidence for high shock pressures and shock pressure heterogeneity in the Vredefort Impact Structure, South Africa, Meteoritics & Planetary Science, vol.36, no. 9, Supplement. p. A65. 2001.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W. U., Stevens., Impact-Related Metamorphism in the Vredefort Dome, South Afr. LPSC XXIX, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston, TX, (CD-ROM). 1998.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W. U., Stevens., Thermal-Metamorphic Signature of an Impact Event in the Vredefort Dome, South Africa, Geology; Sept. 1998; vol. 26; no. 9; p. 787-90. 1998.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W. U., The Metamorphic Fingerprint of Large Impact Events, The Example of the Vredefort Dome, South Africa, Meteoritics; vol. 34, No. 4, Supp. p. A42-3. 1999.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W. U., The Vredefort Impact Structure, South Africa (the scientific evidence and a two-day excursion guide). Memoir 1992, Council for Geoscience. 2002.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W.U. and Wallmach,T., Metamorphic textures associated with pseudotachylite in the Vredefort Structure, South Africa: Impact in a "Hot" Crust? (abstract). European Science Foundation, Third International Workshop. Shock Wave Behaviour of Solids in Nature and Experiments, p. 30. 1994.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W.U. and Wallmach,T., Origin of pseudotachylite in the lower Withwatersrand Supergroup, Vredefort Dome (South Africa): constraints from metamorphic studies. Tectonophysics, v. 283, pp. 241-262. 1997.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W.U., Ashley,A.J.and C.Koeberl., Shock pressure distribution in the Vredefort impact structure, South Africa: evidence from feldspar and ferromagnesian minerals. Lunar and Planetary Science XXXII. 2001.
Gibson, R. L., Reimold, W.U., Wallmach,T. and Colliston,W.P., A reappraisal of metamorphism in the Vredefort Dome, South Africa, and its implications for the origin and evolution of the dome (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 423-424. 1994.
Gibson, R. L., The Vredefort hornfelses revisited: negotiating a terminological minefield. S. Afr. J. Geol., v. 1, pp. 93-96. 1996.
Gibson, R. L., The Vredefort hornfelses revisited: negotiating a terminological minefield. S. Afr. J. Geol., v. 99, pp. 93-96. 1996.
Goltrant, O., Cordier, P and Doukhan,J - C., Planar deformation features in shocked quartz; a transmission electron microscopy investigation. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 106, pp. 103-115. 1991.
Graham, I. T., De Waal, S. A. , Armstrong, R. A., New U-Pb SHRIMP zircon age for the Schurwedraai alkali granite: Implications for pre-impact development of the Vredefort Dome and extent of Bushveld magmatism, South Africa. Journal of African Earth Sciences, Vol. 43, P. 537 - 548. 2005.
Green, R. W., Chetty, P., Seismic refraction studies in the basement of the Vredefort structure. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 105-113. 1990.
Grieve, R. A. F., Coderre, J.M., Robertson, P.B. and Alexopoulos,J.S., Microscopic planar deformation features in quartz at the Vredefort structure: Anomalous but still suggestive of an impact origin. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 185-200. 1990.
Grieve, R. A. F., Masaitis, V. L., The economic potential of terrestrial impact craters. International Geology Review, v. 36, pp. 105-151. 1994.
Grieve, R. A. F., The record of impact on Earth: Implications for a major Cretaceous/Tertiary impact event. Geological Society of America, Special Paper 190, pp. 25-37. 1982.
Grieve, R. A. F., Therriault, A., Vredefort, Sudbury, Chicxulub; three of a kind, Annual Review of Earth and Planetary Sciences, v.28, p.305-338. 2000.
Grieve, R., Therriault, A., Vredefort, Sudbury, Chicxulub: Three of a Kind? Ann. Rev. Earth Planet. Sci. 2000 vol. 28, pp. 305-38. 2000.
Gurov, E. P., Gorova, E.P. and Rakitskaya,R.B., On the orientation of planar feature sets in quartz from rocks of explosion meteorite craters (in Russian). Zapiski Vsesoyuznogo mineralogicheskogo obshchestva, v. 108, pp. 578-584. 1979.
Gurov, E. P., Gurova, E. P., Impact structures on the Earth's surface (in Russian). Geologicheskii Zhurnal, v. 47, pp. 117-124. 1987.
Hall, A. L., Molengraaff, G. A. F., The Vredefort Mountain Land in the southern Transvaal and northern Orange Free State. Verh. K. Alak. Wet. Amst., v. 24, (2 Sec.), p. 1-83. 1925.
Halvorson, K., McHone, J. F., Vredefort coesite confirmed with Raman spectroscopy (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIII, pp. 477-478. 1992.
Hargraves, R. B., Paleomagnetic and 40Ar/39Ar evidence for intrusion of dioritic and peralkaline rocks at Vredefort prior to overturning of the collar. Unpublished Report, Princeton University, Princeton, N.J., 21 p. 1987.
Hargraves, R. B., Paleomagnetic evidence relevant to the origin of the Vredefort ring. Journal of Geology, v. 78, pp. 253-263. 1970.
Hargraves, R. B., Shatter cones in the rocks of the Vredefort ring. Geological Society South Africa Transactions, v. 64, pp. 147-154. 1961.
Hart, R. J., Andreoli, M. A. G., A geological traverse of the Vredefort Structure: The natural equivalent of a 15 km borehole into the Archaean Kaapvaal craton, South Africa. Geocongress '86, 22nd. Bienn. Congr. Geol. Soc. S.Afr., Johannesburg, South Africa, pp. 823-826. 1986.
Hart, R. J., Andreoli, M.A.G., Reimold, W.U. and Tredoux,M., Aspects of the dynamic and thermal metamorphic history of the Vredefort cryptoexplosion structure: implications for its origin. Tectonophysics, v. 192, pp. 313-331. 1991.
Hart, R. J., Andreoli, M.A.G., Smith, C.B., Otter, M.L. and Durrheim,R., Ultramafic rocks in the center of the Vredefort structure (South Africa): Possible exposure of the upper mantle? Chem. Geol., v. 83, pp. 233-248. 1990.
Hart, R. J., Andreoli, M.A.G., Tredoux, M. and Wit,M.J., Geochemistry across an exposed section of Archean crust at Vredefort, South Africa: With implications for mid-crustal discontinuities. Chem. Geol., v. 82, pp. 21-50. 1990.
Hart, R. J., Andreoli, M.A.H., de Wit, M.J. and Tredoux,M., Geotraverse of the Vredefort structure: Implications for a mid-crustal discontinuity in the Kaapvaal craton (extended abstract). Int. Workshop on Cryptoexpl. and Catastr. in the Geol. rec., Parys,. 1987.
Hart, R. J., Cloete, M., Impact-Related Magnetic Rocks from the Vredefort Impact Structure, Meteoritics; vol. 34, No. 4, Supp. p. A50. 1999.
Hart, R. J., Connell, S.H., Cloete, M., Mare,L., 'Super magnetic' rocks generated by shock metamorphism from the centre of the Vredefort impact structure, South Africa. South African Journal of Geology, March 2000, v.103, pp.151-155. 2000.
Hart, R. J., Hargraves, R.B. andreoli, M.A.G., Tredoux,M.and Doucouré., Magnetic anomaly near the center of the Vredefort structure: Implications for impact-related magnetic signatures. Geology, v. 23, pp. 277-280. 1995.
Hart, R. J., McDonald, I., Tredoux, M, de Wit, M.J., Carlson, R.W., Andreoli, M, Moser, D.E and Ashwal,L.D., New PGE and Re/Os-isotope data from lower crustal sections of the Vredefort Dome and a reinterpretation of its "crust on edge" profile. South African Journal of Geology, v.107, p.173-184. 2004.
Hart, R. J., Nicolaysen, L.O. and Gale,N.H., Radioelement concentrations in the deep profile through Precambrian basement of the Vredefort structure. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 86, pp. 10639-10652. 1981.
Hart, R. J., Welke, H.J. and Nicolaysen,L.O., Geochronology of the deep profile through Archean basement at Vredefort, with implications for early crustal evolution. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 86, pp. 10663-10680. 1981.
Hayward, C. L., Fluid Movement and Gold Remobilization Triggered by the Vredefort Impact, Witwatersrand Basin, South Africa, Meteoritics; vol. 34, No. 4, Supp. p. A52. 1999.
Henkel, H., Magnetic anomalies of the Vredefort central rise structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Henkel, H., Reimold, W. U., Combined geophysical modeling of the Vredefort structure (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Henkel, H., Reimold, W. U., Integrated geophysical modelling of a giant, complex impact structure: anatomy of the Vredefort Structure, South Africa. Tectonophysics, v. 287, pp. 1-20. 1998.
Henkel, H., Reimold, W. U., Integrated geophysical modelling of the Vredefort impact structure, Witwatersrand Basin, South Africa (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science, v. XXVII, pp. 527-528. 1996.
Henkel, H., Reimold, W. U., Integrated gravity and magnetic modelling of the Vredefort impact structure - reinterpretion of the Witwatersrand Basin as the erosional remnant of an impact basin. EGRU Int. Circ., v. 299,. 1996.
Henkel, H., Reimold, W. U., Integrated gravity and magnetic modelling of the Vredefort impact structure - reinterpretion of the Witwatersrand Basin as the erosional remnant of an impact basin. EGRU Int. Circ., v. 299,. 1996.
Henkel, H., Reimold, W. U., Magnetic Model of the Central Uplift of the Vredefort Impact Structure, LPSC XXX, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston, TX, Abstr. 1336 (CD-ROM). 1999.
Henkel, H., Reimold, W. U., Reconstruction of the Vredefort impact crater (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Ivanov, B. A., Large impact crater formation: thermal softeneing and acoustic fluidization, 61st Annual Meteoritical Society Meeting, Dublin, Ireland. 1998.
Ivanov, B. A., Large impact crater formation: thermal softening and acoustic fluidization. Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v 33, n 4, p A76. 1998.
Jahn, A. and Riller, U., A 3D model of first-order structural elements of the Vredefort Dome, South Africa-Importance for understanding central uplift formation of large impact structures, Tectonophysics, v. 478, pp. 221-229, 2009.
Jahn, A., Riller, U., Kinematics of large terrestrial impact crater formation inferred from structural analysis and three-dimensional block modeling of he Vredeford Dome, South Africa. Special Paper- Geological Society of America, vol.518, pp.85-97. 2015.
Kamo, S. L., Reimold, W.R., Krogh, T.E. and Colliston,W.P., Shocked zircons in Vredefort pseudotachylite and the U-Pb zircon age of Vredefort impact event (abstract). Centennial Geocongress '95, Geol. Soc. S. Afr., pp. 566-569. 1995.
Kamo, S. L., Reimold, W.U., Krogh, T.E. and Colliston,W.P., A 2.023 Ga age for the Vredefort impact event and a first report of shock metamorophosed zircons in pseudotachylitic breccias and Granophyre. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 144, pp. 369-387. 1997.
Killick, A. M., Reimold, W. U., Review of the pseudotachylites in and around the Vredefort 'Dome', South Africa. South African Journal of Geology, v. 93, pp. 350-365. 1990.
Killick, A. M., Roering, C., An estimate of the physical conditions of pseudotachylite formation in the West Rand Goldfield, Witwatersrand Basin, South Africa. Tectonophysics, v. 284, pp. 247-259. 1998.
Koeberl, C., African meteorite impact craters: Characteristics and geological importance. Journal of African Sciences, v. 18, pp. 263-295. 1994.
Koeberl, C., Milkereit, B., Continental Drilling and the Study of Impact Craters and Processes - an ICDP Perspective, In: Continental Scientific Drilling (eds. Harms, U., Koeberl, C., and Zoback, M.D.), Springer, Heidelberg, p. 95-161. 2007.
Koeberl, C., Peucker-Erenbrink, B., Reimold, W.U., Shukolyukov, A., Lugmair,G.W., Comparison of the osmium and chromium isotopic methods for the detection of meteoritic components in impactites: Examples from the Morokweng and Vredefort impact structures, South Africa, Geological Society of America, Special Paper 356 p. 607 - 617. 2002.
Koeberl, C., Reimold, W.U. and Shirey,S.B., Re-Os isotope and geochemical study of the Vredefort Granophyre: Clues to the origin of the Vredefort structure, South Africa. Geology, v. 24, pp. 913-916. 1996.
Lana, C., Gibson, R.L. and Reimold,W.U., Structural evolution of the Archaean basement complex, Vredefort Dome. Geocongress 2000, Stellenbosch, Bienn. Congr., Geol. Soc. S. Afr., Late Abstract, 2pp. 2000.
Lana, C., Gibson, R.L., Kisters, A. and Reimold,W.U., Structural analysis of the core of the central uplift of the Vredefort impact structure, South Africa, Lunar Planet. Sci. XXXII, Lunar and Planet Inst., Houston, CD ROM, #1032, 2pp. 2001.
Lana, C., Reimold, W.U., Gibson, R.L., Koeberl, C., Siegesmund,S., Nature of the Archean midcrust in the core of the Vredefort Dome, Central Kaapvaal Craton, South Africa, Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta Vol. 68, No. 3, p. 623 - 642. 2004.
Leroux, H., Joreau, P., Reimold, W.U. and Doukhan,J.-C., A T.E.M. investigation of shock metamorphism in quartz from the Vredefort dome, South Africa (abstract). European Science Foundation, Third International Workshop. Shock Wave Behaviour of Solids in Nature and Experiments, Limoges, France. 1994.
Leroux, H., Reimold, W.U. and Doukhan,J.-C., A TEM investigation of shock metamorphism in quartz from the Vredefort dome, South Africa. Tectonophysics, v. 230, pp. 223-239. 1994.
Lieger, D., Riller, U. and Gibson, R.L., Generation of fragment-rich pseudotachylite bodies during central uplift formation in the Vredefort impact structure, South Africa, Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 278, pp. 53-64. 2009.
Lilly, P. A., Coesite and stishovite in the Vredefort, South Africa. Nature, v. 277, p. 495. 1979.
Lilly, P. A., Faulting mechanics in the collar rock of the Vredefort ring structure. Tectonophysics, v. 67, pp. 45-60. 1980.
Lilly, P. A., Shock metamorphism in the Vredefort collar: Evidence for internal shock sources. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 86, pp. 10689-10700. 1981.
Lofgren, G., Donaldson, C.H., Williams, R.J., Mullins, Jr., O. and Usselman,T.M., Experimentally reproduced textures and mineral chemistry of Apollo 15 quartz normative basalts. Proceedings of the 5th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, pp. 549-557. 1974.
Lofgren, G., Spherulitic textures in glassy and cyrstalline rocks. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 76, pp. 5635-5648. 1971.
Loper, D. E., McCartney, K., Shocked quartz found at the K/T boundary: A possible endogenous mechanism. EOS, v. 69, p. 961. 1988.
Manton, W. I., The orientation and origin of shatter cones in the Vredefort ring. New York Acadamy of Science Annals, v. 123, pp. 1017-1049. 1965.
Maree, B. D., The Vredefort structure as revealed by a gravimetric survey. Geological Society of South Africa Transactions, v. 47, pp. 183-196. 1945.
Martini, J. E. J., Coesite and stishovite in the Vredefort Dome, South Africa. Nature, v. 272, pp. 715-717. 1978.
Martini, J. E. J., Reply to comment of W.U. Reimold et al. on "The nature, distribution and genesis of the coesite and stishovite ...........Vredefort Dome , South Africa. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 112, pp. 219-222. 1992.
Martini, J. E. J., The metamorphic history of the Vredefort dome at approximately 2 Ga as revealed by coesite-stishovite-bearing pseudotachylites. Journal of Metamorphic Geology, v. 10, pp. 517-527. 1992.
Martini, J. E. J., The nature, distribution and genesis of the coesite and stishovite associated with the pseudotachylite of the Vredefort Dome, South Africa. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 103, pp. 285-300. 1991.
Masaitis, V. L., Danilin, A.N., Maschak, M.S., Raykhlin, A.I., Selivanovskaya, T.V. and Shadenkov,Ye.M., The Geology of Astroblemes (in Russian). Leningrad, Nedra, 231 p. 1980.
Mashchak, M. S., Orlova, Z. V., Recrystallized diaplectic quartz from the Ternovskaya astrobleme (in Russian). Meteoritika, v. 44, pp. 164-167. 1985.
McCarthy, T. S., Charlesworth, E.G. and Stanistreet,I.G., Post-Transvaal structural features of the northern portion of the Witwatersrand Basin. Transactions of the Geological Society of South Africa, v. 89, p. 311-323. 1986.
McHone J F., Dietz, R. S., Earth's multiple impact craters and astroblemes (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science, v. XXIII, pp. 887-888. 1992.
Minnitt, R. C. A., Reimold, W.U. and Colliston,W.P., The geology of the Greenlands Greenstone Complex and selected granitiod terranes in the Southeastern Quadrant of the Vredefort Dome. Econ. Geol. Red. Unit. inf. Circ. No 281, Univ. of the Witwatersrand, 46p. 1994.
Minnitt, R. C. A., Reimold, W.U. and Colliston,W.P., The Vredefort Dome, South Africa: New structural geolgical data from the granite-greenstone terrane in the southeastern quadrant (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIII, pp. 915-916. 1992.
Moser, D. E., Dating the shock wave and thermal imprint of the giant Vredefort impact, South Africa. Geology, v. 25, pp. 7-10. 1997.
Moser, D. E., Hart, R., Age of impact melting and metamorphism in the Vredefort Structure, South Africa (abstract). GAC/MAC, p. A67. 1996.
Moynier, F., Koeberl, C, Quitte, G. and Telouk, P., A tungsten isotope approach to search for meteorite componenets in terrestrial impact rocks, Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v.286, pp.35-40. 2009.
Muundjua, M., Hart, R. J. , Gilder, S. A. , Carporzen, L. and Galdeano, A., Magnetic imaging of the Vredefort impact crater, South Africa, Earth and Planetary Science Letters, Vol. 261, P. 456 - 468. 2007.
Muundjua, M., Hart, R. J. , Gilder, S. A. , Carporzen, L. and Galdeano, A., Reply to comment by Reimold, W.U., Gibson, R.L. and Henkel, H. on Muundjua et al. (2007), "Magnetic imaging of the Vredefort impact crater, South Africa", EPSL 261, pp 456-468, Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 273, pp. 397-399. 2008.
Nel, L. T., Geological Map of the Country Around Vredefort. Scale 1:63360. Union of S. Afr., Dept. Mines and Ind., Geol. Surv., Pretoria. 1927.
Nel, L. T., The Geology of the country around Vredefort. D. Sc. Thesis (unpubl.), Stellenbosch Univ., 167pp. 1927.
Nel, L. T., The geology of the country around Vredefort--An explanation of the geological map. Pretoria, Special Publication, South Africa Geological Survey, v. 6, 134 p. 1927.
Nicolaysen, L. O., Burger, A.J. and Van Niekerk,C.B., The origin of the Vredefort dome structure in the light of new isotopic data (abstract). International Union of Geology and Geophysics, 13th General Assembly, Berkeley, Calilfornia. 1963.
Nicolaysen, L. O., Hart, R.J. and Gale,N.H., The Vredefort Radioelement Profile extended to supracrustal strata at Carletonville, with implications for continental heat flow. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 86, pp. 10,653-10,661. 1981.
Nicolaysen, L. O., Reimold, W. U., Shatter cones revisited. Contr. to Int. Workshop on Cryptoexpl. and Catastr. in the Geol. Recl, Parys, Section N2, 8p. BPI Geophysics Univ. of the Witwatersrand. 1987.
Nicolaysen, L. O., Reimold, W. U., Shock deformation, shatter cones, and pseudotachylite at Vredefort: A review of major unsolved problems and current efforts to resolve them (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XVI, pp. 618-619. 1985.
Nicolaysen, L. O., Reimold, W. U., Vredefort shatter cones revisited, Journal of Geophysical Research, v 104, B3, p 4911-4930. 1999.
Nicolaysen, L. O., The Vredefort structure. Contrib. to Int. Worksh. on Cryptoexpl. and Catastr. in the Geol. Rec., Parys. July 1987, section N1, 8p., BPI Geophysics, Univ. of the Witwatersrand. 1987.
Nicolaysen, L. O., The Vredefort structure: An introduction and a guide to recent literature. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 1-7. 1990.
Penny, F. W., On the relationship of the Vredefort granite to the Witwatersrand system. Quarterly Journal Geological Society of London, v. 70, pp. 328-335. 1914.
Penny, F. W., The Vredefort granite in relation to the Witwatersrand system. Quarterly Journal of the Geological Society of London, v. 70, pp. 328-335. 1914.
Perchuk, L. L., Sazonova, L.V., van Reenen, D.D., Gerya,T.V., Ultramylonites and their significance for the understanding of the History of the Vredefort Impact Structure, South Africa, Petrology, Vol. 11 No. 2, p. 114 - 129. 2004.
Perchuk, L. L., Tokarev, D.A., van Reenen, D.D., Varlamov, D.A., Gerya, T.V., Sazonova, L.V., Fel'dman, V.I., Smit, C.A., Brink, M.C., Bisschoff,A.A., Dynamic and Thermal History of the Vredefort Explosion Structure in the Kaapvaal Craton, South Africa, Petrology, Vol. 10 No. 5, p. 395 - 397. 2002.
Phillips, G. N., Law, J.D.M. and Stevens,G., Alteration, heat, and Witwatersrand gold: 111 years after Harrison and Langlaagte. S. Afr. J. Geol., v. 100, pp. 377-392. 1997.
Phillips, G. N., Zhou, T. and Powell,R., Metamorphic temperature variations among Witwatersrand goldfields: evidence from the pyrophyllite-chloritoid-chlorite mineral assemblage. S. Afr. J. Geol., v. 100, pp. 393-404. 1997.
Pretorius, D. A., The depositional environment of the Witwatersrand goldfields: A chronological review of speculations and observations. Mineral Science and Engineering, v. 7, pp. 18-47. 1975.
Pretorius, D. A., The nature of the Witwatersrand gold-uranium deposits. Handbook of Strata-bound and Stratiform Ore Deposits. II. Regional Studies and Specific Deposits, Wolf, K.H., ed., Amsterdam, Elsevier Scentific Publishing Company, v. 7, p. 29-88. 1976.
Pretorius, D. A., The sources of Witwatersrand gold and uranium: A continued difference of opinion. Economic Geology, pp. 139-163. 1991.
Pybus, G. Q. J., Reimold, W.U. and Smith,C.B., Studies of mafic intrusives in the Vredefort impact structure, South Africa: implications for craton wide igneous activity at 1.1 Ga ago (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 1113-1114. 1994.
Reimold W.U., Gibson, R. L., Geology and evolution of the Vredefort impact structure, South Africa. Journal of African Earth Sciences, v. 23, pp. 125-162. 1996.
Reimold W.U., Minnitt, R. C. A., Impact-induced shatter cones or percussion marks on quartizites of the Witwatersrand and Transvaal Supergroups?. S. Afr. J. Geol., v. 99, pp. 299-308. 1996.
Reimold, W. U., Andreoli, M. and Hart,R., Pseudotachylite from the Vredefort dome (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XVI, pp. 691-692. 1985.
Reimold, W. U., Colliston, W. P., Pseudotachylites of the Vredefort Dome and the surrounding Witwatersrand Basin, South Africa. Geological Society of America Special Paper 293, eds., B.O. Dressler, R.A.F. Grieve and V.L. Sharpton, pp. 177-196. 1994.
Reimold, W. U., Colliston, W. P., The pseudotachylites from the Vredefort structure and the Witwaterstrand basin (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 60-61. 1992.
Reimold, W. U., Colliston, W.P. and Robertson,A.S., Chronological and structural work in the Vredefort Dome. Geocongress '88, 22nd Bienn. Meet. Geol. Soc. S. Afr., Durban, pp. 501-504. 1988.
Reimold, W. U., Dressler, B. O., The economic significance of impact processes (abstract). Abstracts for the International Workshop on Meteorite Impact on the Early Earth, Perth, Australia, pp. 36-37. 1990.
Reimold, W. U., Duane, M. J., Discussion of the criteria for recognition of multiring impact basins--with reference to the Simpson Desert depression and the Vredefort Dome (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXII, pp. 1115-1116. 1991.
Reimold, W. U., Fletcher, P., Ferreira, C.A.M. and Colliston,W.P., The Vredefort structure - new results, with a focus on structural aspects of the Vredefort Dome and surrounding areas of the Witwatersrand Basin (abstract). Abstracts for the International Workshop on Meteorite Impact on the Early Earth, Perth, Australia, pp. 38-39. 1990.
Reimold, W. U., Fletcher, P., Snowden, P.A. and Wilson,J.D., Pseudotachylite - a general Witwatersrand basin phenomenon! (abstract), Lunar and Planetary Science XVII, pp. 701-702. 1986.
Reimold, W. U., Fracture density statistics along radial traverses through the crystalline basement of the Vredefort dome, South Africa (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XVIII, pp. 826-827. 1987.
Reimold, W. U., Geochemistry of pseudotachylites from the Vredefort Dome, South Africa. Neues Jahrbuch für Minerogie, Abhandlungen, v. 161, pp. 151-184. 1991.
Reimold, W. U., Gibson, R. L. and B. O. Dressler., Pseudotachylites, pseudotachylitic breccias, and other melt breccias in impact settings - a discussion. Lunar and Planetary Science XXXII. 2001.
Reimold, W. U., Gibson, R.L. and Layer,P.W., Further 40Ar-39Ar stepheating data of fault rocks and metamorphic minerals from the Vredefort Dome and Witwatersrand Basin (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science, v. XXVII, pp. 1067-1068. 1996.
Reimold, W. U., Gibson, R.L., Colliston, W.P. and Layer,P.W., The Vredefort Dome in the Witwatersrand basin: New argon chronological data and the geochronological record of the central Kaapvaal craton between >3 and <1 Ga ago (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVI, pp. 1157-1158. 1995.
Reimold, W. U., Hart, R.J. and Andreoli,M.A.G., Fracture density statistics along radial traverses through the crystalline basement of the Vredefort dome, South Africa-new data from a NNW-traverse (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXI, pp. 1005-1006. 1990.
Reimold, W. U., Horsch, H. and Durrheim,R.J., The "Bronzite"-Granophyre from the Vredefort Structure - A detailed analytical study and reflections on the genesis of one of Vredefort's enigmas. Proceedings Lunar and Planetary Science Conference 20th, pp. 433-450. 1990.
Reimold, W. U., Horz, F., Experimental shock metamorphism of Witwatersrand quartzite (extended abstract). Geocongress '86, Bienn. Congress Geol. Soc. S.A., Johannesburg, pp. 53-57. 1986.
Reimold, W. U., Horz, F., Textures of experimentally shocked (5.1-35.5 GPa) Witwatersrand quartzite (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XVII, pp. 703-704. 1986.
Reimold, W. U., Impact cratering - a review, with special reference to the economic importance of impacat structures and the southern African impact crater record. Earth, Moon and Planets, v. 70, pp. 21-45. 1995.
Reimold, W. U., Jessberger, E.K. and Stephan,T., 40Ar-39Ar dating of pseudotachylite from the Vredefort dome, South Africa: A progress report. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 139-152. 1990.
Reimold, W. U., Jessberger, E.K. and Stephan,T., A multistage, long term evolution of the Vredefort dome, South Africa - as suggested by 40Ar-39Ar dating of pseudotachylite (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science Conference XVIII, pp. 830-831. 1987.
Reimold, W. U., Koeberl, C., About the impact origin of the Vredefort structure. Geobulletin. The Geological Society of South Africa, v. 37, pp. 3-7. 1994.
Reimold, W. U., Leroux, H. and R. L. Gibson., TEM analysis of naturally deformed zircon from the central Vredefort Dome. Lunar and Planetary Science XXXII. 2001.
Reimold, W. U., Levin, G., The Vredefort structure, South Africa: A bibliography relating to its geology and evolution. Economic Geology Reserach Unit, University of Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, Information circular No. 242, 24 pp. 1991.
Reimold, W. U., Pseudotachylites in impact Structures - a review, but with special reference to the Vredefort structure, South Africa (abstract). European Science Foundation, Third International Workshop. Shock Wave Behaviour of Solids in Nature and Experiments, Limoges, France. 1994.
Reimold, W. U., Reid, A. M., New facts on the Bronaite Granophyre from the Vredefort structure and implications for the genesis of this enignatic rock type. International Workshop on Cryptoexplosion and Catastrophe in the Geol. Rec., v. Section R1, p. 9p. 1987.
Reimold, W. U., Reid, A. M., Petrographic observations on granitic clasts in granophyre of the Vredefort structure. Bienn. Symp., Mineral. Assoc. of S. Afr., Pretoria, pp. 16-21. 1989.
Reimold, W. U., Reid, A.M. and Therriault,A.M., Observations on granitic clasts in granophyre from the Vredefort Dome, South Africa (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXI, pp. 1009-1010. 1990.
Reimold, W. U., Shock experiments with preheated Witwatersrand quartzite and the Vredefort microdeformation controversy (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XIX, pp. 970-971. 1988.
Reimold, W. U., Stephan, T. and Jessberger,E.K., Testing younger than 2 Ga 40Ar-39Ar ages for pseudotachylite from the Vredefort structure. South Africian Journal of Science, v. 88, pp. 563-573. 1992.
Reimold, W. U., The controversial microdeformations in quartz from the Vredefort Structure, South Africa - a discussion. South African Journal of Geology, v. 93, pp. 645-663. 1990.
Reimold, W. U., The Vredefort Dome - review of geology & deformation phenomena & status report on current knowledge & remaining problematics (5 years after the cryptoexpl. wks), International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 59-60. 1992.
Reimold, W. U., Vredefort 1997: A controversy resolved - still a challenge for the future (abstract). Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution,. 1997.
Reimold, W. U., Wallmach, T., The Vredefort structure under discussion. South African Journal of Science, v. 87, pp. 412-417. 1991.
Reimold, W.U., Gibson, R.L. and Henkel, H. Scientific comment on "Muundjua et al. 2007: Magnetic imaging of the Vredefort impact crater, South Africa, EPSL 261, 456-468", Earth and Planetary Science Letters, v. 273, pp.393-396. 2008.
Robertson, P. B., Grieve, R.A.F., Alexopoulos, J.S. and Coderre,J., Shock metamorphism at the Vredefort structure, South Africa: Evidence for a single shock event (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XVIII, pp. 840-841. 1987.
Roering, C., Barton, J.M., Jr. and Winter,H.de la R., The Vredefort structure: A perspective with regard to new tectonic data from adjoining terranes. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 7-22. 1990.
Rondot, J., About the Size of the Vredefort Impact Crater, Meteoritics; vol. 34, No. 4, Supp. p. A98-9. 1999.
Salminen, J., Pesonen, L.J., Reimold, W.U., Donadini, F. and Gibson, R.L., Paleomagnetic and rock magnetic study of the Vredefort impact structure and the Johannesburg Dome, Kaapvaal Craton, South Africa-Implications for the apparent polar wander path of the Kaapvaal Craton during the Mesoproterozoic, Precambrian Research, v. 168, pp. 167-184. 2009.
Schreyer, W., Abraham, K., Symplectitic cordierite-orthopoyroxene-garnet assemblages as products of contact metamorphism of per-existing basement granulites in the Vredefort structure, South Africa, and their relations to pseudotachylite. Contrib. Mineral. Petrol., v. 68, pp. 53-62. 1978.
Schreyer, W., Metamorphism and fluid inclusions in the basement of the Vredefort Dome, South Africa: Guidelines to the origin of the structure. J. Petrol., v. 24, pp. 26-47. 1983.
Schwarzman, E. C., Meyer, C.E. and Wilshire,H.G., Pseudotachylite from the Vredefort ring, South Africa, and the origins of some lunar breccias. Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 94, pp. 926-935. 1983.
Shand, E. J., The pseudotachylite of Parys. Quart. Jour. Geol. Soc. London, v. 62, pp. 1998-221. 1916.
Simonson, B. M., Chadwick, B. and P. Claeys., Spherules in a paleoproterozoic dolomite layer in the Ketilidian Orogeny of South Greenland are candidates for ejecta from the Vredefort structure. Lunar and Planetary Science XXXII. 2001.
Simpson, C., A structural analysis of the rim synclinorium of the Vredefort Dome. M.Sc. Thesis (unpubl.), Univ. of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, 257pp. 1977.
Simpson, C., Occurrence and orientation of shatter cones in Pretoria group quartzites in the collar of the Vredefort dome: Impact origin precluded. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 86, pp. 10701-10706. 1981.
Simpson, C., The structure of the rim synclinorium of the Vredefort Dome. Trans. Geol. Soc. S. Afr., v. 81, pp. 115-121. 1978.
Slawson, W. F., Vredefort core: A cross-section of the upper crust? Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, v. 40, pp. 117-121. 1976.
Spray, J. G., Kelley, S. P., Laser fusion 40Ar-39Ar dating of pseudotachylites from the Vredefort impact sturcture: New evidence for a major formation event at 2.0 Ga (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXV, pp. 1321-1322. 1994.
Spray, J. G., Kelley, S.P. and Reimold,W.U., Laser probe argon-40/argon-39 dating of coesite- and stishovite-bearing pseudotachylytes and the age of the Vredefort impact event. Meteoritics, v. 30, pp. 335-343. 1995.
Spray, J. G., Pseudotachylyte type area: Vredefort. Fault Rocks and Fault Mechanisms, Snoke, A.W., Tullis, J. and Todd, V.R. (eds.), Fault-related rocks: A photographic atlas, Princeton University Press, Princeton, NJ, USA, p.75-79. 1998.
Spray, J. G., Thompson, L. M., Friction melt distribution in a multi-ring impact basin. Nature, v. 373, pp. 130-132. 1995.
Stepo, D., A geological and geophysical study of the central portion of Vredefort dome structure. Ph.D. thesis (unpublished), University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg. 1979.
Stepto, D., The geology and gravity field in the central core of the Vredefort structure. Tectonophysics, v. 171, pp. 75-103. 1990.
Stevens, G., Boer, R. and Gibson,R., Metamorphism, fluid-flow, and gold mobilization in the Witwatersrand Basin: towards a unifying model. S. Afr. J. Geol., v. 100, pp. 363-375. 1997.
Stewart, R. A., Reimold, W.U., Charlesworth,E.G.and W.D.Ortlepp., The nature of a deformation zone and fault rock related to a recent rockburst at Western Deep Levels Gold Mine, Witwatersrand Basin, South Africa, Tectonophysics, v 337, p 137-190. 2001.
Therriault, A. M., Grieve, R. A. F., Reimold., Original Size of the Vredefort Structure: Implications for the Geological Evolution of the Witwatersrand Basin, Meteoritics; vol. 32, p. 71-7. 1997.
Therriault, A. M., Grieve, R.A.F. and Reimold,W.U., How big is Vredefort? (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 30, pp. 586-587. 1995.
Therriault, A. M., Grieve, R.A.F. and Reimold,W.U., Original size of the Vredefort Structure: Implications for the geological evolution of the Witwatersrand Basin. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 32, pp. 71-77. 1997.
Therriault, A. M., Grieve, R.A.F. and Reimold,W.U., The Vredefort Structure: original size ans significance for geological evolution of the Witwatersrand Basin. Meteoritics Planet. Sci. 32, 71-77. 1997a.
Therriault, A. M., Ostermann, M., Grieve, R.A.F. and Deutsch,A., Are Vredefort granophyre and Sudbury offsets birds of a feather? (abstract). Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, p. A142. 1996.
Therriault, A. M., Reid, A. M., "Bronzite" granophyre: New insight on Vredefort (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 72-73. 1992.
Therriault, A. M., Reid, A.M. and Reimold,W.U., Origin of the Vredefort structure, South Africa: Impact model (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 1421-1422. 1993.
Therriault, A. M., Reid, A.M. and Reimold,W.U., Original size of the Vredefort structure, South Africa (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXIV, pp. 1419-1420. 1993.
Therriault, A. M., Reimold, W. U., Reid., Field relations and petrography of the Vredefort granophyre, S. Afr. J. Geol. 99 pp.1-21. 1996.
Therriault, A. M., Reimold, W.U. and Reid,A.M., Geochemistry and impact origin of the Vredefort Granophyre. S. Afr. J. Geol., v. 100, pp. 115-122. 1997.
Tredoux, M., Hart, R.J., Carleson, R.W., Shirley,S.B., Ultramafic rocks at the center of the Vredefort structure: Furthur evidence for the crust on edge model, Geology, v.27, n.10, p.923-926. 1999.
Tredoux, M., Hart, R.J., Carlson, R.W., Shirey,S.B., Ultramafic Rocks at the Center of the Vredefort Structure: Further Evidence for the Crust on Edge Model, Geology; Oct. 1999, v. 27; no. 10; p. 923-6. 1999.
Trieloff, M., Kunz, J., Jessberger, E.K., Reimold, W.U., Boer, R.H. and Jackson,M., 40Ar-39Ar dating of pseudotachylites from the Witwatersrand basin, South Africa, with implications for the formation of the Vredefort Dome (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 75-77. 1992.
Trieloff, M., Reimold, W U., Kunz, J, Jessberger, E K., Boer, R H. and Jackson,M C., 40Ar-39Ar dating of pseudotachylites from the Witwatersrand basin, South Africa, with implications for the formation of the Vredefort dome (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 27, pp. 300-301. 1992.
Turtle, E. P., Finite-element modelling of the Vredefort impact structure; Implications for the formation of multi-ring impact craters (abstract). Fall AGU, p. F444. 1996.
Turtle, E. P., Melosh, H. J., Finite-element modeling of the Vredefort impact structure with implications for the collapse and modification stage of large crater formation (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science, v. XXVII, pp. 1347-1348. 1996.
Turtle, E. P., Pierazzo, E., Constaraints on the size of the Vredefort impact crater from numerical modeling, Meteoritics & Planetary Science, 33, pp. 483-490. 1998.
Turtle, E. P., Pierazzo, E., Constraints on the size of the Vredefort impact crater from numerical modeling (abstract). Lunar and Planetary Science XXVIII, pp. 1459-1460. 1997.
Waanders, F. B., Brink, M. C. , Bisschoff, A. A., Mossbauer study of two different aged rock types in the Vredefort structure, South Africa, Hyperfine Interact, 166, P. 693 - 698. 2005.
Walraven, F., Armstrong, R.A. and Kruger,F.J., A chronostratigraphic framework for the north-central Kaapvaal craton, the Bushveld Complex and the Vredefort structure. Tefctonophysics, v. 171, pp. 23-48. 1990.
Weiland, F., Gibson, R. L., Reimold., Field Studies in the Central Uplift of the Vredefort Impact Structure, Lunar and Planetary Science XXXV. 2004.
Welhe, H., Nicolaysen, L. O., A new interpretive procedure for whole rock U-Pb systems applied to the Vredefort crustal profile. Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 86, 10,681-10,687. 1981.
Wenk, H-R., Lonardelli, I., Vogel, S.C., Tullis,J., Dauphine twinning as evidence for an impact origin of preferred orientation in quartzite: An example from Vredefort, South Africa, Geology, v. 33 , n. 4 , p. 273-276. 2005.
Westbroek, H., Stewart, R., The formation, morphology, and economic potential of meteorite impact craters, CREWES Research Report v. 8, p. 1-26. 1996.
White, J. C., Electron petrography of silica polymorphs associated with pseudotachylite, Verdefort structure, South Africa (abstract). International Conference on Large Meteorite Impacts and Planetary Evolution, LPI Contribution No. 790, pp. 78-79. 1992.
White, J. C., Shock-induced melting and silica polymorph formation, Vredefort structure, South Africa. In: Defects and Processes in the Solid State: Geoscience Applications, Boland, J.N. and Fitz Gerald, J.D., eds., Elsevier, pp. 69-84. 1993.
Wieland, F., Reimold, W. U., Field and laboratory studies on shatter cones in the Vredefort Dome, South Africa, and their genesis, 66th Annual Meteoritical Society Meeting. 2003.
Willemse, J., On the Old Granite of the Vredefort region and some of its associated rocks. Trans. Geol. Soc. S. Afr., v. 40, pp. 43-119. 1937.
Wilshire, H. G., Pseudotachylite from the Vredefort Ring, South Africa. Journal of Geology, v. 79, pp. 195-206. 1971.
Winter, H. de la R., Cratonic foreland model for Witwatersrand Basin development in a continental back arc plate tectonic setting (extended abstract). Geocongress '86, Johannesburg, Geol. Soc. S. Afr., pp. 75-80. 1986.
Wronkiewicz D., Condie, K. C., Geochemistry of Archean shales from the Witwatersrand Supergroup, South Africa: Source-area weathering and provenance. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, v. 51, pp. 2401-2416. 1987.
Youssof, M., Thybo, H., Artemieva, I.M., Levander, A., Moho depth and crustal composition in Southern Africa. Tectonophysics, vol.609, pp.267-287. 2014.
Zaychenko, V. Yu., Kuznetsov, O.L. and Popsuy Shapko,G.P., Nature of ring-shaped photo-anomalies identified by remote surveys (in Russian). Sovetskaya Geologiya, v. 1, pp. 98-106. 1981.
Zotkin, I. T., "Moon" craters on the Earth (in Russian). Priroda, v. 9, pp. 95-105. 1969.