Wetumpka
Alabama, U.S.A.
N 32° 31'
W 86° 10'
6.5
81.0 ± 1.5
Y
Y
M
Chondrite?
Alvarez, W. A., A candidate KT boundary crater in Alabama, Eos, Transactions of the American Geophysical Union, v. 74, p. 387. 1993.
Bentley, R. D., T.L. Neathery and G.C. Lines., A probable impact-type structure near Wetumpka, Alabama, Eos, Transactions of the American Geophysical Union, v. 51, p. 342. 1970.
Carrington, T. J., Current studies of Cretaceous formations in eastern Alabama and Columbus, Georgia: Tuscaloosa, Alabama, Alabama Geological Society Guidebook 20, 52p. 1983.
Hall, J. C., Ground zero - The Wetumpka Astrobleme: Alabama Heritage Magazine, Fall issue, p. 6-13. Reprinted in Alabama Geological Society Guidebook 34c (1997). 1996.
King Jr., D. T., Neathery, T.L., Petruny, L.W., Koeberl, C., Hames,W.E.,., Shallow-marine impact origin of the Wetumpka structure (Alabama, USA), Earth and Planetary Science Letters 202 p. 541 - 549. 2002.
King, Jr,D.T., Neathery, T.L., Petruny, L.W., Koeberl,C.and W.E.Hames., Evidence confirming meteoritic impact at Wetumpka crater, Alabama, USA, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, v 34, n 4, p 63-64. 1999.
King, D. T., L. W. Petruny and T.L. Neathery., Biological effects of a Late Cretaceous marine impact structure (Gulf Coastal Plain, USA), Biological processes in impact craters, Abstract book of the 10th ESF Workshop (Cambridge), p. 38. 2003.
King, D. T., L. W. Petruny and T. L. Neathery., Drilling into the Wetumpka impact crater, Alabama, VOYAGES!, May/June, p. 8-10. [Reprinted in Journey (College of Sciences and Mathematics, Auburn University), 2000, p. 3, 8.]. 1999.
King, D. T., L. W. Petruny and T. L. Neathery., Paleobiologic effects of the Late Cretaceous Wetumpka marine impact, a 7.6-km diameter impact structure, Gulf Coastal Plain, USA, in Cockell, C, I. Gilmour, and C. Koeberl, eds., Biological processes associated with impact events (Impact Studies): Berlin, Springer-Verlag, (in press). 2004.
King, D. T., L. W. Petruny and T.L. Neathery., Stratigraphy drilled at Wetumpka impact structure, Alabama, Geological Society of America, Annual Meeting Abstracts with Programs, v. 34, no. 6, p. 318. 2002.
King, D. T., L. W. Petruny and T.L. Neathery., Structure-filling stratigraphy of the marine-target Wetumpka impact structure, Alabama, USA, USGS-ICDP Workshop on deep drilling in the central crater of the Chesapeake Bay impact structure, Virginia, USA (Proceedings volume): U.S. Geological Survey Open File Report 2004-1016 [CD-ROM], p. 32-33. 2003.
King, D. T., L.W. Petruny and T.L. Neathery., The horseshoe-shaped rim of Wetumpka marine impact crater -- from oblique impact or heterogeneity in the rim? Geological Society of America, Annual Meeting Abstracts with Programs, v. 35 (in press). 2004.
King, D. T., L. W. Petruny and T.L. Neathery., Use of upward-facies transition analysis to help interpret stratigraphy drilled at Wetumpka impact structure, Alabama, USA: Impacts, a Geological and Astronomical Perspective, Abstracts of the 8th ESF Workshop (Prague), Impacts, a Geological and Astronomical Perspective, Abstracts of the 8th ESF Workshop (Prague), in press. 2002.
King, D. T., L. W. Petruny and T.L. Neathery., Upward-facies transition analysis in interpretation of stratigraphic sequence within the Wetumpka impact structure, a marine impact feature in Alabama, USA, Eos, Transactions of the American Geophysical Union [AGU Fall 2002 Meeting], v. 83, in press. 2002.
King, D. T., L. W. Petruny., Wetumpka impact crater guidebook, Auburn, Alabama, 29p. 1999.
King, D.T., Morrow, J.R., Petruny, L.W., Ormoe, J., Surficial polymict impact breccia unit, Wetumpka impact structure, Alabama; shock levels and emplacement mechanism. Special Paper - Geological Society of America, vol.518, pp. 149-164. 2015.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery and L. W. Petruny,., Results of investigations of Wetumpka impact crater, 1998-2003, Alabama Geological Society Newsletter, v. 17, no. 2, p. 4 and 6. 2004.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery and L. W. Petruny., Crater-filling sediments of the Wetumpka marine-target impact crater (Alabama, USA), in Dypvik, H., M.J. Burchell, and P. Claeys, eds., Cratering in marine environments and on ice (Impact Studies): Berlin, Springer-Verlag, p. 97-113. 2003.
King, D. T., Neathery, T.L., Petruny, W., Koeberl, C., Hames,W., Shallow-marine impact origin of the Wetumpka structure (Alabama, USA), Earth and Planetary Science, v.202, p.541-549. 2002.
King, D. T., Neathery, T.L., Petruny, W., Koeberl, C., Hames, W. Neathery, L. Petruny, L. W. Koeberl, C. Hames,W., Shallow-marine impact origin of the Wetumpka structure (Alabama, USA), Earth and Planetary Science Letters 202, 541-549. 2002.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery, L. W. Petruny, W. E. Hames,C.Koeberl., Wetumpka, a Late Cretaceous shallow-shelf impact structure in the Gulf Coastal Plain of Alabama, USA, Submarine Craters and Ejecta-crater Correlation, Abstracts and Proceedings of the Norwegian Geological Society and the 7th ESF Workshop (Longyearbyen, Norway), p. 40-41. 2001.
King, D. T., Neathery and L. W. Petruny., Late Cretaceous shallow shelf impact in Gulf Coastal Plain of Alabama, Geological Society of America, Bolide Impact on Wet Targets, Abstracts (Nevada and Utah Field Forum), 1p. 2001.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery, L. W. Petruny,C.Koeberl and W.E.Hames., Evidence confirming meteoritic impact at Wetumpka crater, Alabama, USA, Catastrophic Events and Mass Extinctions: Impacts and Beyond (Lunar and Planetary Institute Contribution 1053, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston, Texas), p. 97. 2000.
King, D. T., Neathery and L. W. Petruny., Wetumpka impact structure (Alabama), a Late Cretaceous marine-target crater, International Forum on Investigations of the Earth - New Information on Earth and Space Sciences (Yamaguchi University, Japan), Program and Abstracts, p. 26-27. 2000.
King, D. T., Neathery and L. W. Petruny., Wetumpka impact structure (Alabama), a Late Cretaceous marine-target crater, Geological Society of America, Annual Meeting Abstracts with Programs, v. 32, no. 7, p. A-161. 2000.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery, L. W. Petruny, C. Koeberl,W.E.Hames and L.W.Wolf., Evidence of meteoritic impact and crater-filling stratigraphy, Wetumpka, Alabama, USA, 31st International Geological Congress (Rio de Janeiro, Brazil), Abstracts Volume, abstract no. GS-25.5.9, 1p. 2000.
King, D.T., Ormoe, J. The marine-target Wetumpka impact structure examined in the field and by shallow core-hole drilling. Speicla Paper - Geological Society of America, vol. 483, pp.287-300. 2011.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery, L. W. Petruny, C. Koeberl,W.E.Hames and L.W.Wolf., Evidence of meteoritic impact, crater-filling stratigraphy, and collateral effects of impact at Wetumpka crater, Alabama, USA, Geological Society of America, Annual Meeting Abstracts with Programs, v. 31, no. 7, p. A-124. 1999.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery, L. W. Petruny., Impactite facies in drill core from the Wetumpka impact crater, Alabama, Geological Society of America, Annual Meeting Abstracts with Programs, v. 30, no. 7, addendum p. 4. 1998.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery, L. W. Petruny., Impactite facies within the Wetumpka impact crater, Alabama, Lunar and Planetary Science [Lunar and Planetary Science Conference abstracts], v. 30, abstract no. 1634, 1p. 1999.
King, D. T. Jr., Neathery, T. L., Petruny., Impactite Facies Within the Wetumpka Impact-Crater Fill, Alabama, LPSC XXX, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston, TX, Abstr. 1634 (CD-ROM). 1999.
King, D. T. Jr., Nethery, T.L., Petruny, L.W., Koeberl, C., Hames, W.E., Wolf,L.W., Evidence of meteoritic impact, crater-filling stratigraphy, and collateral effects of impact at Wetumpka crater, Alabama, USA, 1999 GSA Annual Meeting - Denver, Colorado. Abs. No. 50205. 1999.
King, D. T., T.L. Neathery., Nature of the Wetumpka impact crater in Alabama, USA, Geological Society of America, Annual Meeting Abstracts with Programs, v. 29, no. 6, p. A 80. 1997.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery., Renewed interest in the Wetumpka impact crater, Alabama Geological Society Newsletter, v. 11, no. 2, p. 17. 1998.
King, D. T., T. L. Neathery., The Wetumpka asteroid impact structure in Alabama, U.S.A. American Association of Petroleum Geologists, Annual Convention Program, v. 7, p. 358a f. 1998.
King, D. T., The Wetumpka impact crater and the Late Cretaceous impact record, in Neathery, T.L., D.T. King, Jr., and L.W. Wolf, The Wetumpka impact structure and related features: Tuscaloosa, Alabama, Alabama Geological Society Guidebook 34c, p. 25 56. 1997.
King, D. T., Wetumpka Melange, a new stratigraphic unit in Alabama, Gulf Coast Association of Geological Societies Transactions, v. 48, p. 151-158. 1998.
King, D. T., Wetumpka Melange, a new stratigraphic unit in Alabama, American Association of Petroleum Geologists Bulletin [GCAGS Meeting Abstracts], v. 82, p. 1784. 1998.
Markin, J., An investigaton of the sedimentary characteristics of the resurge facies, Wetumpka marine impact structure, central Alabama. AAPG Bulletin, vol.95, pp.329-330. 2011.
Neathery, T. L., D.T. King, Jr. and L.W. Wolf,eds., The Wetumpka impact structure and related features: Tuscaloosa, Alabama, Alabama Geological Society Guidebook 34c, 68p. 1997.
Neathery, T. L., D.T. King, Jr and L. W. Wolf., Introduction and Field trip (road log and descriptions), in Neathery, T.L., D.T. King, Jr., and L.W. Wolf, (eds.), The Wetumpka impact structure and related features: Tuscaloosa, Alabama. 1997.
Neathery, T. L., D.T. King, Jr. and L.W. Wolf,eds., The Wetumpka impact structure and related features: Tuscaloosa, Alabama, Geological Society Guidebook 34c, 68p. 1997.
Neathery, T. L., Stop descriptions (Wetumpka astrobleme), in Carrington, T.J. (ed.) Current studies of Cretaceous formations in eastern Alabama and Columbus, Georgia: Tuscaloosa, Alabama, Alabama Geological Society Guidebook 20, p. 48-52. 1983.
Neathery, T. L., R.D. Bentley and G.C. Lines., Cryptoexplosion structure near Wetumpka, Alabama, Geological Society of America Bulletin, v. 87, p. 567-573. [Reprinted in Alabama Geological Society Guidebook No. 20 (1983) and No. 34c (1997).]. 1976.
Nelson, A. I., Geological mapping of Wetumpka impact crater area, Elmore County, Alabama, [unpublished M.S. thesis]: Auburn, Alabama, Auburn University, 187p. 2000.
Wartho, J.A., van Soest, M.C., King, D.T., Petruny, L.W. An (U-Th)/He age for the shallow-marine Wetumpka impact structure, Alabama, USA. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, vol.47, pp. 1243-1255. 2012.
Wartho, J.A., van Soest, M.C., Utstins, P.I., King, D.T., Petruny, L.W., et al. A tale of two craters; (U-Th)/He dating and modeling of age resetting of two small/low energy impact structures. Meteoritics & Planetary Science, vol.46. 2011. 
Wolf, L. W., Plescia and M.G. Steltenpohl., Geophysical investigation of a ‘suspect’ impact crater in Wetumpka, Alabama, Alabama Geological Society Guidebook 34c, p. 57-68. 1997.