Zapadnaya
Ukraine
N 49° 44'
E 29° 0'
3.2
165 ± 5
N
Y
C
-
Basilevsky, A. T., Fel'dman, V.I., Kapustkina, I.G. and Kolesov,G.M., On the distribution of iridium in the rocks of terrestrial impact craters (in Russian). Geokhimiya, v. 6, pp. 781-790. 1984.
Fel'dman, V. I., Catalog of impact and meteorite craters of the Earth (in Russian). Akademiya Nauk SSSR, v. 46, pp. 154-171. 1987.
Grieve, R. A. F., Masaitis, V. L., The economic potential of terrestrial impact craters. International Geology Review, v. 36, pp. 105-151. 1994.
Gurov, E. P., Gurova, E.P. and Rakitskaya,R.B., Impact diamonds of the Zapadnaya crater: Phase composition and some properties (abstract). Meteoritics & Planetary Science, v. 31, p. A56. 1996.
Gurov, E. P., Gurova, E.P. and Rakitskaya,R.B., Impact diamonds in the craters of the Ukrainian shield (abstract). Meteoritics, v. 30, pp. 515-516. 1995.
Gurov, E. P., The characteristics of the geological structure of the eroded astrobleme in the western part of the Ukranian Shield (in Russian). Dipovidi Adademii Nauk Ukrainskoi Rodyanskoi Sotsialistychnoi Respubliky, Seriya "B", pp. 8-11. 1985.
Masaitis, V. L., Diamond-bearing impactites and problems of their development. Mineral Resources of Russia: Diamonds and Gold. Proceedings of the Second International Symposium, Mineral Resources of Russia, pp. 41-43. 1995.
Masaitis, V. L., Diamantiferous impactites, their distribution and petrogenesis (in Russian). Regional Geology and Metallogeny, v. 1, pp. 121-134. 1993.
Sokur, T. M., Shock Metamorphism of Quartz of the Zapadnaya Crater, LPSC XXIX, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston, TX, (CD-ROM). 1998.
Val'ter, A. A., Gurov, E. P., Ustanolennaya in predpolagaemaya rasprostranennost vzryvnykh meteoritnykh craterow na Zemle i ikh sokhrannost na Ukrainskom shchite (in Russsian). In Meteoritnye structuzy na poverkhnosti planet, Nauka, pp. 126-148. 1979.